Ability to tolerate anarthas of people within bounds
	if it comes to your concern then settle the matter then and there. Of course, it is cheap on your part meaning that your spending behavior still is not at the point where you would consider that much amount to be insignificant and not worth thinking about.
	And of course, it is cheap on other side as well but this is pretty much expected from the worldly existence. Becoming overtly disturbed or excited by such worldly exchanges is itself a proof of less spiritual advancement. 
	Not that a spiritually advanced person would be apathetic towards it but he would perform dharma while tolerating rather accepting people for the state that they are in. He won't be disturbed by it just concerned and address the issue thru head-on pragmatism. If the issue can't be handled, he would rather accept the situation as it is. Like BSST would say KC can't wait for britishers to leave the country. There would be someone in material world whose subtle body wants power (coming from descent of any ego or identity) - which is a legitimate expectation from VA - it is people with anarthas willing to conform to Krishna's model of mutual cooperation and not pure devotees trying to have interactions within material world.
	First thing is to empathize with Shringi and second is to understand how terribly wrong he was in terms of disproportionate punishment and immaturity in seeing small picture and not its repercussions.
	There has been intolerance debate on tv - which is an excellent word to bring up - people do and should tolerate within limits - some place the anarthas are the norm and rules need to be made to accomodate such behaviors within the laws. Some places will permit anarthas under the table. Beyond limits some action needs to be taken otherwise the tolerance is seen as weakness and cowardice which leads to a realm that you don't belieave in.
	Like movie seven, even extreme anger towards someone's anarthas is also an anartha. Anartha of anger.
Realm changes with spiritual advancement.
	We may think that it is ego that determines realm - to a good degree it does. but not entirely. Abstract out further from ego interactions within a society and you realize that the society could have had different models called social ideologies. Those social ideologies accept or reject the worldly "tools" of different crafts or egos depends on the their beliefs, social customs, social values, etc. Eg - India accepted IT but with lots of discussion on the impacts it will have in the economy. Realm is not just made the interaction of those egos that make up the economics but also human psychology of that place.
	A person of similar subtle body is born in that place and pivots to an ego as per the upbringing and person attraction. But the person feels very happy in the ambience and environment of that place. Identifies a lot with people. Believe in the ideological end goals, ideological means, etc. The thing to them is superior to themselves. It stands above them. This explains why people agree to die for their nation or for their profession in taj. Some rebels fight against the state - to them they are fighting on this layer which is above their personal ego.
	That's why people persuaded with spiritual reasonings are dangerous and so terribly wrong. It addresses a need of belonging to a realm of choice.
	Different places are differently suited as per the state of anarthas or weeds you have. Surprisingly people with anarthas in some places are very highly situated - it is a disadvantage spiritually so first it's not that good. Why opulence? We should not be jealous of anybody behind the surface. Whoever has opulence has got them by the grace of god - on what basis? they have paid the price. The price of tapasya or penance, the price of giving time, money, efforts. The price of donations, etc. These are spiritual dimensions expressed in the material realm. They may even be into spirituality but at their deepest core they have taken birth in a realm cuz they belong there - from subtle body perspective. After death the realm is chosen on the basis of subtle body - family and society is given as per what would be most apt.
I don't think very high of people - well, duh! in general but more evolved state is like 6 goswamis of bowing down to even neophyte devotees.
	what does this mean? It means that they are fully dedicated to the transcendence and whatever spark of transcendental rightness they find they bow down unto that and the holder is respectable for representing that to whatever degree.
	Less anarthas are good for business - eg a person arranged for another plate free of cost cuz we were not satisfied with the service. Don't you think if we were frequent visitors, we will like to visit them again. Whereas those who are cut to cut and would rather take rounding off as ceiling instead of floor or nearest digit of even mild amount, we will be less disposed towards it. Many may ignore accepting anarthas as they are but you know what is more respectable and gratifying experience.
Centralized market vs distributed market - centralized where champs rock the show. With communism things just replace champs with govt being the champ.
	VA working model knows too well that there are pros and cons on both sides but VA believes in distributed model of economy. Not centralization of power.
	Think globally but act locally is their motto. I heard some people say that centralization of say singing helped them get better at increase in demand in the distributed model. So probably what we need is the distributed model of economy coupled up with centralization co-existing.
	We don't want a selected few holding all the money in the world - that just makes crime increase and increase in social dissatisfaction. So income taxes are a great help but those belong to govt - so they can make a thumbs up deal among each other.
	IT like other tools made the jobs increase in market as expected but graph of economy it creates doesn't grow exponentially.
	Think past decades even rich people would eat chapattis with pickle cuz of bad economy so centralization is necessary.
	