<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PIES>
    <About>
    Make Resume for all of PIES
            PIES - all of them require Bhakti while we are in material world - are they against KC - no, Krishna wants us do them. 
                    Of course, eventually all of them should stabilize (MOG) so that they are not impedance to KC but that's in very high stages of development
                    the basis of relationship can be client server or peer to peer (sadhu sang of stages of bhakti) on any of PIES.
                    B and J club together
                            B - act of making resume, Courses done for the same. Proof of devotion - TME invested => Scrum.
                            J - Chakshu developed (ability to understand and make of sense of anything outside); Capability Developed (Standardized behavior invocable for some service)
                                    Case Studies fall under this (and not D - cuz they are not your own)
                                    Covers all the tools and techniques at your disposal
                    D and K club together
                            D - act of solving a real world problem in terms of capabilities
                            K - use case solved and the corresponding karmic reactions - which all customers benefitted, some user stories, etc.
            Interview Projects Stories
                    it is just expansion of the core philosophy of the thing - like Data Science stages of development and tell your trace thru them.
                    Ability to draw UML diagrams to explain specifications, architecture, tools used, validation, deployment, maintenance.
                    Also an opportunity to go into D and K specifics of the project 
                            like what challenges did you face during devp, what were your responsibilities, who all used your product and their reviews.
                    Plan some 10-15 mins story around it.
            EQ
                    B
                            Civics (politics, law are just specializations), History (Civics of the past though people focus a lot on politics)
                            Economics
                            Psychology, Physical Science (Geography), Biology
                            Metaphysics, Chemistry
                    J - All News, discussions are actually J case studies but simply explore the dynamics of the J. Even action and impact of others are case studies for us to understand.
                    D - What's new with you; what are you up to, how are you doing, what's going on.
                    K - study of your actions and impacts or stories in the world
            PQ - Health
			BJDK
				B - Scrum -> Themes in there.
					Epics (yearly update), Backlogs (release or monthly update), Stories (sprint or weekly update), Subtasks (daily update)
					For the dhansu thing that comes after the year, what is planned this month. What to do this week to get there. Give daily status update on that weekly goal.
				D - (Logs --> IQGrats, Lapse --> Stories, Standardizations). All the routine IQGrats and lapse don't come here; only the ones that stand out. DMPM goes to specific XMLs.
				J - All the DMPM doesn't come here but only the courses done. Others can go in MS Notebook or some concrete sections (local cache for all online helps)
				K - All the Logs don't come here but their rolled-up information. Logs used in ego section to support narratives.
            Ego Specific - Logs view prepared for a narrative.
			Uncat - Grand Story or Larger Narrative - It is all about your exciting journey
				excitements or fun along the way
				services or contributions along the way.
			Yoga is life's essence (with DAKM as the medium or driving force) - Life is composed of following phases of yoga evolution.
				About -
					We need to deploy both aaroh and avaroh methods in BJDK to do this.
					yes, we can't wait for the phases but there is a generic focus
					mostly based on current working of society
					Premature acceptance of last stage ignoring former stages can be immature.
					our goal is to perform these stages ourselves and try to assist others in their phases (whether naive or advanced) thru BJDK.
						sb doesn't want to take any assistance is their choice but ensuring availability is our part.
					Love at transcendence is the ultimate essence but quite far off to aspire immediately
						may not even be attractive in initial stages.
						but our eyes should always be to improve on the next neural network layer of yoga in light of final outcome.
					Every yoga phase suffers when the previous one isn't in a standardized and stable shape.
						Eg - after 40, Leadership is necessary for e1 but a must in KC (evam raj rishayo viduh - this knowledge for kings)
						actually others also can do - but it's somewhat risky for formally untrained and hence less refined or immature person
				Till 20 - Personal Yoga
					oneness of body, senses, mind, intel, ego, ourselves.
				Till 40 - Group Yoga (Home Yoga, Business or office Yoga)
					become one with your groups.
					Seva brings oneness.
					even enjoyment is best done as co-enjoyment and not independent enjoyment.
					But group level enjoyments and services (and personal side should be subservient to it)
				Till 60 - Social Yoga
					oneness with society at large.
					Legacy - society contributions thru SVAF - mastery already there, concrete transactional, concrete predictive, concrete prescriptive.
				Till 80 - Spiritual Yoga
					oneness beyond society - with God almighty.
					And if aaroh alone, then realizations and standardizations thru life stories - Life analytics.
					Abstract transactional, exploratory, prescriptive, etc.
					Exploring inner, outer, meta and transcendental world with full enthusiasm.
				Beyond - fine tuning yoga.
				wrt others
					we do our yoga nicely and assist them in their dharma to whatever extent possible.
					eg parents in spiritual yoga phase and you in group yoga phase
						it is expected that you do lots of SVAF and assist them in their life insights.
						But I can't do it all like cooking
						actually we can - to whatever degree in their ERP domain and strong in our own ERP domain
						We must do Leading the show else they have the unnecessary burden which won't let them focus on their phase.
						and as per previous traditions our complementary friend is supposed to assist us also in helping them and vv.
						Eg - wife should help in cooking and when I go to saure, then I should also help with some things.
						This is not how conservative systems work but the fact that wives also work, some aspects of HomeErp definitely need reconsiderations
							not denied but reconsidered like ishta goshti.
					Read aaroh pantha - personal help books in FND ABCDE and apply them for effective yoga.
    </About>
    <S>
		<B>
			About - Proof of Devotion
			Early morning in spite of dogs.
			Services and All life association in BJDK Yoga.
				Going wide and going deep both.
			Staying at VOICE
			No onion garlic even if it meant staying hungry.
			Following 4 regs - lifetime of not letting problem seep deeper from senses to mind or mental to intellect.
				nipping it in the bud. Never justifying and accepting conditioning (to standardize) and trying to continue fight like Arjuna in Kurukshetra.
				Newer innovative ideas to abate conditioning, exposure, make progress exceed restrictions (thru counter)
			Never forgoing the hunt for truth even if I had reason to deny the path.
				Not succumbing to lower pursuits (inebriation, etc) when really frustrated with material realm
				thoughts but didn't make them action items.
		</B>
		<J>
			All comparative study of all philosophies of life - refer relevant xml.
			Aaroh Panth of science being an integral part of being - DYS helps a lot to bridge with spiritual principles.
			My specialization in KC
				SME, Camps - VANY Syllabus.
				VMML VTW or Etiquettes - Deity Worship workshops (also individual departments)
				EBG, GSNS Camps
				Counselor Group
				Bhakti Shastri - 4 books with technical study.
				Itihas for Yugavtaars - Ramayan, Krishna book, MB.
				?SB (Vaibhav and vedanta)
				?CC (saurvabhaum)
		</J>
		<D>
		SQGrats
			HG PSP - hey STW VTW for you only you must attend.
			NIT JSR - Sab moh maya hai. I won't attend that session on Krishna is SPOG. Saurabh is not in our competition.
				Cow Milk started. Jack of 50-50 partitioned further into 25-25-50.
			Jumping the gate to enter. I won't stop him from using my cycle but sth is objectionable. More of a story than SQGrat.
			RSP - He is my old friend. Give this laddu to one with most beautiful dress. He will do something special (of course, besides grat this is also my regret)
			CCP - congratulating on good article.
			KTP - Reading the book and finishing Salted bread.
			Gauranga Pr - Why not use broom in vessels if it's all spiritual. Go have your meals. You heard Daily BG talks on Atma series - what's your name.
				you are still in Pune. Are you married. In Chowpatty - RSP students are very sharp - on asking what my soul means - it means you need to do more services.
				Should not tell KC is difficult that bluntly - yes I should take permissions from you, right.
				Kolkata dancing on Narsimha Arti.
			RNSM stroke in the head in Chowpatty on obeissance to him while walking past the stairs.
			Your Mangal arti is very absorbing - I didn't have it since Mandali Bhadra Pr last came.
			Devarayan Durga or sw - What a kirtan - that elicits emotions while it's going on - feels so heartfelt.
			Shayan Kirtans celebrations in YOGA phase. Shloka recitation - Brahma samhita st in the morning - drama anecdotes in MP and Quiz from notice board with awards.
			VAP - brutally honest. So, many praises in our festivals and celebrations but I have not kepts track of them.
			Even with beginners we can have SQGrats of preaching - like we awe our seniors. ISKCON is such a great acronym.
			Lots of KC centered deep friendships - many of them - some being Jyotirmoy Pr, etc - lots of revisits in Bangalore and even in Pune.
			Many many more but I never kept track of them b4.
				Amarendra Pr - forgot his initiated name - his world view was excellent - Shikha but working of street is still glorious.
		</D>
		<K>
		<BYStory>
			AboutSQ (BY centered) - Chanting (Bhajans) and Association (temples, places, preaching)
				BY - Scrum and Themes
			B4 - all TV series - MB, Ramayan, Sai Baba.
				Temple jai jagdeesh hare song. Calling from the dholak sound.
			2004 - Peer Baba. Baba Gabah.
			2006 - 1 thru 16 even b4 joining camps - inspired to control my mind - throat mala, adopting no tea, adopting onionless garlicless.
			2007 camps and joined voice - 16 rounds. BTG. But wasted interest in Krishna book chapters.
			2008 - Moving out to explore acads but unfortunate internal reality to explore NFP. Burst of tears. infrequent chanting.
				Later IDT stuffs. But also worldly artworks and poetry - wasted. Poetry revisits with KC connection.
				Some hare Krishna website chats. Where learning that it's towards 4 regs only as per SP - personal association.
			2009 - internal anger going to Nityanand's mercy giving place. Jagannath Puri Yatra and small experiences with Gauranga Pr.
			2010 - Mayapur visit and deep spiritual experience - Irregular chanting.
			2010 - I will be waiting, waiting for you - choosing Pune over Chandigarh swap. Atma series. Chanting few rounds - enacting drama alone.
				repeat exam - hearing lectures - Practically MOI to MOG thru MOP.
				Chanting searching for a devotee - Bangalore call from KTP and Chandan Pr - heard there was 7 - searching with bead bag to find 7 - met 1 with tilak whose guru would eat butter becoming Krishna - his room visit.
				Ritwik temple visit in Mysore - any sanyasi's here - who are you - I am only interested in KC not political stuff - they still dropped me at weird place with no bus.
			2011-2014 - 16 rounds resume with 4 regs excepts few break points. Many camps. Many rich experiences in temples, VOICE, etc.
				NVCC starts with donation, inauguration, movement, camps.
				Preaching in IISER - revisit from selection in NIT JSR IIT. beating dead snake. Preaching in I2IT. BD - company bus encounter. Preaching Gulbarg - wearing dress in other religious areas with frowns.
			2014 - Irregular chanting. Help extended to Lakshya Pr's family - smirk in front of deity.
			2015 - Spiritual revisit for NFP - regular 2 rounds and temple visits.
				Ritwik to ICC to Jagannath temple to SLNT (1st time free uber)
				YOGA VAP's place (where later VAP would come and I would still visit him - it is worse - it has always been temple)
				Bhakti center in Electronic City and Later Bhakti Center in Whitefield connected to SLNT - regular 2 rounds with festival super streaks - 64 rounds. 10 attentive MM starts.
				Sunday streaks - 16 rounds. Still some camps.
				Siemens - understanding the strong need to be atheist when it comes to expecting sth from Krishna.
			2020 - asking Krishna for mental help - depressed with greatest complaint against Krishan than others - reduced faith in trans, karma, etc
				but reinstated with a little thought and maturity in KC - that 3 doers always.
				Learning to be more practical while in KC and deeper insights into stages of Bhakti (importance of anarthas (inclusion of MOI based also) and dangers thereof)
				Importance of all the spiritual paths including atheism and aptheism, impersonalism and where they fit in the jigsaw - where they should be adopted and given up.
				1 round streak. With plan to chant Ekadashi extra and special days extra.
			<Misc>
				chanting laughing stories.
				chanting as responsibility not automatic "Be happy"
				chanting recording and listening phase - how well do I chant.
				chanting 16 rounds no eyes open phase - especially in Bangalore - on sunday streaks especially.
				SQ - Uncat - not arranged as per time.
					Gauranga Pr some interaction early on - praised thru 7 else but too much attention first and then no personal attention in GS CC study.
					RSP - 2 transitive sources of ego gratification - both so advanced that they appreciated this weird statement.
						burst while eating prasadam - when he just said plz take prasadam.
						pleasure of getting served prasadam from him in camps.
						He will settle in here.
					Laddu in exchange of tough words - are we qualified to blaspheme LCM's blasphemer - foolish of me - but greatness of him.
						did you mean that he is not qualified - ask forgiveness else it destroys bhakti - I immediately asked forgiveness and he disapproved but forgave with a laddu.
					Lamination from a Anant Bhagavan Pr - retained for a significant time - Radha Madhav - altar in many hostel rooms, later in Mysore, etc.
					Grihastha home visit in JSR. Gaudiya Math visit for Prasadam in holidays and arguments. Tear in his eyes on hearing about grand disciples of SP.
					BY is about 2 things - chanting and association (which includes temples, etc)
					DY is about pranayam and meditation.
					JY is about books and studies.
					KY is about VA.
					ISKCON Amritsar many temples - visit during Gaura Purnima - with external view. Another temple during corona - just a visit.
						Very beautiful deities - but seen in pixels.
					Nathdvara temple seen with gupta darshan. Fortune of colors. Many more temples and places visited.
					DY Patil Voice preaching - assistance.
					HG BGP personal association in Pune - Wednesday classes and later on TTC course - I longed for his association b4.
			</Misc>
		</BYStory>
		<DYStory>
			About - DY - Mantra Meditation, Naiti Meditation, Attention Meditation, Transcendental Meditation, Pranayama Breathing Meditations, Affirmations, motivations.
			Family of yoga - first done in school and stage performances relished.
			Morning yoga routine at Udhampur and lifestyle. Learning about dhirendra brahmacari
			asanas (landing on head) and forced MOG (raw veggies only) failed in NIT JSR; without onion garlic (1 meal at hostel) thru alu chops only - so unhealthy and turns out it had garlic all this while.
				some yoga at hostel
			Mysore - mild yoga. Pune - very little yoga. Some running later starts.
			yoga for youth phase in VOICE and lotus voice during GATE preparation.
				Mindfulness meditation by Sandeep Maheshwari.
				Guided Exercises on apps.
			Om chanting in Bangalore and morning regular yoga with 1:3 defined with breathing recordings.
				holiday streaks in morning yoga in garden.
				Sadhguru and others start.
				Exercises extreme means samadhi.
			Running (with morning motivation) or morning yoga titbits (with song or motivation or timer) in SLS Square.
				Affirmations b4 sleep on headset.
				Saturday streaks with regular Swami Ramdev school.
				Maun vrata discussions with SAP colleague.
					Others being - Introduced to Gaiya youtube, hindu academy, hindu protectors, IIT Kanpur talks which is what inspired 1 of the colleagues.
				Naiti Meditation on wake up - st scary that I am independent of my circumstances.
				Balancing meditations - Multi-dimensional analog reality with many numbers between 0 and 1. It's about song of ice and fire - balance in everything.
				Book on power of now. Shlokas b4 bed retire.
				Power of demigod worship on the special days leveraged - more as response to mindless opposition prevalent in pop.
			ASR -
				2020
					Planned naiti meditations to resume in morning.
					Saturday streaks stopped but very irregular yoga titbits with motivation going on.
					Plan of every day yoga streaks postponed
					Alphabetic Night Affirmations Streak.
					Amritsar evening run - half an hour powerful workout.
					Long walk streaks - 8 Km walk in evening in Amritsar.
						As part of Samsung walk - integrated with SAP Cloud for visualizations.
				Q1 2021
					Yin Yang (complementary dualities) realizations - darkness in light and vv.
					Mindfulness during the workday.
					Pranamyam + Motivation
				Q2 2021 Quarter
					Night Audiobooks.
					Pranayam + Affirmations.
					Chanting 2 book reading and improving the quality - Listen to 1 MM (Mindfulness over transcendence - superself)
				2021 June - MDNIT Delhi online Yoga Camp.
		</DYStory>
		<JYStory>
        JY - SMY, Bhakti Shastri, Sadhguru casual talks, Art of living casual talks.
			Courses and teachers journey.
				Most prominent Guides - SP, RNSM, RSP, CCP, Gauranga Pr, Govind Pr.
				Inspiration - SP, Humungous widespread culture of ISKCON Hare Krishna Swamis under SP and their disciples (different specializations)
				General Shelter - Many temples and extensions. Associations of wide variety of devotees.
				SMY - DYS, EBG, Camps - RSP (and whole jet age gurukul teachers - Pune, Kolkata) - 2006-2012
				Vaishnava Lifestyle Training (VOICE YOGA) VMML - Many Pune sr devotees. (2007-2008, 2010-2015) - Deity worship
				Practical KC - Radha Gopinath Prerana (personal), KTP applied BG study.
					More - Social applications, Pune and Mumbai Congregation on Ashram. Variety of lectures from Swamis and Prabhus.
				Ashram - GS Teams and NS Teams (2012-2015)
				TTC - BGP, Camp - RSP, CCP (2011-2015)
				Bhakti Shastri - CCP (2018-2021)
				MB, Ramayan, Krishna Lila - Govind Pr (Dharma application), ?CCP (insights, controversies, relevance), ?Amogh Lila Pr - (2021 - 2 sems)
					Krishna Lila - Krishna book and Radha Govinda Swami YouTube Playlists - baal lila, braj lila, dwaraka lila, saptah.
					Book - Krishna dharma Prabhu
				?SB - RNSM (Theme based - folder random files IDT, lila based - covered in VOICE) - (2022 2 semesters)
					Krishna Lila - Radha Govind Swami (Krishna book)
					Inspiration - Many, Mahavishnu Goswami Maharaj, CCP, etc
				?CC - BCS - 2023 spring
					Inspiration - RNSM, etc.
				?SP - Random Lectures from different IDT sources (search - Prabhupada, _ Lila, _ pastimes, etc - 2023 fall
					Books - Prabhupada Lilamrita
				future - Applied Spirituality (SVAF Applications at different scales - personal, relationships, society, etc)
					systematic, Revisits, numerous devotees with their specialities, etc.
				Uncat - SA course (Radha Govinda Swami's disciple), Kalacakra Krishna Pr, Sanskrit insights from a pune sanskrit scholar, etc.
					Countless inspiration from wide range of Swamis (SP Disciples) and Prabhus (recognized for their unique KC presentations)
		</JYStory>
		<KYStory>
			About - KY - VA Evolution Focus.
				Sakaam - Services (social or trans-spiritual) Sacrificing fruits portion - Charity for spiritual growth, for social well being.
				Nishkaam - Services sacrificing fruit (partly or completely) and work portion - services that please but no tangible outcome eg - FFL
				Nishkaam2 - Services sacrificing fruit and work outside personal space - takes tapa and no tangible outcome eg - BG Book distribution.
				BKY - Services sacrificing oneself (there exists no other personal space) - only interested in work for others or Krishna.
					Eg - Camps Services like vessel washing - heavy lifting, Temple Services rendered. VOICE services all kinda (more like ashram or home in its worldly projection but trans in nature)
			Very good at acads but irresponsible st in college - NPTEL - no exposure of work culture.
			performer without incentive.
			Irresponsible with no interest in work although very smart at stuffs. Reflected in time escapes - it's time to go back home else next day wake up SQ stuff.
			Alternative fortunate to find professorship which I was anyways interested - genuine work but sh didn't work out.
				walks to solve other problems around work.
			Bad Twist - Yearning for work - hearing SP that better work for free than not work. Broke with all money gone.
			Gate wasted cuz of distracted mind. Calls start from home - frequent calling. Family Supportive of bad twists of life.
				walks to figure out my life's direction - intuition that sth very special is coming.
				extremely Demotivated - Feeling I should not be staying at VOICE - but preparing for GATE - lead of IIITB from quora.
				Drawn into CS stuffs in the mind even if some govt exams like SSC tier 2 than UPSC civil services for tier 1.
			IIITB good hard work and genuine interest. as expected depth with revisits.
				online stuffs and friendliness and inspirations from colleagues. Projects were game changers.
			Siemens big lead thru OOP.
			SAP Labs - big lead into humungous softwares.
				All acads leveraged including Big Data, ML, etc.
			Recruitments in biggies Huawai Labs RnD, Samsung Labs, Consulting for ML, etc.
			<Donations>
				About - To be merged with above.
				Prasadam distribution in VOICEs.
				Easy donations with punctuality.
				Some donation at every place.
				NVCC 3 months.
				Birthday donations - cows, books, etc.
				Gratitude of any favors - online drama, online songs, transitive favors, IDT, temple or bhakti center favors, etc.
				Diwali donations for diya. Old sources donations - kolkata, pune - old gratitude and being a patron. Narsimha yajna, etc.
				Mayapur donations from a distance - gesture of support. Pandharpur.
				Goshala donations. Temples renovations, ganga project, sadhguru, COVID fund, etc.
				Delhi, Dwaraka, Vrindavan thru people. Vrindavan medium for 7's donation - do you want to give or not?
				Food Plates packing and distribution, Temple food for life distribution. Food for devotees cooking, carrying, packing, dispatching - all services at various places.
				Tried wiki donations but they asked too much information.
			</Donations>
		</KYStory>
		</K>
        <EgoSpecific> Covers Trans Spirituality
            Objective
                B and J
                    Educational Qualifications
                        NIT J VOICE - DYS, Sphurti, DD Series, VANY Courses
                        IIT KGP - Sankalpa, Utkarsh, VTW
                        Pune - EBG, BG Sloka Series, ISKCON Leadership Course by BGP Pr Course, TSS CCP listen streak
                            Nishtha, Ashray, GS / NS Camps
                        Bangalore - Bhakti Shastri Online (Isho, NOI, NOD, ToDo - BG)
                    Skills
                        Vaishnav Etiquette, Musical Instruments, Singing, 1-1 casual inspiration (preaching)
                        Services - Food For Life Distribution, BG Marathon, ?Fund Collection, Transcription, cleaning and temple services.
                            QA on class, Singing
                        Department In charge - 
                            Bulk Sabji/ Grocery Purchase (JSR, VIT) - Quality identification, Bargaining for bulk purchase, arrange auto, heavy lifting, Reimbursements.
                            Account management - Book keeping, reimbursements, personal fulfillment of gaps, etc.
                            Notice Board Department - Inspiring Articles from different sources procured and pasted, Quiz weekly for awards.
                            Book Distribution inventory management - Book keeping.
                            Deity Department - utensils, altar cleaning, morning puja schedule, decoration plans, etc.
                            Utensils - assignment to all devotees in round robin.
                            milk - procurement, delivery, PR, payments and devs advanced payments, boiling, mensuration, stage/ board inspiration.
                            Morning Program Incharge - Lect, Sr Devs request, QA, Orchestrating schedules, etc.
                            Garland Purchasing in JSR - Standardizing the rates, exploring all options, keeping them in fear.
                            Cylinder brining Seva in JSR and Hinjewadi - vehicles, personal, auto arranging, maneuvering thru crowd, advance booking.
                            ?Cleaning - Altar floor cleaning, 
                            Event Management - When all paraphernalia was carried to some camp and somethings got lost and I paid for them.
                    Case Studies and Projects - ??
                D and K
                    Professional Relevant Projects - 
                        About 
                            The purpose of any project is preaching (being essence or prayojan) - iow, culture of inspiration in DS.
                            basis is books (sambandha)
                            utility or engagement (abhidhyeya)
                            Vision success dependent on purity (oil that runs the machine - gratitude is internal)
                        Radha Govinda Kolkata
                            Jagannath Puri Voice - Rourkela Project intiative, M.Tech Preaching.
                            Krishna Gatipur Voice
                        Radha Kunjabihari Pune
                            Atmanivedan YOGA - Accounting, etc
                                Initiative Projects - Gurbarg, IISER, I2IT Pune, etc.
                            Atmanivedan Lotus VOICE - Cleaning, etc.
                            Atmanivedan YOGA2 - Deity Worship, etc.
                        Radha Vrindavan Chandra
                            Vraj Dham VOICE - Utensils washing, Milk Department, etc.
                        Jagannath Temple ICC Bangalore
                        Jagannath Temple Seshadripuram Bangalore
                        SLNT (Gandharvika Giridhari Mandir)
                            Whitefield Bhakti Center
                    Personal or other Projects
                        Visited Temples - Radha Gopinath, Radha Giridhari, Vrindavan temples, Jagannath Puri, Mayapur, Hampi, Udupi, Pandarpur, Dehu.
                Details - doesn't apply
                    Technical Skills
                    Domain Skills
                    Management Skills
                    Additional Qualifications
                    Personal Interests
			Uncat - Grand Story or Larger Narrative
				VOICE (10+) - SMY Books - KC Basics.
					Basic Concepts of KC - SP Small Medium Books (KC Basics), Vani Lecture Series (DD, Prerana, SP, RNSM, Boiling the milk)
					SMY camps - Utkarsh (DYS), Sankalpa (Faith and Doubts), Sphurti (Mind)
					//Backward compatibility with Prahlad School Phase and Lots of foreshadowing (FS)
				20s - Personal Application Phase
					YOGA - ABG (Personal Applications) - EBG. Prerana.
						FS - EBG since VOICE.
					VOICE Revisit - GS NS.
						FS - B2G, Ashray Camp.
					Temple - KC Culture, Preaching inspiration.
						FS - Preaching camp or TTC (Preaching foreshadowing), Guru Disciple Course, STW VTW (KCC FS)
				30s - Deep Study Phase
					Bhakti Shastri.
						FS - All throughout the journey. Nishtha Camp.
					Lila Smaran (30+) - SB, CC, SP.
						FS - all throughout the journey.
					?Wide Study - Other schools basics (FS from Bhakti Shastri, etc)
				40s - Sharing Phase
					Preaching Phase (40+) - All Revisits + Sharing
						More of everything - More SP Lila, More Lord Devotee's lila, etc.
					Social Application Phase (50+)
					Advaita Sabha (75+) - Crash Course or sincere preparation for exam starts, Life Reflections.
        </EgoSpecific>
    </S>
    <V>
        About - Varna is about being best producer in the social ecosystem (career)
        <B> about - Life Story Tracing FDDL and ego targets
            About - there's a possibility to merge Power and Money also - but let's not do that - then focus of FDDL maybe lost.
            <Power>
                About - job security, politics, rising to top, expressions of power
                    Proof of IQGrats (sincere) from others - better if broadcast, but unicast also good.
                    Also, sheer action of IQGrats being broadcast or recognized - even if not appreciated - eg - new development demo or even KT.
                NIT JSR - Paper writing on VOIP. NPTEL Lecture downloads until made public.
                Infy - Offer from foreign. Bank Finnacle.
                VIT Pune - Lab sessions from him are different ballgame - very learnable.
                Siemens - writing mail testimony he is really good. Suggestion to take regular sessions.
                BYD - Mail to all for faster verification of ML of scanned invoice.
                    Entrusted with production support team.
                    Award from Managers.
                NSME - My devp demo ew on ML.
                    Our team singled out for POC of NSME and we delivered it - Navigating thru uncertainties.
                    Sessions on what's being made.
                    PO validating that I was being underused as per my capability.
                SIOT - Idea for Ticket classification appreciated.
                    Suggestion to take up more work for better work being entrusted.
            </Power>
            <Money>
                Infy - 10 - 3.5, ?4.5
                VIT Pune - 13 - 4.2
                Siemens - 16 - 3.5+Diet (12 otherwise)
                SAP - 17 - 7.5 (and one time 2.5)
                    18 - 8.02, 8.35
                    19 - 9.01, 9.39
                    20 - 10.19
                    21 - 10.69 (9.70+1.00)
                Leads
                    19 - Huawei - !16/17 (refused 19)
					20 - DS Comps (PwC, etc) - !13/14.
                    20 - Samsung - !19 (Asked but lockdown so no response)
					20 - Internal Change to SAP IOT - PHI
                    21 - Empty fire - !Amazon written 1.5/2 (cuz optimal) solved, Amazon Alexa, Amazon kindle, Amazon AWS resume found attractive.
					21 - Samsung Networking - 18.40 (=15.77F+2.63V1 + 1.8V2) and 1 time 2 (B) => 22.20 for first year.
					21 - PayTM - 19 (=19+0) and 1 time 2L for 18 months retention.
					21 - Grey Scale AI - 29 (25F + 4V + 2B + RSU was possible) (Free hand offer - 22F + 5F + 1B + RSU)
            </Money>
            <Contributions>
            About - All Projects Done - be able to tell tech, etc used, contributions, roles played; challenges faced
                some really interesting problems you feel proud to solve
                This has to be abstracted out of project level domain details in interest of technically what is done
                consulting abstraction is also possible but that can be done later on from source if needed.
				can think of writing social contributions as company visions or end product making society a different place.
            NIT JSR
                Java Media Player
                SQL Administration
            Infy - 3.5
                SEZONL
                Manual Testing for AT&T
                Expert Support for BT
            VIT Pune - 4.2
                Teaching Programming
            IIIT B
                eBAY and REST on top
                ACT Project - Testing Automation using Scripts
                Semantic Web on NoSQL (Neo4J)
                Stackoverflow analytics
            Siemens - 3.5+Diet intern (12 otherwise)
                Best execution engine for a given query - Data Science to metrics collection using program
                Space Optimization Engine for NoSQL Engines - Cassandra, HBase, etc
                Design Proposed for handling IOT sensor data
            SAP - 7.5 (2.5 over 2 years)
                Business By Design - mid year hikes,
                    End to End ERP Business Suite
                NSME - appreciation awards
                    End to End ERP Business Suite on NodeJS Express PostSQL tech stack.
                SAP IOT - Big Data Analytics for SAP IOT Data Streams.
            </Contributions>
            <Egos>
            Ego Targets
                DevOps
                    EPIC - ?; Backlog - Spark Streaming.
                DataScience
                    EPIC - ?; Backlog - Spark ML.
                Systems
                    EPIC - ?; Backlog - CF.
                Research
                    EPIC - ?; Backlog - Book Reader.
            </Egos>
			<ProofOfDevotion>
				NITJSR - Left my heart VOICE for studying subjects; Travelled far and wide for NPTEL; devoting hours studying courses.
				Infy - Working in office till 11 pm almost everyday learning in the campus, giving up comforts of fancy hostel.
					If I said it, I will stay even if I do nothing.
					If I wanna switch just say it. Not ideal.
				VIT - continue even in when it's demanding and solving.
				IIITB - Staying up nights and devoting every hour I had in pursuit of excellence. Learning from peers and contributing.
				BYD -
					Working thru weekends for ticket.
					Creating VB Script to make systems faster - working thru nights and weekends. Even improvements accepted.
					Bug caused SAP GUI to fail - skipped lunch to go to previous version using debugger.
				NSME - Not leaving the team in start up phase of crisis and stretching to make it work with hacks and knowledge sharing.
				SIOT
					Working even in covid extreme weakness
					Not stretching working - working over the night - accepting perfectness of the application
			</ProofOfDevotion>
        </B>
        <J> technologies I know
            <AppsUsed> SaaS - being client of to give some service
                AWS
                Outlook
                Word
                Photoshop
                Networking - TCP Dump, WinSCP, Putty, Moba, ssh.
                Postman, Slack, Browser Debugging.
                Tableau, etc.
            </AppsUsed>
			<Management>
				JIRA, Ticket Queues - BCP, CSS NG, ServiceNow, etc.
				Scrum, Kibana, TDD (Test Driven Development), Pair Programming.
			</Management>
            <Domain>
                FIN
                SCM - SRM, SCM, CRM
                HCM
                Foundations - Auth, Security, BC, etc.
            </Domain>
            <DesignTime> Regex, HW, POC.
                <Tools> can use an app as a server or for extension.
                    Excel, Browsers.
                </Tools>
                <CodeManagement>
                    Version Management - Github
                    Build Management - Ant, Maven
                    Integration - REST API, SOAP API, 
                    Parsing - Regex, CUP Parser, Lex/Yacc.
                    ByD Specific - Event Manager, Message Manager, Change Manager, PDAO.
                    Quality - JMeter.
                </CodeManagement>
                <Frontend>
                    HTML, JS, CSS, Bootstrap
                </Frontend>
                <Libraries>
                    <ReuseUtils>
                        UI Automation - Selenium
                        JAVA Email Integration
                        Clients - SparkClient, RestClient, etc.
                        API for Persistence - GSON, YAML, XML, JSON, Text Files, Properties, Cassandra, etc.
                            Properties
                        Log4J
                    </ReuseUtils>
                    <LanguageFeatures>
                        Memory Manipulations - Pointers, DSA.
                        IO - Files, Databases, console, etc.
                        Low level programming
                            OS - Threads, Sockets,
                            IPC, System calls.
                        OOP - encapsulation, abstraction, inheritance, and polymorphism
                            Generics, Exception handling, Collections, Reflections, Garbage Collection.
                        Functional - Async Await, Callbacks, Closures, Lambda, etc.
                    </LanguageFeatures>
                    <Frameworks> Everything is done - you need to only set properties or customize the code to suit you - using exits; Diagrams with explanations
                        XWeb Client Frameworks - Bootstrap, React, Angular, Vue, OpenUI5 using FIORI, Silverlight, etc.
                        Microservices - Jersey, Spring - MVC, Security, boot, persistence, etc.
                        <WebFrameworks>
                            DOTNET - IIS Server.
                            ABAP - ?
                            JAVA - Swings, Servlet, JSP, Hibernate, J2EE, Struts, Jersey.
                            NodeJS - Express, Router
                            JAVA Spring - MVC, Boot, Security, Persistence, Model.
                        </WebFrameworks>
                        <ApplicationFrameworks>
                            DOTNET 3.5
                            ByD Descriptive/Exploratory Analytics Framework, PD Framework
                        </ApplicationFrameworks>
                        <UtilityFrameworks>
                            MR / Spark Libs - Batch Processing (Language, SQL), Spark Streaming, XSparkML, XSparkGraphX.
                        </UtilityFrameworks>
                        <Testing>Start Scripting for testing, BOUM2 for Integration Testing, JUnit, ABAPUnit</Testing>
                    </Frameworks>
                </Libraries>
                <Langauges> Scripts included
                    G4 - SQL (MySQL, Oracle, MS-SQL), Hive, Pig, Shell Scripting, NoSQL (Cassandra, MongoDB, HBase)
                    G3 - C, R, Java, C#, C++, Scala, Python, JS, TS, ABAP.
                        Functional - JS, TS, R, Scala, Python.
                        OOP - JAVA, C#.
                            Java Language Features - Generics, Threads, Lambda, etc.
                        Procedural - C, CPP, ABAP.
                        system calls,
                    G2 - Assembly Language
                </Langauges>
                <IDE> 
                    UI - UIDesigner
                    ?IntelliJ, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Ginee, Netbeans, RStudio, Notepad++, Textpad, ABAP Logon
                </IDE>
            </DesignTime>
            <PaaS>
                About - Read Servers which are Concerned about runtime not design time
                    so Languages / Libs don't exist here only binaries.
                <TierServers>
                    Web Server - Apache Tomcat, Glassfish, LanguageSpecific Servers like NodeJS.
                    Application Server
                        Language Servers - C# dotnet Server, Node Server, ABAP Server, JVM Server.
                    Utility Servers
                        Database Server
                            NoSQL - Cassandra, HBase, Redis, MongoDB, Neo4J, etc.
                            RDBMS - PostGre, MS SQL, MySQL
                            Data Models - RDBMS, XML, JSON, Text, Semantic Web, Data Warehousing, NoSQL,
                        Big Data - Spark Framework, Spark Job Server.
                        Messaging Servers - Kafka Brokers
                        Model Verification - TOC - NuSMV (Model Checking or software verification)
                        Compilers - yacc, lex, CUP, etc.
                </TierServers>
                BigData - Hadoop Platform Ecosystem, MapReduce Framework, Spark Framework.
                Ops - Jenkins, Cloudfoundry, Kubernetes, Docker.
            </PaaS>
            <IaaS> aka Bare metal we procure from online services or products.
                Servers - AWS, Azure, GCP, Alibaba, SCP, Private Cloud.
                Virtualization - OS - VMWare, IOT, Arduino, Raspberry Pi.
                    OS - Windows XP, 7, 8, vista, 10. Mac 15 Catalina (Darwin).
                        Linux - Ubuntu, KaliLinux, CentOS, ?Redhat, ?OpenSuse
                Networking - F5 VPN, SCP, SSH, etc
                Storage - Windows FTP, Desktop file sharing (All apps in turn using cloud storage like mails, communicators)
                    Platforms based storages like OneDrive, Google Cloud, etc.
                    HDFS - on Public Cloud, SAP Private Cloud, On Premise, VMs.
                Systems - HCL, Asus, Lenovo Thinkpad, HP, MacBook Pro.
            </IaaS>
            <Misc>Kafka, Ambari, Hortonworks</Misc>
        </J>
        <D>
            About - 
                List of Problems Solved with ingenuity - smart and clever approach; engineering tested here (how excellently managed all techs to an end); POCs, Ideas proposed
                Can cover all engineering and architectural details
                List all the IQGrats.
            ADT and DS known - Set, List, Tree, DAG, Graphs; handling strings
            Algos - Brute Force, Divide and Conquer, Greedy, Dynamic Programming, etc.
            Design Patterns - Strategy, Singleton, Factory Design, etc.
            Courses done (or capabilities at disposal) - Compiler Design, Approximation Algorithms.
			Noteworthy Instances - Otherwise there are numerous.
				KV - Yes, you can do it > 90; topping the district or state.
				NITJSR - NPTEL - everything finished.
					Security Program written. Graphics programs appreciated.
					Digital Electronics applaud for solving.
				Infy - Windows crash during middle of exam. Scribbled everything afresh after a water break.
				VIT - In Labs sessions he is a different beast.
				IIITB - solving all problems in Discrete Maths, personal guidance from many profs.
				SAP
					Debug surpassed to reset the version to old when NGAP transactions started failing
					ability to download data to analyse a ticket - like tracing the stacks of execution for 2 exits where data changed!
					Shell scripts for fast implementations of Hadoop execution engines.
					using java code to create API for custom queries on hadoop execution engines.
					web scraping for presto to read performance - cuz REST API was not known.
						web scraping for desktop images.
					Subscript matching assignments
					excel vba for reducing efforts of manipulating data details from REST JSON response of ML based Leonardo API.
					IDEA - Ticket runtime assignment
        </D>
        <K>
            About - All Projects Done - be able to tell tech, etc used, contributions, roles played; challenges faced
                some really interesting problems you feel proud to solve
                This has to be abstracted out of project level domain details in interest of technically what is done
                consulting abstraction is also possible but that can be done later on from source if needed.
			<Personal>
				VB in Excel for data cleaning and organizing
				OpenCV for nephew photos detection from huge folder
				Subtitles Changer
				Many Text reorgs
				MMA - Micro Management Analytics for personal Self (later OneNote)
				Auto-Desktop Background changing thru scraping
				Scraping thru Selenium for Presto until its REST is found
				Newer Facade Queries in Cassandra (not personal)
				CF Personal App
			</Personal>
			<NITJSR>
            NIT JSR
				Idols - Pradeep Panigrahi, Amit Happy.
                Graphics Programs Pixel programming, Network Security Programs.
                SQL Administration - Paper Presentations.
                Java Media Player - UML diagrams.
			</NITJSR>
			<Infy>
            Infy - 3.5
				Idols - "I want to help but don't have time" guy, Mayank, KT lady for maintenance, Vibhor, Presentation guy onboarding.
                Contributions
                    SEZONL
						System Design
							Front End - ASP Pages.
							Application - C#
								Framework - DOTNET 3.5 (even certifications I got)
							DB - MS SQL
                        Traceability Matrix from Customer Requirements to Implementation
                        Traceability - SRS Requirements to Implementation mapping - Sequential Diagram for faster development, better maintenance thru easy debugging.
                    Manual Testing for ATnT
                        Application Testing - Regression Based Testing, System Testing, Test Case Generation.
                        LINUX scripts for data generation, QTP or selenium for data generation for stress testing
                        running UI scripts for scenario coverage
                    Expert Support for BT
                        Maintenance – Customer Issues Handling, Process Integration Message Handling.
                        Message management
                        SQL scripts writing for application data consistency.
			</Infy>
			<VITPune>
            VIT Pune - 4.2
				Idols - Vishal Kaushal Sir, Karthick Sir, Ras Vigrah Sir.
                Contributions
                    Computer Programming Concepts
                    Guide for Programming Projects
                Teaching Computer Programming - Structured and OOPS.
                    invented ideas - online google form based quiz, etc.
                Guide for Projects - Tic Tac Toe, Console Based Marketing Software, etc.
			</VITPune>
			<IIITB>
            IIIT B
				Idols - Anish, Anjani, Mayur Bhaiya, Shishir
                EBay Prototype and REST Services
                    what
                        Bootstrap, Jquery, JSP, AJAX, Windows, Eclipse, Apache Tomcat 9, Structs, Java, Mysql, MVC.
                    contribution
                        Management - work assignment dynamics, etc.
                            //ability to list all management lessons learnt from professor
                        Schema Design, and UML Diagrams - Use Case, Sequence, DFD, etc on paper and StarUML.
                        Purchase Scenario Coverage - division by application areas (and not technologies - cuz e1 wants to learn)
                ACT Project - Abstract to Concrete Testing Framework
                    what - CUP Parser, JAVA, Selenium, Solvers (Linear Programming), Paper reading.
                    contribution - architectural ideas, Random data types generations, Web Design representation in invented format, Parsing the format to build a graph
                        navigation thru the graph for finding all the paths, formulation of equations for all the paths, using solvers to come up with answers.
                        build test cases using the answers, abstract to concrete conversion, running selenium scripts on the concrete test cases.
                Semantic Web modeled in Neo4J
                    what - XML Parser, XML, Neo4J, MongoDB for evaluation, OWL for semantic web, Bootstrap, Apache Tomcat.
                    contribution -
                        Application of Rules of Reasoning to infer based on existing edges - eg - isFather and isBrother means isSon relationship, etc.
                        Modeling of a college data model
                Stackoverflow analytics
			</IIITB>
			<Siemens>
            Siemens - 3.5+Diet (12 otherwise)
				Idols - Vikram Singh Chandel, Priyansh Saxena, Varsha Raveendran, Vinay Sudhakaran.
                what
                    VM - VMWare, Hortonworks HDP2.0, CentOS, Windows SCP, Moba for SSH, etc.
                    Libraries - Properties File, Logger, Random Number generation Types.
                    UML online Softwares like Visual Paradigm
                    Hadoop Technologies - HIVE, Spark, Drill, Presto, Ambari REST API.
                    NoSQL (Cassandra, MongoDB, HBase)
                    JAVA, REST API, Bootstrap for display, JUnit for Testing, Threading for faster access
                    Factory Design Pattern, Singleton
                Contribution
                    Benchmarking Studio - Best execution engine for a given query
                        TPCDS, customizing queries as per syntax (using regex)
                    Query Metrics Collector - Space Optimization Engine for NoSQL Engines
                        Ideas - compressors, trend avoiding algorithm based on a paper, distributions that perform best.
                        randomly generated data of different data types as per specific distribution.
                        collection of running the application on AWS with specified data besides local cloud.
                    Design Formulation for IOT based Project
                Runtime Selection of Best Hadoop Execution Engines for a query on Big Data
					System Design
						Front end - Command Line utility, Bootstrap UI for Healthcheck
						Application - REST App for Healthcheck
							JAVA Application - Regex, JUnit, Hadoop Tools APIs, Design Patterns - Factory, Singleton
							VM, Private Cloud, AWS
						Persistence and Execution Engines - TPCDS in HDFS over HIVE, Drill, Presto, Spark.
                    Solution
                        Runtime Selection of Best Hadoop Execution Engines for a query on Big Data
                        HDFS, HIVE, Drill, Presto, Spark, JAVA, JAVA Regex, JUnit, REST API, Bootstrap UI
                        Knowledge of Design Patterns, Logger, Property File employed to create the framework.
                        Used TPCDS data store to test the execution metrics for queries run on candidate Hadoop ecosystem tools.
                        REST API used to fetch results from AMBARI after every query run.
                        Handled multiple formats like text, JSON/ XML, CSV
                        Regression didn't seem to be the best technique to be employed and hence classification was proposed for the same.
                Selecting best NoSQL Database for storing stream data from sensors and algorithms to minimize the disk storage for the same
                    System Design
						Front End - Command Line Utility, Excel (for analytics results showcasing), R for Visualizations.
						Application - JAVA Application, Design Patterns - Factory, etc
							Mutex thru semaphores.
						DB - Cassandra, HBase, Influx, Text - CSV, JSON, etc.
                    Solution
                        Adding another NoSQL tool influx to the existing framework.
                        Generation of random data types (numbers, strings, etc) following a certain distribution to simulate the sensor behaviors.
                        Collection of metrics and visualization in excel
                        Creating types of queries in java which are not supported by the tool out of the box. Eg – Hbase total records.
                        Implementation of slope algorithm to minimize the data objects instances stored by HBase.
                Design Proposal for handling IOT Data Stream
                    Skills - Diagrams - starUML, LucidChart Online
                    Solution
                        Proposed a Design for the upcoming application.
			</Siemens>
			<SAP>
            SAP - 7.5 (2.5 over 2 years)
				<BYD>
                Business By Design - End to End ERP Business Suite
					Idols - Saurav Nahata, Nikhil Bhaji, Sunil Bhandarkar, Sunil Kumar, Karthik, Vishesh, Krishna, Hitesh, Mukesh.
                    Specification
                        Exposure Large scale ERP applications, Suite in a box - end to end business processes support (SCM, SRM, CRM, FIN, HCM, Foundation)
                    Design
						System Design
							Front End - UIDesigner in XML and Ruby - Framework by core team and exit code handled by Front end team for handling these xml design time and json data at runtime.
							Application on ABAP - Exit code across BOs in functional areas.
								Design Time Tool - SAP GUI for Coding, Configuration (Model Driven for all master, BC data), and Design.
								Framework - NGAP (Fork of NW)
								PI over application areas thru XML (RabbitMQ or Kafka not known)
							Persistence abstracted by OpenSQL - Internally HANA.
						Design Contributions
							Experience of NGAP Application Platform, Multiple Application Frameworks, Communications across Application Areas; SRM Application Area Development
							Trace framework thru debugging to tell which configuration is missing or where the data provided for next exit was insufficient or if framework needs a change
								very small changes like variable retaining old value so clear - very corner case like unit price rounding followed by total price rounding
								loss of precision causes PO for approval to take place although shopping cart said otherwise - business scenario suffers.
								?exposure to real world scenarios for design patterns - command pattern, factory, singleton, Strategy, Subscriber, etc.
                    Implementation
                        Tools
                            Eclipse on ABAP, SAP GUI IDE for Web based IDE development
                            HANA DB, MAX DB - Materialized Views for Analytics
                        Features
                            Fully Model Driven Software Development (configurations at different levels Developer, Key user, end user, etc)
                            Analytics - Managing OLAP Systems - UI, Internal development tool, framework, MAX DB Materialized view secondary storage.
                            Task Management - for end user attentions from messages failed across applications, etc.
                            Output Management - pdf generation and sending by email. Using XML and Template (Adobe LiveCycle Designer) to Adobe Server.
                            Workflow management - Approvals based on configured BO conditions, mapped to task management, Exception Handling in SIV, etc.
                        UI
                            ABAP, Fiori, UI5, Silverlight, Inbuilt version management, Transport Requests Management for DevOps.
                            UI Development thru internal tool
                            RUBY Scripts on internal tool, javascript, html;
                        Integrations - Synchronous (A2X for tools like excel, etc) and Asynchronous (within or outside tenants)
                            RMI or RFC as SAP calls it.
                        ABAP to Typescript conversion - regex to create templates ready to use. (but didn't use it)
                        User Stories (in short and incomplete - refer to byd for details)
                            GDPR LXP, eInvoicing, Scanned Invoicing from text (support for intercompany), Scanned Invoicing from pdf, PO Reminder Letters (dunning), Manual PR,
                            Link PRs to PO, PO Schedule Lines, IFRS, OLAP Reports (GDPR Data protection related, and more)
                            Scanned Invoice to SIV BO - from text, from pdf (REST API, using OAuth1), from pdf on email, from pdf on folder thru collaboration window
                            Manual PR QAF ECO
                            shopping cart mobile app
                            GDPR implementation adoption - writing code for BO exits - filtering and bo name.
                            delivery sch lines
                            Link PR Items with PO - action
                            Document Destroy GDPR implementation
                            Background job filtering out for health checks
                            PO root price components in Output Form
                            Kit items price calculation issue
                            Invoice scanning review screen
                            Master data PPS gaf.
                            Create SIV From SIS - BO Updates Determinations, etc.
                                    date User Fields from API fields in SIS BO - regex
                                    PO reference so SIV created from SIS
                                    Able to delete PDF files 1 or multiple.
                            Update A2X Web Service - Read PO. A2A etc updates.
                            Invoice scanning from text - Pattern Correction for Scanned Invoice from Text - problem of image having a pattern - that matches ditto fine tuned the regex.
                            Email PDF to SIS BO Changes
                                    SIS only permit PO that exist in system
                            Data Source fields addition, updates.
                            GDPR - BO Retention supplement
                                    GDPR Person Deletion adoption.
                            IFRS16 Lease Contract Payment Schedule Status Handle - Authorization handling included.
                                    Lease Contract Run Remove Unauthorized Companies
                            Excel integration - catch exceptions
                            Cost Distribution for Goods Returned, All kinds of scenarios coverage. Additional cost distribution items
                            Translation - OneChina Adoption also, otherwise b4 also.
                            SIV Attachment Update (EC mappings)
                            SIV Template supress errors
                            BTM Task for ISI GSA request with bad PO Item ref - XML fails, inform user on UI with expected action.
                            GSA expected read only flag as per business scenario state. IMAT, Finish resume PO properties. Shopping Card Retrieval COBL SO ref for Proj
                            SME - Create SIV From PO, Make Payment on SIV and message handling.
                                    SIV OWL Filters - selections and filters on CIP.
                            Lease contract not found error messages - many such.
                            Intrastat added error message for clarity
                            Avoid dump for convert key to node id on item node - lots of framework level changes or adoptions even in PD - like clear the buffer.
                            Product Category w/o Product Assignment not possible;
                            Z-prefix CDT Days Due and Fixed Date both active together - Enable parameters of days, month and fixed date for payment terms maintenance
                            More -
                                management very well understood roll up, drill down.
                                Consulting related discussions for end desirable product for end users, AUnits creation, JS Mocha Tests created and suggested.
                                Design discussions like e-invoicing using word cloud
                                Testing - BOUM2 and START scripts creation, run, correction - CRUD.
                                Deployments - Hotfixes, patches, VP, EP.
                                    Bug fixes and extensions in practically every BYD implementations, deployment assistance once using SPC (Service Provider Cockpit)
                                Maintenance at all levels L1, L2, L3 -
                                    Consulting - helps thru call 1:1, 1:n, consulting; Customer concerns directly visible. VH and over weekend support.
                                    corrections - UI workarounds, runtime corrections (debugger), back end DB corrections;
                                    code corrections, customer influence or extensions or future commits.
                    Testing
                        Unit Testing (AUNIT), Internal Tools for Testing - Integration testing (BOUM2), System Testing (Start WebIDE, Stand alone), Regression Based Testing (RBT)
                    Support
                        Creation and maintenance of tools for maintenance and support - along with custom reports writing for backend correction, DB Corrections.
                        Consultations to customers for adapting software to their business needs or suggesting work arounds
                        ABAP Debugger, User change log and few days interaction log for code correction
                    Misc - communications
				</BYD>
				<NSME>
                NSME - End to End ERP Business Suite on NodeJS Express PostSQL tech stack.
					Idols - Kavitha, Deepak, Vishesh Agrawal, Siddharth, Sunil Parvartikar, Chandan.
					System Design
						Front End - UIDesigner in XML and Javascript (not Ruby) - Framework by core team and exit code handled by Front end team for handling these xml design time and json data at runtime.
						Application on Node Express Router - Exit code across BOs in functional areas.
							Design Time Tool - VS Code for Coding, Configuration (Model Driven for all master, BC data), and UI XML Design Storage (later)
							Framework - X4 (bugs or debugging for undesirable behaviors)
							PI (Process Integration) over application areas thru XML (RabbitMQ or Kafka not known)
						Persistence abstracted by Framework Libs calls to Postgres.
                    what and contributions
                        Specifications - Fresh scoping the application for different packages.
                            Cross Functional works - Pricing, Master data, Foundation task creation, FIN coding block.
                        Design - Fresh implementations so usage of many design patterns - singleton, strategy, template method, DAO, command, Visitor, etc.
							Framework Dependability Discussions / hacks - working on systems that are still stabilizing and not robust
								raising bugs (eg colleagues on UI)
								Debugging thru framework for undesirable behavior and explain to the team for code change / config updates or completeness.
									?saw working of an application server end to end.
									internal hacks to circumvent framework limitations until next release thru making changes in local branch.
								UI lack of dependability and adaptation
									Didn't support Ruby anymore but JS
										So, and Retrieve design time Ruby to JS converted from persistence of BYD and plug there and debugging thru SAP UI5 framework and exits involved many a times.
									Manual XML changes when UIDesigner changes didn't reflect.
									Retrieving Front end XML from persistence for correctness - whether changes reflect correctly on activation or save - all DB names figured thru code or names.
							Created many stubs and skeletons for experimental pilot project
								Also, suggested folder structures for organizing, codes, refactoring, etc
                        Implementations - GIT, VS Code, NPM, Node Express, Sinon, REST API.
							UI Conversions in FIN - enabled thru ABAP Script (Not my idea)
                            Promises, callbacks, decorators, Postgres, HANA, etc. Debugging in TS, JS.
                            Implemented Determination, validation, action, folder structure organization; used libraries like request.
                            ML API integration for shopping cart approval - confidence as input for user and auto-approve as per user's choice. Configurable to write into a file.
                                Mass Approval (set confidence in process map and play approvals in 1 go)
                        Testing - Mocha Chai Unit Testing, Integration Testing, Sys and UAT by different teams in china.
                            Unit Test also across lcp calls assuming all validations and determinations in place. Not class specific.
                                UT cuz of less granular tests at attribute level
                                integration test should focus on less granular stuff - PR is created, PO is in this status - scenario specific.
                        Support - Logger Service for us to read the logs and tell what went wrong.
                        Misc - start up feel, Manager roles understood better. Concept of Time recording better understood for billing and planning.
                    User Stories -
                        SRM POC for the NSME foundation - doable.
                            IR - HEADER_CURR_CHECK - migrating validations and determinations.
                                /SRMAP/CL_LREQ_IR_MODBO_PARTY
                                Action: ITEM Copy
                                /SRMAP/CL_LREQ_IR_IPROC_PRCT_E
                                /SRMAP/CL_FND_C_FILL_ITEM_ID
                                Incident solving or maintenance in NSME
                                    Date handling and changing dates
                                    Save not rejected for shopping carts w/o items
                            ML API for Auto approvals of IR - REST API asynchronous calls to deployed models, data formatting and manipulations.
                        SRM on NSME - all 3 tiers
                            SIV OIF - all the layers - front, middle, back tiers.
                                Done and remaining update regularly - hours recorded and task level tracing for updates.
                            PurchaseOrderFactsheet - all layers - added task tracing at bugs and fixing level -
                                cuz many at that time and micromanagement so would tell them where the error in framework is
                                or use workarounds like adding codes to framework or DB query running after run.
                                Creating pending user stories for transparency of bottlenecks.
                            Migrate Purchase order Factsheet
                        FIN UI And CIP mapping from BYD to NSME
                            SplitOpenItemsFactSheetEnhancedController - UI and CIP.
                            CheckDepositOWL - CIP
                            txecslfactsheet - UI - Europe Community Tax Returns based on sales list.
                            PaymentAllocationEditQAFEnhancedController_QAF_V2 - Allocate payment to SIV or CIV etc.
                            IncomingFileOWL_V2 - Files for Bank or partners interface - bank statements, cheque deposits, etc.
                            CostObjectsSettlementRunCreate_QAF - EC for background job creation.
				</NSME>
				<SAPIOT>
                SAP IOT - Big Data Analytics for SAP IOT Data Streams.
					Idols - Sathya (PO and Arch), Ashok (Computer Science terminology and clarity), Abhijeet (agressive achiever), Ajay (Architecture and programming), Imran (neat coding), Pavan (Services), Varsha (Scrum master).
					System Design
						Front End - Sensors Actuators (MQTT or REST microservices), Simulations for writing and reading (DataGen, Direct REST), Read-Only Configurable UI Facade.
						Application -
							Master Core Apps for registration
							Runtime AE Apps -
								2 types of apps:
									Springboot on CF apps waiting for REST or MQTT Calls; Job submission and Persistence management.
									Spark Apps in Scala
								3 use cases
									Abstract Thing Model Mapping Apps
									Derivation App
									Coldstore Apps - CSW (V2, V3), CS-Reader
							Misc Apps - Rule, Geo, Edge, Performance, Deployment Pipelines, JMeter, etc.
						Persistence - Kafka, Cassandra, HANA, Redis.
					Onboarding Facilitation - Created and Maintained Onboarding MS Teams channel containing details for new joiners.
						Environment set up
						Credentials and commands - organized commands and sources for all the tools and services that we use.
						Artifacts for new joiners - IDE, Compressed binaries, postman collections and env.
					High Level State Monitoring
						Contributions
							Support for newer endpoints (spark by context name)
							Extending slack integration for exceptions.
							Refactoring code using OO Principles and design patterns
						Tools - Updating GIT Wiki, Slack, REST APIs, HANA DB, Spring boot, JAVA, Adapter pattern,
                    Refactoring Code for Data Generation Simulator
						Contribution
							Refactoring and Code clean up.
							Redesign of existing code for compactness.
						Tools - JAVA, Spring boot, Kafka
                    Security Handling through Version Management
						Contributions
							Updating the dependency versions in order to take care of the identified vulnerabilities.
								Security team identifies version vulnerability with reasons - we appreciate and adapt to it.
							Dependency tree exclusion of transitive dependencies.
						viz - Version updates for security, master parent pom, library adoption etc
						Tools - MAVEN, GIT
					Performance Metrics POC for different Cloud foundry space
						Contributions
							Adapting config file to a CF space different from originally intended to avoid traffic.
							Communications with Performance team to fill the gaps.
							Idea proposal for automation of data collection for future analytics - Jmeter runs, REST endpoints to be given by the team, etc.
                    	viz - POC for Performance Execution on different CF Space
						Tools - Cloud Knowledge, Cloud Foundry, Wiki Page Creation
                    Spark Services Connections (and CF included) - Hana, Kafka, Cassandra, Redis.
						Contributions
							Supporting deployment checks and checks through REST endpoints for connection health of spark with other services.
							Extendable design to accommodate easy additions or removals in future.
						Tools - Cloud Foundry, Spark, Hana, Kafka, Redis, Cassandra. Multi-module Maven. JAVA, Mockito, JUnit, Scala, Factory / Builder Design Pattern
					Developer on Duty (DoD)
						Organizing and Structuring credentials and information for monitoring systems and handling wide demands
							ensure services running and available
						Solving issues in consultation with colleagues and customer
						Maintaining the spark jobs and cf apps running thru all thick and thins - like platform updates, app deployment.
					Cold Store writer (CSW JAVA and Scala or spark job) - JUnit, Mockito, Powermock, scalatest_2.11 (MockitoSugar)
						Testing (Unit and Functional)
						ensure code coverage.
						Integration Testing - not big bang but integration with few modules also checked but using mockito for all external dependencies.
					Thing Data Ingestion Analysis
						Local set up
						Analyse the working of current system
						Analysis on why jobs with small batch intervals were unstable.
							Try with different batch intervals - black box
							Proving that processing time exceeds the ingestion time by far.
					Testing - Commit / Stage Testing before / after stage promotion for tests b4 live.
						Also sandbox testing for every new development with sonar, jmeter, build, etc in jenkins.
						Nightly build scripts - red ones - re-trigger thru jenkins bot
						in workspace results csv file with every call - figure out where the problem is.
						Raise BCP for those problems or solve them whichever works.
				</SAPIOT>
			</SAP>
        </K>
        <EgoSpecific>
            about - focus on how I am suitable for a role cuz my ego matches with that.
                also include friends and what they did is also a sign of what you are.
                anything you do must be a line in resume!!
                How does my life give a perfect story or narrative or execution trace for a role in question.
                This is what finally makes it to word file - it's an effort at a certain frequency but other parts is sync.
            <Schema>
                Objective
                B and J
                    Educational Qualifications
                    Analytical Skills and Certifications
                        Highlighted Tools
                        Technologies
                    Case Studies and Projects
                D and K
                    Professional Relevant Projects
                    Personal Projects
                        College
                        OSS or Independent
                    Other Projects
                Details
                    Technical Skills
                    Domain Skills
                    Management Skills
                    Additional Qualifications
                    Personal Interests
            </Schema>
            <Research>
                //innovative ideas that saw the light can be quoted casually.
                    ideally, not just papers read but papers read on specific topic as knowledge part and for project part, papers read to solve a problem or write a paper.
                Objective
                    ???
                B and J
                    Educational Qualifications
                        M.Tech - 
                            RDBMS Criteria paper
                            ACT Project Paper reading and proposing ideas - what were they?
                            Semantic Web on NoSQL Ideas
                    Analytical Skills and Certfications
                        Highlighted Tools
                            All tools apply
                        Technologies
                            All technologies apply
                    Case Studies and Projects
                        ???
                D and K
                    Professional Relevant Projects
                        Siemens - Implementation of Paper on Minimize the storage in NoSQL using graph
                        SAP
                            ?multi-tenancy support for Software Defined Networks
                            ?Applications of physics in gaming
                    Personal Projects
                        College
                            ???
                        OSS or Independent
                            ???
                    Other Projects
                        ???
                Details
                    Technical Skills
                    Domain Skills
                    Management Skills
                    Additional Qualifications
                    Personal Interests
                Friends - 
                    ?Mayank Tiwari papers.
            </Research>
            <Systems> also includes frameworks development or utils development
                Objective
                    ???
                B and J
                    Educational Qualifications
                        B.Tech - Compiler Design - yacc and CUP Parser
                        M.Tech - OS, CN, TOC, Network Security(, Cryptography), Model Validation (nuSMV), ?Distributed Computing, IOT Seminar.
                            General - DSA, Data Modeling, OOAD, DP, etc.
                        online curious run on raspberry pi and arduino
                            !Cloud Design Patterns (eg - valet), etc.
                    Analytical Skills and Certifications
                        Highlighted Tools
                        Technologies
                            Socket Programming, System Calls - ability to make processes communicate, etc, thread management, semaphores locking
                    Case Studies and Projects
                        Implemented and added shell command for calendar
                        Socket Programming in JAVA - for sorting numbers (sounds like exercise and not project)
                        Updated kernel with a function of our own - Used VM for the same.
                        Cryptography algorithms and simulation
                D and K
                    Professional Relevant Projects
                        Siemens
                            a lot of linux command utilities for hadoop cluster maintenance; creating hadoop cluster
                            Shell script to auto-install presto and configure it fully on the system.
                            In Siemens, created a shell like program - which would take commands and run the commands we supported in java.
                            hadoop installation - thru VM directly, thru personal local set up, thru private cluster set up, thru AWS.
                            VMs networking, SSH, SCP, etc across VM, personal system.
                            Deployment of JAVA software on AWS for performance measurement on public cloud platform.
                            Threading in Siemens but used semaphores for critical section to ensure concurrency that doesn't overwrite existing records.
                            Siemens suggested a UML Design Document for IOT based Project for storage of the data.
                                Graph based trend algorithm following to minimize disk space consumed by IOT data produced by machines 
                                although it is DS but overall it's a framework also
                        SAP - Docker, Kubernetes, GIT, out of the box Tools for operations and testing
                            Training in Operations or deployment - Service Provider Cockpit (SPC), Regressions handling.
                            Used IaaS, PaaS out of the box to make our SaaS from SCP - changed to NodeJS to avail hyperscalers facility.
                                used SCP for Leonardo API for every system in ByD Product Space.
                            SAP Frameworks explored - ESF, BOPF, PDF, Oberon, Frontend JavaScript Framework, PI Framework - Message exchange across Deployment Units
                                frameworks used - let's call it application thing
                            SIOT - version updates of libraries cuz of security patches. MITM, Request Smuggling, Authentication, etc.
                    Personal Projects
                        College
                            ACT Project - created our own tiny language for web site abstracts - ability to parse it through yacc or CUP Parsers - ability to perform compilation.
                        OSS or Independent
                            Personal Practice - Operating System Programs, Networking Algorithms like Sliding Window Protocol, DNS, DHCP
                            ?Implementing the algorithms used by OS.
                    Other Projects
                        //should come under application perhaps but lots of thingy stuff here. Still call it extensions Programming - comes under Applications.
                            VLC match subtitles file
                            automatic desktop background changer
                            ?Google extension code - not done but to change the URL from silverlight to UI5.
                            convert transcript to text notes.
                Details
                    Technical Skills - vs on top - this is more casual and exhaustive and top one is only highlights for the specific JD role
                        Tools for Network Security.
                        ?Blockchain
                    Domain Skills
                    Management Skills
                    Additional Qualifications
                    Personal Interests
                Misc
                    //Interview call for every system company that visited - Arista, Cisco, etc.
                Casual
                    Shell Scripting (using git) - Find Lines, words or characters of Code implemented till now in SME. Also number of files.
            </Systems>
            <DevOps>
                Objective
                    ???
                B and J
                    Educational Qualifications
                        IIT Kharagpur Certification in C++ and JAVA.
                        M.Tech - OOAD, Design Pattern, Data Modeling, ?Distributed Computing
                        Online Lynda Courses - Javascript, Typescript,
                        LinkedIn - NodeJS, Express, GITHUB, Microservices Foundation (assignments remaining), 
                        JavaBrains - Spring, Lambda, TS, Maven, JS, Struts, 
                    Analytical Skills and Certifications
                        Highlighted Tools
                            DOTNET, C#, ?CPP, JAVA, SQL, NoSQL Databases like Neo4J, Cassandra, HBase; Struts, JQuery, Bootstrap; Jenkins, JMeter, ?Cloudfoundry / Kubernetes / Docker,
                            Ops Tools, Java Lambda, OAuth, Log4j2, etc.
                        Technologies
                            Algorithms, Approximation Algorithms, Data Structures, Design Patterns (Frontend (UI, Persuasive) and Backend(Java, JS)), OOAD/ UML, Data Modeling
                    ?Case Studies and Projects
                        Algorithms - 
                            Fibonacci series number generation; multiplication of 2 very large numbers - beyond the storage capacity of the data type.
                            ACT Project - Traversing all paths in Test automation of a system
                        Approximation Algorithms - ??
                        Data Structures - ??
                        Design Patterns - ?SME Solution Model
                        OOAD - EBay Prototype
                        Data Modeling - Semantic Web Modeling in Neo4J
                        Javascript - ?Analog Clock, ?Typing Speed Test App (can merge the two)
                        Typescript - ?ToDo List App
                        NodeJS 
                D and K
                    Professional Relevant Projects
                        Infy - Systems Engineer
                            Trainee
                                C, JAVA, SQL, LINUX, UXD.
                                DOTNET
                                Some Case Studies - Airline Booking System
                            Infy - SEZ Online
                                what - windows, IDE VS, asp dotnet, c#, ms sql
                                Traceability - SRS Requirements to Implementation mapping - Sequential Diagram for faster development, better maintenance thru easy debugging.
                            ATT Testing
                                what - LINUX, QTP, Citrix, Excel, Internal Tools.
                                LINUX scripts for data generation, QTP or selenium for data generation for stress testing
                                running UI scripts for scenario coverage
                            BT Support
                                what - PL/SQL, Internal Tools.
                                Message management
                                SQL scripts writing for application data consistency.
                        VIT Pune - Assitant Professor
                            Teaching Computer Programming - Structured and OOPS.
                                invented ideas - online google form based quiz, etc.
                            Guide for Projects - Tic Tac Toe, Console Based Marketing Software, 
                        IIITB - Student
                            EBay Prototype and REST Services
                                what
                                    Bootstrap, Jquery, JSP, AJAX, Windows, Eclipse, Apache Tomcat 9, Structs, Java, Mysql, MVC.
                                contribution
                                    Management - work assignment dynamics, etc.
                                        //ability to list all management lessons learnt from professor
                                    Schema Design, and UML Diagrams - Use Case, Sequence, DFD, etc on paper and StarUML.
                                    Purchase Scenario Coverage - division by application areas (and not technologies - cuz e1 wants to learn)
                            ACT Project - Abstract to Concrete Testing Framework
                                what - CUP Parser, JAVA, Selenium, Solvers (Linear Programming), Paper reading.
                                contribution - architectural ideas, Random data types generations, Web Design representation in invented format, Parsing the format to build a graph
                                    navigation thru the graph for finding all the paths, formulation of equations for all the paths, using solvers to come up with answers.
                                    build test cases using the answers, abstract to concrete conversion, running selenium scripts on the concrete test cases.
                            Semantic Web modeled in Neo4J
                                what - XML Parser, XML, Neo4J, MongoDB for evaluation, OWL for semantic web, Bootstrap, Apache Tomcat.
                                contribution - 
                                    Application of Rules of Reasoning to infer based on existing edges - eg - isFather and isBrother means isSon relationship, etc.
                                    Modeling of a college data model
                            StackOverflow Analytics - Deriving Insights from Stack Overflow data survey
                                Visualizations on tableau with different combinations of features.
                                Clustering of related technologies that tend to go together based on user’s interests.
                                Clustering of users that are very similar to each other in terms of the specified details.
                                Classification – Predicting salary bracket for any set of specified details fo
                        Siemens - Research Scientist - proves capability of making a framework
                            what
                                VM - VMWare, Hortonworks HDP2.0, CentOS, Windows SCP, Moba for SSH, etc.
                                Libraries - Properties File, Logger, Random Number generation Types.
                                UML online Softwares like Visual Paradigm
                                Hadoop Technologies - HIVE, Spark, Drill, Presto, Ambari REST API.
                                NoSQL (Cassandra, MongoDB, HBase)
                                JAVA, REST API, Bootstrap for display, JUnit for Testing, Threading for faster access
                                Factory Design Pattern, Singleton
                            contribution
                                Benchmarking Studio - Best execution engine for a given query
                                    TPCDS, customizing queries as per syntax (using regex)
                                Query Metrics Collector - Space Optimization Engine for NoSQL Engines
                                    Ideas - compressors, trend avoiding algorithm based on a paper, distributions that perform best.
                                    randomly generated data of different data types as per specific distribution.
                                    collection of running the application on AWS with specified data besides local cloud.
                                Design Formulation for IOT based Project
                        Associate Developer at SAP Labs
                            BYD
                                what and contributions
                                    Specification
                                        Exposure Large scale ERP applications, Suite in a box - end to end business processes support
                                    Design 
                                        Experience of NGAP Application Platform, Multiple Application Frameworks, Communications across Application Areas; SRM Application Area Development
                                        Trace framework thru debugging to tell which configuration is missing or where the data provided for next exit was insufficient or if framework needs a change
                                            very small changes like variable retaining old value so clear - very corner case like unit price rounding followed by total price rounding 
                                            loss of precision causes PO for approval to take place although shopping cart said otherwise - business scenario suffers.
                                            ?exposure to real world scenarios for design patterns - command pattern, factory, singleton, Strategy, Subscriber, etc.
                                    Implementation
                                        Tools
                                            Eclipse on ABAP, SAP GUI IDE for Web based IDE development
                                            HANA DB, MAX DB - Materialized Views for Analytics
                                        Features
                                            Fully Model Driven Software Development (configurations at different levels Developer, Key user, end user, etc)
                                            Analytics - Managing OLAP Systems - UI, Internal development tool, framework, MAX DB Materialized view secondary storage.
                                            Task Management - for end user attentions from messages failed across applications, etc.
                                            Output Management - pdf generation and sending by email. Using XML and Template (Adobe LiveCycle Designer) to Adobe Server.
                                            Workflow management - Approvals based on configured BO conditions, mapped to task management, Exception Handling in SIV, etc.
                                        UI
                                            ABAP, Fiori, UI5, Silverlight, Inbuilt version management, Transport Requests Management for DevOps.
                                            UI Development thru internal tool
                                            RUBY Scripts on internal tool, javascript, html;
                                        Integrations - Synchronous (A2X for tools like excel, etc) and Asynchronous (within or outside tenants)
                                            RMI or RFC as SAP calls it.
                                        ABAP to Typescript conversion - regex to create templates ready to use. (but didn't use it)
                                        User Stories (in short and incomplete - refer to byd for details)
                                            GDPR LXP, eInvoicing, Scanned Invoicing from text (support for intercompany), Scanned Invoicing from pdf, PO Reminder Letters (dunning), Manual PR, 
                                            Link PRs to PO, PO Schedule Lines, IFRS, OLAP Reports (GDPR Data protection related, and more)
                                            Scanned Invoice to SIV BO - from text, from pdf (REST API, using OAuth1), from pdf on email, from pdf on folder thru collaboration window
                                            Manual PR QAF ECO
                                            shopping cart mobile app
                                            GDPR implementation adoption - writing code for BO exits - filtering and bo name.
                                            delivery sch lines
                                            Link PR Items with PO - action
                                            Document Destroy GDPR implementation
                                            Background job filtering out for health checks
                                            PO root price components in Output Form           
                                            Kit items price calculation issue
                                            Invoice scanning review screen
                                            Master data PPS gaf.
                                            Create SIV From SIS - BO Updates Determinations, etc.
                                                    date User Fields from API fields in SIS BO - regex
                                                    PO reference so SIV created from SIS
                                                    Able to delete PDF files 1 or multiple.
                                            Update A2X Web Service - Read PO. A2A etc updates.
                                            Invoice scanning from text - Pattern Correction for Scanned Invoice from Text - problem of image having a pattern - that matches ditto fine tuned the regex.
                                            Email PDF to SIS BO Changes
                                                    SIS only permit PO that exist in system
                                            Data Source fields addition, updates.
                                            GDPR - BO Retention supplement
                                                    GDPR Person Deletion adoption.
                                            IFRS16 Lease Contract Payment Schedule Status Handle - Authorization handling included.
                                                    Lease Contract Run Remove Unauthorized Companies
                                            Excel integration - catch exceptions
                                            Cost Distribution for Goods Returned, All kinds of scenarios coverage. Additional cost distribution items
                                            Translation - OneChina Adoption also, otherwise b4 also.
                                            SIV Attachment Update (EC mappings)
                                            SIV Template supress errors
                                            BTM Task for ISI GSA request with bad PO Item ref - XML fails, inform user on UI with expected action.
                                            GSA expected read only flag as per business scenario state. IMAT, Finish resume PO properties. Shopping Card Retrieval COBL SO ref for Proj        
                                            SME - Create SIV From PO, Make Payment on SIV and message handling.
                                                    SIV OWL Filters - selections and filters on CIP.
                                            Lease contract not found error messages - many such.
                                            Intrastat added error message for clarity
                                            Avoid dump for convert key to node id on item node - lots of framework level changes or adoptions even in PD - like clear the buffer.
                                            Product Category w/o Product Assignment not possible;
                                            Z-prefix CDT Days Due and Fixed Date both active together - Enable parameters of days, month and fixed date for payment terms maintenance
                                            More - 
                                                management very well understood roll up, drill down.
                                                Consulting related discussions for end desirable product for end users, AUnits creation, JS Mocha Tests created and suggested.
                                                Design discussions like e-invoicing using word cloud
                                                Testing - BOUM2 and START scripts creation, run, correction - CRUD.
                                                Deployments - Hotfixes, patches, VP, EP.
                                                    Bug fixes and extensions in practically every BYD implementations, deployment assistance once using SPC (Service Provider Cockpit)
                                                Maintenance at all levels L1, L2, L3 - 
                                                    Consulting - helps thru call 1:1, 1:n, consulting; Customer concerns directly visible. VH and over weekend support.
                                                    corrections - UI workarounds, runtime corrections (debugger), back end DB corrections;
                                                    code corrections, customer influence or extensions or future commits.
                                    Testing
                                        Unit Testing (AUNIT), Internal Tools for Testing - Integration testing (BOUM2), System Testing (Start WebIDE, Stand alone), Regression Based Testing (RBT)
                                    Support
                                        Creation and maintenance of tools for maintenance and support - along with custom reports writing for backend correction, DB Corrections.
                                        Consultations to customers for adapting software to their business needs or suggesting work arounds
                                        ABAP Debugger, User change log and few days interaction log for code correction
                                    Misc - communications
                            NSME
                                what and contributions
                                    Specifications - Fresh scoping the application for different packages.
                                        Cross Functional works - Pricing, Master data, Foundation task creation, FIN coding block.
                                    Design - Fresh implementations so usage of many design patterns - singleton, strategy, template method, DAO, command, etc.
                                        ?saw working of an application server end to end.
                                        raising bugs, working on systems that are still stabilizing and not robust (eg colleagues on UI)
                                        Creating many stubs and skeletons.
                                    Implementations - GIT, VS Code, NPM, Node Express, REST API.
                                        Promises, callbacks, decorators, Postgres, HANA, etc. Debugging in TS, JS.
                                        Implemented Determination, validation, action, folder structure organization; used libraries like request.
                                        ML API integration for shopping cart approval - confidence as input for user and auto-approve as per user's choice. Configurable to write into a file.
                                            Mass Approval (set confidence in process map and play approvals in 1 go)
                                    Testing - Mocha Chai Unit Testing, Integration Testing, Sys and UAT by different teams in china.
                                        Unit Test also across lcp calls assuming all validations and determinations in place. Not class specific.
                                            UT cuz of less granular tests at attribute level
                                            integration test should focus on less granular stuff - PR is created, PO is in this status - scenario specific.
                                    Support - Logger Service for us to read the logs and tell what went wrong.
                                    Misc - start up feel, Manager roles understood better. Concept of Time recording better understood for billing and planning.
                                User Stories -
                                    SRM POC for the NSME foundation - doable.
                                        IR - HEADER_CURR_CHECK - migrating validations and determinations.
                                            /SRMAP/CL_LREQ_IR_MODBO_PARTY
                                            Action: ITEM Copy
                                            /SRMAP/CL_LREQ_IR_IPROC_PRCT_E
                                            /SRMAP/CL_FND_C_FILL_ITEM_ID
                                            Incident solving or maintenance in NSME
                                                Date handling and changing dates
                                                Save not rejected for shopping carts w/o items
                                        ML API for Auto approvals of IR - REST API asynchronous calls to deployed models, data formatting and manipulations.
                                    SRM on NSME - all 3 tiers
                                        SIV OIF - all the layers - front, middle, back tiers.
                                            Done and remaining update regularly - hours recorded and task level tracing for updates.
                                        PurchaseOrderFactsheet - all layers - added task tracing at bugs and fixing level -
                                            cuz many at that time and micromanagement so would tell them where the error in framework is
                                            or use workarounds like adding codes to framework or DB query running after run.
                                            Creating pending user stories for transparency of bottlenecks.
                                        Migrate Purchase order Factsheet
                                    FIN UI And CIP mapping from BYD to NSME
                                        SplitOpenItemsFactSheetEnhancedController - UI and CIP.
                                        CheckDepositOWL - CIP
                                        txecslfactsheet - UI - Europe Community Tax Returns based on sales list.
                                        PaymentAllocationEditQAFEnhancedController_QAF_V2 - Allocate payment to SIV or CIV etc.
                                        IncomingFileOWL_V2 - Files for Bank or partners interface - bank statements, cheque deposits, etc.
                                        CostObjectsSettlementRunCreate_QAF - EC for background job creation.
                    Personal Projects
                        College
                            SQL Administration
                            JAVA Media Player
                        OSS or Independent
                    Other Projects
                Details
                    Technical Skills
                    Domain Skills
                    Management Skills
                    Additional Qualifications
                    Personal Interests
            </DevOps>
            <DataScience>
                Interview
                    Techs    ----> Knowledge of architecture and Ability to demo thru a challenge
                    Projects ----> Ability to convince about your best architecture
                <Objective>
                    To pursue a challenging and growth-oriented career in a Progressive Organization 
                        and to engage/ enhance the level of my technical knowledge, domain expertise along with skills and ability to work in-group
                </Objective>
                <BAndJ>
                    <EducationalQualification>
                            2021
								LinkedIn Certifications for 2021
								Gaurav Sen - System Design (ongoing)
								Spark Seminars - Streaming by Tathagat Das.
								OpenCV - Programming Knowledge Tutorials, ?Robotics,
								LinkedIn - Deep Learning in OpenCV (Intro)
							2020
								Online Certification - Udemy - PySpark, Spark Streaming.
								Youtube - Learning Journal - Apache Kafka, Scala Programming (Revisits)
								JAVA Brains Courses - Spring Frameworks, JAVA 8, OAuth.
								Youtube - Redis (ProgrammingKnowledge)
								Online Course - Deep Learning (Take full responsibility of)
								Others LinkedIn - Hadoop, Microservices foundations.
								SAP - Careers over Coffee.
							2019
								Online Certification - Coursera - Machine Learning
								Courses
									Java Brains - Javascript, Typescript, JAXRS (Revisit)
									Learning Journal - Scala
									Lerna.
									Automation Step by step - Kubernetes (and other sources), Postman, JMeter, Jenkins.
									JumpstartCS - Cassandra.
									Youtube - Maven (LinkedIn also), JUnit Mockito.
								Misc
									TutorialDrive - Zookeeper.
									Spark Kafka Integration - Data Savvy.
									Spark Learning Journal.
									Arduino and Raspberry Pi - Last Moment Tutions.
									Android Glimpse.
									Udacity - Advanced OS.
									Crash Course - Statistics - Also Khan Academy Revisited.
									Codevolution - Chrome Extensions.
							2018
								Online Courses - 2018 (Take full responsibility of)
									Jigsaw Academy
										Specialization - Machine Learning in R
									Analytics Vidhya
										Specialization - NLP
								IBM Cloud Intro. Excel and VBA (ExcelVbalsFun)
								JAVA Brains - Soap.
								OpenSAP
									Writing Testable Code for ABAP
									SAP Business ByDesign Financials
									SAP Business ByDesign Supply Chain Management
									iO Startup School (SAP internal, Pilot)
									Excel Course.
									Introduction to SUSE Linux Enterprise Server (SLES, Repeat)
								Success map - RAW - Respect at work, Data Security, GDPR, etc.
							2017 - 2019
								BYD - ERP Courses (SCM, SRM, CRM, FIN, etc)
									NodeJS, Typescript, Express Router Frameworks.
									GIT, etc.
								Youtube and success map - ABAP Tutorials.
								Coursera or so - Approximation Algorithms (2 part course)
								OpenSAP
									Application Development for SAP Business ByDesign
							College Online Refreshers
								OOP - Derek, Web resources.
								CN - Gate Teacher Guy, Network Security from Saurabh.
								DSA - Naveen, IIT KGP, IIT Mumbai, Stanford, UNSW, Tushar Roy, random.
								Maths - IIT Madras, Khan academy.
								OS - NPTEL IIT KGP, random, etc.
								DBMS - NPTEL, Random.
								Data Modeling - Random.
								OOAD - Java Brains.
								TOC - Harry Potter, IIT Madras, IIT Kanpur.
								Data Analytics - Statquest, Luis Serrano, Random, SentDex, mathematicalmonk.
								Design Pattern - Derek Banas
								Model Verification (Prove correctness) - NPTEL MOOC.
								AI - IIT Madras.
								Distributed Computing - Durgasoft, MIT.
								Stats - XMIT.
								IDEs - Eclipse, VSCode, Intellij.
								ComputerPhile.
                            M. Tech - 2017 - IIIT Bangalore
                                Specialization - Data Science
                                Optional - Data Analytics, Data Modeling, Data Visualization, Distributed Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning
                                    Future - Network Science for Web, GIS, Deep Learning.
                            B. Tech - 2010 - NIT Jamshedpur
                                Specialization - Computer Science
                            H.S.C - 2006 - K V No 1, Udhampur
                                Specialization - PCMB
                            S.S.C - 2004 -  K V No 1, Udhampur
                            Specialization - NA
                            Future - AI, DC, DIP, etc.
                    </EducationalQualification>
                    <AnalyticalSkillsAndCertifications>
                        <HighlightedTools>
                            R programming
                            Python
                            Hadoop
                            Spark - PySpark Batch, Spark Streaming, ?SparkML, ?GraphX
                            Kafka
                            Hadoop Ecosystem Tools (HIVE, Drill, Presto, etc.)
                            Tableau
                            Advanced Excel (VBA)
                            Cloud Platforms like AWS, Private Cloud
                            SQL Tools (MS, MySQL, Oracle, etc.)
                            NoSQL Tools (Cassandra, HBase, Influx, etc.)
                        </HighlightedTools>
                        <Technologies> Techniques, algos, etc
                            Data extraction, cleaning, Data warehousing
                            Statistical Techniques, Data Visualization
                            Big Data Mining through Hadoop Tools
                            Hypothesis Testing
                            Regression Analysis (linear, logistic, etc.)
                            Classification (Random Forest, Ensemble Modeling) - Predictive Modelling
                            Clustering techniques (k-means, agglomerative, RFM analysis)
                            Association Rules
                            Neural Networks
                            Time series Forecasting
                            Strong Analytical and presentation skills
                            Optimization and simulation models
                        </Technologies>
                    </AnalyticalSkillsAndCertifications>
                    <CaseStudiesAndProjects>
                        <Techniques>
                            Statistics, Visualization
                                Visualizations based on Stack overflow data survey
                            Linear regression	
                                Predicting food truck profits from the city population
                                House Price Prediction of a locality from house size and number of bedrooms.
                            Polynomial Regression (regularization included)
                                Prediction of the amount of water flowing out of a dam using the change of water level in a reservoir.
                            Logistic regression
                                Predict Student’s admission into University based on marks in 2 exams
                            Support Vector Machines (SVM)
                                Spam Classifier – predict if a given email is spam based on the training over a dataset.
                            Neural Network
                                Digits recognition from handwritten image
                            Clustering
                                Image Compression using K-means clustering on RGB pixels.
                            PCA (Principle Component Analysis)
                                Dimensionality Reduction of an image of 1024 pixels to 56 without significant loss of data and speed up learning.
                            Anomaly Detection
                                Detecting anomalous behavior of computing servers in terms of latency and throughput.
                            Recommender System
                                Suggest a movie based on different ratings given to movies by various users
                            Time series
                        </Techniques>
                    </CaseStudiesAndProjects>
                </BAndJ>
                <DAndK>
                    <ProfessionalRelevantProjects>
                        <Siemens2016>
                            Research Scientist (internship):
                                R&D, Siemens, 
                                Electronic City, Bangalore.
                                Total Experience: 7 Months (Dec 2016-June 2017)
                            <ProblemsAndSolutions>
                                Runtime Selection of Best Hadoop Execution Engines for a query on Big Data
                                    Skills - HDFS, HIVE, Drill, Presto, Spark, JAVA, JAVA Regex, JUnit, REST API, Bootstrap UI
                                    Solution
                                        Runtime Selection of Best Hadoop Execution Engines for a query on Big Data
                                        HDFS, HIVE, Drill, Presto, Spark, JAVA, JAVA Regex, JUnit, REST API, Bootstrap UI
                                        Knowledge of Design Patterns, Logger, Property File employed to create the framework.
                                        Used TPCDS data store to test the execution metrics for queries run on candidate Hadoop ecosystem tools.
                                        REST API used to fetch results from AMBARI after every query run.
                                        Handled multiple formats like text, JSON/ XML, CSV
                                        Regression didn't seem to be the best technique to be employed and hence classification was proposed for the same.
                                Selecting best NoSQL Database for storing stream data from sensors and algorithms to minimize the disk storage for the same	
                                    Skills - Cassandra, HBase, Influx, JAVA
                                    Solution 
                                        Adding another NoSQL tool influx to the existing framework.
                                        Generation of random data types (numbers, strings, etc) following a certain distribution to simulate the sensor behaviors.
                                        Collection of metrics and visualization in excel
                                        Creating types of queries in java which are not supported by the tool out of the box. Eg – Hbase total records.
                                        Implementation of slope algorithm to minimize the data objects instances stored by HBase.
                                Design Proposal for handling IOT Data Stream
                                    Skills - Diagrams- starUML, LucidChart Online	
                                    Solution
                                        Proposed a Design for the upcoming application.
                                Uncat - Kafka 
                            </ProblemsAndSolutions>
                        </Siemens2016>
                        <SAP2017>
                            Associate Developer
                                Business ByDesign (ERP Business Suite), SAP Labs
                                Whitefield, Bangalore.
                                Total Experience: 2 years 1 month (July 2017-Till Now)
                            Requirements and Responsibilities
                                Real Time Analytics (OLAP) for Business Users
                                    Skills - Knowledge of Data warehousing, Understanding of existing data model
                                    Major Responsibilities
                                        Creating materialized views for storage of transactional data to HANA data base on the fly.
                                        Modeling the mapping of dimensional features and fact variables from user view to the materialized views.
                                        Handling the change in user requirements through customized reports and design time modeling changes.
                                Conversion from Supplier Invoice PDF from multiple sources to a Business Document
                                    Skills - Excel, VBA, Data Cleaning, JSON to CSV conversion, Validation metrics against ground truths, REST API, ABAP Regular Expressions		Availing the exposed REST based Machine Learning Service for reading pdf in different used formats.
                                    Major Responsibilities
                                        Availing the exposed REST based Machine Learning Service for reading pdf in different used formats.
                                        Giving feedback on the results in validation metrics through comparing grounds truths with obtained results though excel, visual basic, data cleaning.
                                        Handling pdf from multiple sources like folder though internal tool, email, or UI.
                                        Handling the obtained results through proper transformation of data types and formats so that the returned data is compatible with DB storage.
                                Domain expertise in Supplier Relationship Management
                                    Skills - Requests Creation (Shopping Cart), Contracts, Request for Quotations, Quotes, Purchasing, Goods and Services delivery, Supplier Invoicing and Credit Memo for Payments
                                    Major Responsibilities
                                        Handling business transactions for internal requirements, supply chain management, and supplier contracts.
                                        Handling exceptional scenarios from customers through work arounds, corrections or suggestions.
                                        Creating traceability of the transactions for a business scenario through document flow and cost accounting.
                                Routine User Experience of Cloud Reporting
                                    Skills - Knowledge of the data model
                                    Major Responsibilities
                                        Identification of existing problems across the customers.
                                        Rolling and Drilling down for problem identification.
                                        Grouping customers with similar issues or problems
                                ToDo - Write NSME Experience within this. Start Adding Data Engineering work here.
                        </SAP2017>
                    </ProfessionalRelevantProjects>
                    <PersonalProjects>
                        <CollegeProjects> Only Relevant Ones
                            Deriving Insights from Stack Overflow data survey
                                Visualizations on tableau with different combinations of features.
                                Clustering of related technologies that tend to go together based on user’s interests.
                                Clustering of users that are very similar to each other in terms of the specified details.
                                Classification – Predicting salary bracket for any set of specified details for a new user.
                                Association Rules – suggesting best country for a given technology toolset.
                            Semantic Web on NoSQL
                                Skills - OWL, MongoDB, Neo4J
                        </CollegeProjects>
                        <IndependentAndOSS>
                            Given a set of Purchase orders suggest and a given item, suggest user with a new item.
                                Proposed usage of association rules with support and confidence evaluation for the same.
                                No ABAP library is available for association rule mining and so implementation of algorithm suggested.
                            Given items with free text description suggest a category - Supervised Learning on the text. 
                                Project Detail - 
                                Role in Project - 
                            Club free text items together based on descriptions to suggest customer to make a product id.
                            CDT at risk.
                            POC Suggested - e-invoicing - multiple xms - 1 xml which one does it belong to. Learn thru tag wordcloud clustering. 
                                Rather than running the xml for each xms one by one as long as match ain't found.
                            given a ticket description, suggest the best user to be able to handle the ticket.
                            Smarter XSearch for tickets - instead of doing free text search - given a ticket, tell what it most resembles with.
                        </IndependentAndOSS>
                    </PersonalProjects>
                    <OtherProjects>
                        <Infosys2010>
                            Systems Engineer
                                SEZ Online, Infosys
                                Hinjewadi, Pune.
                                Total Experience: 2 years 7 months (July 2010-Feb 2013)
                            Contributions
                                Traceability Matrix from Customer Requirements to Implementation
                                Application Testing - Regression Based Testing, System Testing, Test Case Generation.
                                Maintenance – Customer Issues Handling, Process Integration Message Handling.
                        </Infosys2010>
                        <VIT2013>
                            Assistant Professor
                                Vishwakarma Institute of Technology
                                Bibwewadi, Pune.
                                Total Experience: 7 months (June 2013- Dec 2013)
                            Contributions
                                Computer Programming Concepts
                                Guide for Programming Projects
                        </VIT2013>
                    </OtherProjects>
                </DAndK>
                <Details>
                    <TechnicalSkills>
                        <Knowledge>
                            Relevant Courses – Machine Learning (By Andrew NG), Data Analytics, Data Modeling, Design Patterns [, Distributed Computing, Artificial Intelligence]
                            Ongoing Self Study Courses – NLP in Python (Analytics Vidhya), ML in R (Jigsaw Academy)
                        </Knowledge>
                        <HLDRelevant>
                            Data Modeling Representations - SQL, Excel, XML, JSON, CSV, Semantic Web, Object Oriented Databases, NoSQL, Temporal DB, Stream DB, Relational Data warehouse (Star Schema)
                            Frameworks worked on – Hadoop Ecosystem, Many Proprietary Frameworks.
                            Optional - Ability to Scale - Knowledge of Design Patterns, Exits/ Frameworks, Property/ Configuration Files, etc.
                        </HLDRelevant>
                        <LLDRelevant>
                            Libraries worked on - Spacy, Pandas, NLTK, stemmer, etc.
                            Algorithms – Induction based, Divide and Conquer, Greedy, Brute Force, Branch and Bound, Backtracking, Dynamic Programming, Artificial Intelligence, Approximation Algorithms, etc.
                            Optional Advanced Algorithms - Approximation Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence
                            ML Algorithms - classification, clustering, association rules, regression
                        </LLDRelevant>
                        <Environment>
                            Clouds Used - Private Cloud, AWS (EC2, EMR, S3).
                            IDE – RStudio, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook, Spyder, Eclipse for JAVA.
                        </Environment>
                        <ImplementationsAndTechnologies>
                            Hadoop Technologies - HIVE, Spark, Drill, Presto, Ambari REST API.
                            DS specific Languages - R, Python, Octave, Matlab, JAVA for big data.
                            Data Analytics Technologies – Excel, VBA, SQL.
                            Optional Tools - SQL, Excel.
                        </ImplementationsAndTechnologies>
                        <Experiences> Optional
                            Datasets worked on (for experimentations or specific exercises)
                        </Experiences>
                    </TechnicalSkills>
                    <DomainProficiency> like Requirements or Functional Specification but kept separate cuz important but after technical skills
                        ERP Application Areas Familiar With – SRM, SCM, CRM, FIN, HCM.
                        SRM Involvements – Shopping Cart, Contracts, Request for Quotations, Quotes, Purchase Orders, Goods and Services Receipt, Goods Return, Supplier Invoicing, Credit Memo.
                    </DomainProficiency>
                    <ManagementSkills> like Problem Solving before Functional Specifications but important separately but less prior than Technical and Domain.
                        Undergone training on Scrum based software development with day today observations of scrum practices.
                        Good Communication skills with sound experience at interactions with different stakeholders. 
                        Ready to shoulders responsibilities, resourceful with a pro-active approach in accomplishing targets.
						Lots of Lynda / LinkedIn Courses to be more effective.
                    </ManagementSkills>
                    <AdditionalQualifications>
                        ???
                    </AdditionalQualifications>
                    <PersonalInterests>
                        YouTube Technical Channels, Reading, Sports, trekking, Cooking
                    </PersonalInterests>
                </Details>
            </DataScience>
        </EgoSpecific>
        <Stories>
            Sume 
                    UI Handling - usage level not framework level
                            UI Discussion with other teams, where some configuration element has to take over. some values are already not coming to inport of OVS.
            Sume JS World
                    react.js - library to create ui components - create html page on client side.
                    angular.js - framework for creating (?single page) web application - MVC (Model and view congruence) -> create routes for views and corresponding controllers - change in controllers refects changes in views and vv.
                    Servlets - is backend creation of html page thru code.
                    JSP - is a backend creation of html page not front end. This also converts to code but looks like html so easier to work with.
                    express.js - server side framework (not library as per lynda) to better manage request and response thru routes, middlewares.
                    vue.js - framework to build fullstack application
                    bootstrap.js - frontend dynamic ready-made ui components to consume (for beautification) - css and js libraries.
                    D3.js - visualizations ?Library
                    tensorflow.js - library for ML.
                    ajax - ?library for contacting server.
                    gulp to start code in default browser.
            Sume - Data visualizations D3, DC, Tableau, Excel.
            Sume DS Scope
                    Analytics, ML Course, R, Python, Excel, SQL, D3/DC, Puzzles, Hadoop. Descriptive Stats (Excel)
                    Curiosity - DL, AI, Maths parts etc.
            Sume - background jobs creation and run.
                    https://stackoverflow.com/questions/7814089/how-to-schedule-a-periodic-task-in-java
                    ScheduledExecutorService, Quartz, TimeTask, AbstractScheduledService.
            Sume
                    OpenCV Intro, 
            Sume - Project Management Views.
                    the view in project OIF is aggregated view of all time recordings.
            Sume - I have worked on following topics in past 4 months.
                    1.	SME Express – Invoicing from PO screen (UI and backend).
                    2.	SME Express – Payment from Invoicing screen (UI and backend).
                    3.	SME Express – bug fixes across process components.
                    4.	S4One – Shopping Cart Action Implementation – submit for approval with confidence determined by ML API, copy items, etc.
                    5.	S4One – Shopping Cart Validations Implementation – currency check, etc.
                    6.	S4One – Shopping Cart Determinations Implementation – Item ID determinations, Item Product determinations, etc.
                    7.	S4One – Test Cases creation and maintenance, etc.
            Sume
                    Tell more than asked - you drive what they will ask - you should drive the interview.
                    I have worked on that. I know this and also that.
                    Insult immune - karni hai karle ek hi baar to milenge if that's the case.
                    Farzi - for practice. Guaranteed you will leave cuz more money. Why not face economics - the fact.
                    Prep <==> Face I/v. the latter is more dependable than former. Any wrong will be one time and won't repeat itself so face it.
            Sume
                    Siemens project - Not a good idea to apply regression on queries but classification of which execution engine is best thru decision tree will be a good idea - this knowledge can be helpful at rule based dispatch to apt execution engine and not apply prediction to find numbers or find execution engine.
            Sume 
                    LinkedIn useful for others - e1 has their accounts so so many results for a request. Primarily for CEO, etc levels.
                    Naukri - means you really need job right now.
            Sume - Tableau
            Sume
                    git website
                    linkedin link
            Sume
                    SAP Role Descriptions (truly - outside of DS role)
                            ERP Product Development for the Application Area of Supplier Relationship Management
                            Support Real Time Analytics (OLAP) for Business Users
                            Maintenance - Debugging and support in resolving customers issues. Using cloud reporting OLAP system to roll up for finding generic issues.
                            Testing - ensure robustness and "no regression" all business scenario - TDD.
                            Support Integration (SOAP, REST, RFC based) across application areas, applications and businesses.
            Sume - JDA Mahatmya
                    JDA Software provides the leading AI-driven supply chain management (SCM) platform.
                    Our end-to-end solutions span supply chain and retail planning, execution, delivery and workforce management.
                    Our mission is to empower companies to better predict, make and deliver exactly what their customers want – when, where and how they want it.
                    We power free-flowing, connected global commerce - without wasted materials, energy, costs or time – to accelerate economic growth, sustainability and prosperity.
                    JDA’s delivers a more Autonomous Supply ChainTM for 4,000 of the world’s leading companies 
                            including 75 of the top 100 retailers, 77 of the top 100 consumer goods companies and 8 of the top 10 global 3PLs.
                    Running JDA, you can plan to deliver.
        </Stories>
    </V>
    <A>
        About - Ashram is about being best Social Consumer.
        <B>
            SocialErp - Services Customer (social interfacing)
                Adventure Management - Plan in terms of resources
                Epic - ?; Backlog - Kerala, ITR.
            HomeErp - Products Customer (base camp grat streaming)
                Epic - ?; Backlog - Chair.
            PersonalErp - Amusements (Me time) 
                Hobbies, Skills, Sports (1 challenges, 2 games, n races).
                Epic - ?; Backlog - Car, Chess.
        </B>
        <J> Talk Capabilities you can take resp for (not just what all I have read)
            Science - physics, chem, bio; maths (Intermediate)
            Sociology - history, politics, Psychology, economics, civics, geography; (Secondary School)
            Home - MBA - Stage Presentation, Group Involvement (SAP Labs BYD, LinkedIn courses)
            Personal - skills and psychology - Singing, Joking, Games, Philosophy (Charisma On Command, Self Help Books)
			Trace
				2021 - Crash Course Psychology
					Khan Academy Microeconomics. Bharatvarsh TV Series.
					?Pradhanmantri 2, Monica Gupta.
					Lots of audiobooks.
				2020 - Study IQ, ThePrint. Bike. Dhruv Rathee, Praveen Mohan. Sid Talk.
					Lots of Audio
				2019 - Philosophy Crash course.
				2017 - Charisma On Command, Seeken.
				2015 - Pradhanmantri 1.
			For F - ASMR, Exercises, Yoga, Affirmations, motivations, etc.
        </J>
        <D> Challenges and stories and Grats during projects for instances
            	Instances - Goa Trip Bike petrol finish story; Heavy rain in Kharagpur story; Left home in yol story;
			Idols and Friends
			Amritsar - Idols - Family, Teacher ward, Rashpal Madam, TV.
			Udhampur - Idols - Johny Sir, Vikram Sir, Manish Sir, Pandey Family, MN Singh Sir, Uttam Sir, Asgar Alam Sir, Anish, Hemant Senior.
			Jamshedpur Hostel Phase 1 - Idols - Roommates, Savyasachi, Dancer guy, Goyal, Litti guy.
			Jagannath Puri VOICE (KGP) - Anand Babu Pr, Scar on cheek Pr, Bharat Pr, Sr Devs, PSP, KTP, RPP, KGP devs.
			Jamshedpur Hostel Phase 2 - Pradeep Panigrahi, Priyaranjan, Mess incharge a friend.
			Mysore - Vikas.
			Pune
				Atmanivedan YOGA - VOICE devs, Indresh Pr, Amarjeet Pr, Deepak Pr, KGP's dev, Preaching Devs. Infy devs. Vibhor Pr, Ravi Pr.
					Arch Pr, Same building waale Pr, Ramvilas Pr, Nilesh Pr.
					BGP, RPP, RK Pr, etc for Wednesday BG talk.
				Atmanivedan Sudarshan VOICE - OC Pr, Desktop waale Pr, Amit Pr, IIM waale Pr.
				ISKCON Pune - KTP, Sanskrit Scholar Dev, etc.
				Atmanivedan Lotus VOICE - Saurabh Mehta Pr, Vraj dev, Canada jaane walle Pr, Ravi Pr.
				Vraj Dham VOICE - OC, PM Pr, Prof Pr at VIT (Maths waale long height waale) and at VOICE also.
			Bangalore
				IIITB Hostel - Anjani, Shishir, Anish, JnK waale, Electronics Anime walle.
				SLS Square - Anshul, Apoorv, Akash, Siddharth, Tejinder Sir.
			Amritsar - Idols - Mama, Papa, Surabhi didi and Jiju, Syami.
				Relatives - 1st level extended family, 2nd level - Other jijus, etc. Vicky Bhaiya, etc.
        </D>
        <K>
            <Social> Standardizations
                TODO - News standardization.
                ITR, Donations.
            </Social>
            <Products>
                FIN - Balance sheet todo.
                    <Money>
                        TODO - finish the list. Plan to increase my worth.
                        Savings Accounts
                        FDs
                        SIP
                        Others - PF
                        Cards - debit card renewed, ICICI Credit Card, HDFC Debit Card.
                        Expenditures this month
                            Food - 2K.
                            Fuel - 1K.
                    </Money>
                ESCM
                    CRM - Guests and Hosts (Networking DMPM Themes - Plans and Stories shared)
                        <Network> People (Visitors, Lead, Prospects and Customers) standardizations and Services
                            TODO - Standardize a plan to stay in touch with all of them. How to grow the network.
                            Standardize all people (especially yourself) are associated with - in terms of body / health, Senses (likes and favorites), mind (stories and experiences), intel (career; do you know driving, etc - stuffs to be leveraged later sometime), ego (nature).
                            Relatives
                            Nanaji - Postman. Naniji - Home Maker. Dadaji - Chemicals Industry. Dadiji - Home Maker.
                            Mama - Yoga Teacher KV. MA in Languages, etc.
                            Kamal Mausi - Yoga Teacher KV.
                            Mausaji - Army Major then broker business for supplying maids, cooks, etc.
                            Ruhi - Yoga Teacher personal.
                            Sammy Bhaiya - MTV b4.
                            Charu Mausi - Yoga Teacher KV.
                            Mausaji - Engineer. Textile - very vast contacts and spiritual interests. Explores lots of places.
                            Anku
                            Shivam
                            Upinder Mamaji - Yoga Teacher KV. Very funny and endearing.
                            Mamiji - Principal in HP state govt school. Bio Teacher before.
                            Rajan
                            ...
                            Pushkar Mamaji - Vice Principal - Hindi teacher before. Funny and evaluative.
                            Goldie Mamaji - High Court Superintendent in Chandigarh. MA in English.
                            Vandana Mamiji - Home Maker. Very good nature.
                            ...
                            Papa - Ph.D in biophysics. Jammu Medical College research. Chemicals business.
                            Baldev Papaji - Textile before. Then Ravi Bhaiya - Aquaguards?, etc.
                            Ravi Bhaiya, Shakti Bhabhi
                            Aruna didi, ?poonam didi
                            Jugal Kishore Papaji - Pharmacy Chemicals Industry.
                            Kamlesh Rani Chaiji - Home Maker.
                            Sonia didi (?), Mona didi (NIT Jal), Rashmi didi (Medical, ), Rajni didi (Car Sales b4, Works at HDFC Bank)
                            Vikas Vashisht Jiju (?), Vijay Jiju (Works at PHF Leasing Ltd), Riju Jiju (Sales Officer at PATEL AIRFREIGHT, self employed now), Karan Manan (Sales Manager at HDFC Bank Ltd)
                            Mehak, Muskaan, K, Zeeshan, Leeshan,
                            Tilak Chachaji - Colonel in Army.
                            Chachiji - PGT Biology Teacher in KV.
                            Ronny Bhaiya
                            Rini
                            Kunti Buaji
                            Fufaji
                            Rajan Bhaiya
                            Poonam didi
                            Nagpur waale Buaji
                            Fufaji
                            ...
                            ...
                            Surabhi Didi
                            Jiju
                            Rishi, Uncle, Aunty, etc.
                            Adhrit
                            Samant
                            His friends that I know
                            Misc - Vinarani Aunty (Vanita, Vikas Bhaiya, Gorkha Bhaiya)
                            Friends - Devs, School friends, college friends, professor friends, etc.
                            ToDo - Networking everyday and new person a week even thru whatsapp.
                        </Network>
                        uncat
                            ASR Visit.
                            Didi Jiju.
                            Jalandhar Trip.
                            Marriage Leads.
                    SCM Production - Kitchen Cooked Dishes (Foodie life DMPM Themes)
                        Snacks - Dhokla, etc.
                        Made by me - ...
                        <Foods>
                            TODO - List of all cooking recipes tried, foods I am gonna try.
                            Breakfast Light
                            Idli, Vada Sambhar
                            Dosa 99 variety, Set Dosa (Uttapam), Pesarattu, Pan Dosa with veg stew, Paneer, Corn Dosa, Matar Dosa, etc
                            Parothas - Variants - Alu, Gobhi, Mooli, Methi, Palak, Pyaaz, Cheeni walla.
                            Particles (Khara Bath (Upma), Seviya, Poha, Daliya),
                            Veg
                            Ghiya - Ghiya vadi, Daal Ghiya.
                            Bhindi - bharva bhindi, bhindi onion.
                            Bengan - bharta, alu baingan, cutlet, bharvan baingan
                            Shalgam
                            Palak,
                            Chilli Potato
                            Mix Veg, Sukhe Chane, Alu Sabji, Tondli, Patta Gobhi,
                            Veg Gravy
                            Shimla Mirch Alu, Manchurian,
                            Pulses
                            Kabuli Choole, Moong Dal, Rajmah, Kaali Chane, Masar Daal, Chane ki daal, Paalak Soppu,
                            Fruits and Juices
                            Sapota, Banana, Orange, Mango, Apples, Grapes, Pomegranates, Guava,
                            Group Fruits - Water Melon, Papaya, Kharbuja, Seetaphal,
                            Breads
                            Chapatti - Tava Roti, Fulka, Tandoori Roti, Parotha, Rumali, Missi, Naan, Kulcha (Garlic, Butter, normal); Kerela Akki Roti, Dosa
                            Rice - Lemon Rice, Coconut Rice, Masala Rice (Poliogare Rice), Biryani (spicy rice with veg), Pulao (sada rice with veg), Khicadi (Bisibele Bath)
                            Snacks / Fried/ Atram Patram / Meeting delights - Samosa, Pakoda (Bread, Paneer, Gobi, Mirchi, etc), Burger, Momos,
                            Rolls - Caliphornia Burrito, Kathi Roll (home rolls)
                            Sandwich - Paneer, Bhurji, Veg, Palak, multi-layered veg sandwich, etc
                            Pizza - Pizza on Papad,
                            Lasagne, Spaghetti
                            French Fries
                            Chinese - Chowmein, Manchurian, Spring Roll
                            Maharashtra - Paav Bhaji, Misal Paav, Vada Paav, Dhabeli,
                            Sweets - Gulab Jamun, Rasagulla, Barfi (Dodda, Milk cake, Normal, Kaju), Choori Kutti, Laddus (Motichoor, Besan, etc), Halva, Kheer
                            Icecream, Rasamali, Rabdi, Seviya (with or w/o milk), Custard
                        </Foods>
                    SCM Logistics - Home DMPM Themes - Home Decor. Cleaning every month. Renew every week.
                        <HomeDecor>
                            TODO - Car charger, Phone adapter, cooking cloth.
                            Bangalore SLS Square
                                Bedroom
                                    Sleep
                                        1 bed, 2 mattress, 4 chadars, Mosquito coil, 2 pillows with cover
                                    Wardrobe
                                        Clothes
                                            UG - n Baniyan, n UW, n socks.
                                            Tops - Formal shirts, Informal shirts, Tshirts.
                                            Bottoms - Pants, trousers, jeans, pyjama, shorts.
                                            Sweaters, jackets.
                                        Docs
                                        Altar - deities, agar battis.
                                        Morning chores and Meds - 2 brush, 1 paste, etc.
                                        Books -
                                Store -
                                    Suitcases - 1 attache, 2 bags, etc.
                                    backup section.
                                Electronics -
                                    1 laptop - 2 usb ports, 2 display ports, type c port, audio jack, ethernet port. Finger scanner, touchscreen. Smart touchpad (12 touch points)
                                        sim card. Camera. Speaker.
                                    Accessories - 1 mouse, 1 headset, 1 hotspot.
                                    Smartphone - dual sim slot either sides, both side camera, volume control, dnd call control, finger scan. Speaker. USB Type C port.
                                Common Area
                                    Fridge, Washing machine, Water purifier.
                                Kitchen
                                    Gas, Cylinder
                                    Cooking Utensils - Drawers.
                                    Food backup - cupboards.
                                    Eating Utensils - Drawers.
                                Garage - 1 Bike, 1 Car.
                                Scrum - Affirmations (Paper posts, Scrum board, Smileys, Smiley ball, SAP medals)
                            Amritsar
                                ...
                        </HomeDecor>
                    SRM - Shopping Experiences.
                        <ShoppingExploring>
                            About
                                XRoutine To Stock, Assets Stocks,
                                What was bought from where. Logs of experiences.
                            TODO - Standardize Bangalore areas, Standardize shops in whitefield.
                            Punjab - Amritsar, etc.
								Golden Temple, Durgiana Temple, Valmiki Ashram, Gobindgarh fort, Wagha Border, War memorial, 12 Gates.
								Sadda Pind - Horse ride, Mela rides, Maut ka kuan, Massage, Dangerous acts, Putli show, light adventure sports. Meals and old artifacts.
                            JnK - Udhampur, Jammu, Katra, Gulmarg.
								Horse ride, rope zipline, Army travel, Army mess, Rope binding, Hill climbing literally.
                            Jharkhand - Tata Nagar, 3 Book distributers birthplace, etc.
							Orissa - Jagannath Puri.
								Haridas Thakur Samadhi (Sea declared pilgrimage place by LCM) and Dhyan place (Siddha Bakul).
							Bengal - Mayapur - ISKCON, BVT Sthali, BSS, Jagannath, LCM Birthplace, Replica of Vrindavan
								Ekacakra or place where Nitai gave mercy to Raghunath G, Cooking place of LCM associate,
                            Maharashtra - Mumbai, Pune - Shanivar Peeth.
								Lonavala views, Shivaji palace and forts, Mumbai stay at Banganga (Walkeshwar temple in south - malabar hill), Local train travel, BACE stay during exams.
								Ganesh Temple in Pune and Mumbai - Siddhivinayak temple.
								Dehu, Pandharpur, Alandi - many visits and govt exam visits. Jatayu's moksha place Taket, Nashik.
							MP - Ujjain, Indore.
							UP - Vrindavan
								Raval, Barsana, Banke Bihari, Sriji temple, Prem Mandir outside, Sri Krishna Balaram Mandir ISKCON,
								Nanda Gaon, Krishna's birthplace, Govardhan view from distance, 6 G Deities, Yamuna.
                            Karnataka - Mysore, Bangalore (nandi hills, wonderla, gardens, bannerghatta), Coorg, Goa, Mahabalipuram.
								Water fall, Sunrise point, Driving city tour on bike, Stone architecture, Beach for all (east west), Sand Art, Vrindavan Garden.
								Bangalore Massage, etc.
								Hampi, Udupi
							Kerala - Cochin oldest church in India, beach walk, Alleppe boat ride.
							Rajasthan - Udaipur City Palace and Lake City, Kumbhalgarh Fort, Nathdvara Srinathji, Haldi Ghati warland.
								Palace Guide. Pujari Guide. Museum exploration. Camel Ride. Rajasthan instruments and dance.
                        </ShoppingExploring>
                HCM - Happy Family Members (life events, entertainments, etc)
                    TODO - Star wars franchise, IMDB next best.
                    Life Events - new year, birthday, anniversary, party, etc.
                    Eating - Ghoomar at Amritsar, Haveli experiences, Brothers dhaba.
                        Ice creams, etc.
                    Gediyan - going to malls, visiting places.
                    <TV>
                        Books -
                        Music - songs.
                            Singers, time, feeling (love, motivation, etc)
                            Pop, Evergreen, personal favorites, Nostalgia, Remix.
                        Movies
                            Comedy -
                            Scary -
                            knowledge -
                            documentary -
                            Spirituality or History - Mahabharat, Ramayan, Chanakya, Chandragupt Maurya, Pradhanmantri.
                        Sports - Challenges, Games.
                    </TV>
            </Products>
        </K>
        <EgoSpecific>
            About and Future Plans
                //Jolly and Scientist - ego cultivation desires indpendent of spiritual pursuits
                ego in EQ is mixture of a lot of things - it is width exploration and not depth - ego targetted can be seen as overall culture of mind - the feel that it elicits.
                think of including discussions also (kinda discussions participated in) eg WW, Modi Govt Performance, etc.
            Objective
            B and J
                Educational Qualifications
                    Communication
                        School - Vocab, Grammar, Poetry in Hindi
                        SSC, HSC - Personal and Interpersonal skills, Grammar, Contextualizing etc
                        NITJ - Phonetics, Vocab
                        Infy - Speak Up, Telephone Conversation, Interpersonal skills, Stephen Covey's 7 principles, etc.
                        SAP - 
                            Take a More Creative Approach to Problem-Solving
                            Bystander Training: From Bystander to Upstander
                            How to Manage Your Manager
                            Improving Your Thinking
                            The Mindful Workday
                            Time Management: Working from Home
							Career Canvas - Manager, Secrets HRs don't tell; overseas; relationships, networking, etc.
                    Social and Science - SSC and HSC respectively.
                        Online Content - dedicated channel - Interviews, comedy, songs, poetry, etc
                Skills
                    Communications - 
                        Languages - English, Hindi, Sanskrit (Vocab + Grammar), Body Language (NITJ), Voice Tone (matters 2nd to BL)
                            Figures of speech, idioms, proverbs, adage, etc.
                        Arts -
                            Personal abilities - Notes making, summary making, fast reading, grammar correction (School), phonetics (NITJ)
                            Abilities wrt people - Ads/ Pamphlet or brochure writing, essay/ report writing (School)
                            Unicast - CV / Interview (NITJ), Telephone conversation (Infy), email etiquettes (IIITB), Speak Up (Infy)
                            Multicast - Stage or public Presentation (ISKCON)
                    Social Studies - Civics (wrt Natural Conditions), Economics, History.
                    Science - Physics (astro, geo included), Chemistry, Biology
                Case Studies and Projects
            D and K
                Professional Relevant Projects
                    Amritsar
                        Places - Golden Temple, Durgyana Temple, Valmiki Ashram, War memorial, Jaliyawala Bagh
                            Chandigarh - Rock Garden, Pinjore Garden; NIT Jalandhar, 
                        Food - Kesar Dhaba, Bhrava da Dhaba, Kulche Chhole, Chhole Bhature, Lassi, etc.
                        Activities (wrt to city or without) or experiences - Gym, Suncity, School Kabaddi, School competitions, etc.
                            Stage presentations - in school for declamation, poetry, fancy dress, etc.
                                declamation, story telling;
                            Poetry - in school, on topics ranging motivation, morality and natural experiences.
                            Specially invited to senior class to sing payo ji maine naam ratan dhan payo.
                            dancing in festivals - marriage occasions, ability to accompany - home festival of dd shadi, Palace hall.
                        Purchases - Cable, etc.
                    Udhampur
                        Places - Kargil Park, Chinar / Dhruva Complex, ISKCON, Vaishno Devi Temple, Patnitop, Gulmarg, J & K tour, etc.
                        Food - Dum Alu, Shehtoot everywhere (white, purple, black), amrood from trees, katcha Papita Sabji.
                        Experiences - Naala, Army Campus, Campus experience, 90% claim successful, training sounds, chill cold, weather, etc.
                            Acting in school
                            Singing in front of crowd
                        Purchases - TV, etc.
                    Jamshedpur
                        Places - ?Dimna Lake, ?Jubilee Park, ?XLRI, Bistupur, TELCO, TESCO, Sakchi
                            Mayapur, Jagannath Puri, Remuna Kshir Chor Gopinath's khir.
                        Food - Bengali Impact
                        Experiences - Gaudiya Math in Sakchi
                            Devotee's hospital experience twice, etc.
                            college VOICE drama, member of CDS - Balaram Lila in JPV, Role of Ravan, Narad Muni, etc.
                            Singing Bhajans and Kirtans, etc.
                    Mysore
                        Places - Mysore Palace, Brindavan Gardens, Chamundeshwari Temple, Sand Art, Dushhehra Celebrations, etc.
                        Food - Food Courts in Infy
                        Purchases - Hearing device, ISKCON Mysore Ritvik
                    Pune
                        Places - ISKCON Katraj, Shanivarvada, Dehu (camps and for IAS exam), Pandharpur, Lonavala weather, Sarvateerth Taaked (Jatayu place), Nashik (Panchvati - BGP camp).
                            Bhopal, Indore, Mumbai visits - SP Stay, Gulbarg
                            Vrindavan, Mayapur, Jagannath Puri, Hampi, Udupi.
                        Food - Misal Paav, Paav Bhaji, Vada Paav, Kachhi Dhabeli, etc
                        Experiences
                            Bina PK Drama participant, Narsimha Drama dialogs, choreography, acting, etc.
                            Temple Dance, etc.
                    Bangalore
                        Places - Wonderla, Art of Living, ISKCON, Bangalore Palace costly ticket, Cubbon Park, Lal Bagh, MG Road, Bannerghatta, Phoenix Mall
                            Nandi Hills, Coorg, Goa, etc
                            Wonderla with college friends - water sports, high rides
                            ?Trek, intercity bike ride, 
                            Coorg - Abbey Waterfall and Raja's Seat Sunpoint; Madikeri; Omkareshwar Temple
                            Goa - Drive adventures, beaches
                            Shivan Samudhram - water fall, 
                            Sri Ranga Pattna, Devarayan Durga, Melekote, Madhva/Ramanuja places
                        Food - South Indian Meals
                        Purchases - Fridge, Mattress, Bed, TV, Smartphone, etc.
                            Pillow, Sports equipments, 
                            Online Streaming - YT, Amazon Prime, Netflix, Jio, Hotstar, etc.
                        Experience - ITR, Company Coupons, RSA Card, etc.
                            Siemens outbound sports - climb then free fall, mountaineering, xorbing, rope slide.
                            SAP
                                Inside resorts for sports, adventures
                                Team Lunch, Team movie (Deadpool), Team bachelor parties
                            Horror House near Wonderla - who initiated, my response to fear was punch the diaroma, etc.
                            Health Check up, etc.
                            Singing in temples - VOICE, Bangalore Seshadripuram temple Janmashtami and Sunday Kirtans.
                            Cinema - 3D Avengers Infinity War, 4D Avengers End Game2, 
                            Mall - Fish Spa, Body Spa or massage (oil, machine), Simulated Virtual Reality (Dragon on tracks, Scare on tracks, swinging with 3D views)
                            Barber - head massage, face wash,
                            YT Channel and Playlist formalization especially Music.
                    More - 
                    Uncat
                        Purchases 
                            Regular - toothpaste with Fluoride, soap alkeline and removes oil, vs go ark, etc
                        Entertainment
                            Movies
                                Bollywood - Anand, 
                                Hollywood - Shawshank Redemption
                            TV Series - GOT, Breaking Bad, etc
                            Comedy - Kapil Sharma, Bachao, etc.
                            Music
                                Old
                                New
                                Remix
                Personal Projects
                    Invented many games and challenges at home, udhampur for fun - tt on normal bench, basketball into havan kund, 
                        carrom board new games and upside down with spoon, chess hits, etc.
                        from inside room to parchhatti without touching the ground.
                        Jumping from roof to ground, badminton between 2 terraces.
            Details
                Technical Skills
                Domain Skills
                Management Skills
                Additional Qualifications
                Personal Interests
			Uncat - Grand Story or Larger narrative should be seen as places of residence that I have been through (homes, cities, etc)
        </EgoSpecific>
    </A>
    <F>
        About - Personal Health (for best resources to be at their best) - sharpening the saw.
            Includes Everything MINUS (Spirituality + Social Production + Social Consumption) = Science + Abstract PIES.
            Layered Health
                Eg - Personal health of different layers (Gym, Video Games, puzzles, sports, etc), Study of PIES.
                Fit@SAP Challenge
            General Abstract Learnings (PIES) - May also involve social interactions but grat is not in its consumption but very pronounced in what it makes you.
                The abstract BJDK doesn't fall under any specific layer.
                Eg - Self Help Books, Motivations, Affirmations.
        Objective
            Health of different layers of existence and their Stability (MOG) is primary concern here.
        B
            December target 150 Kms distance travel.
        J
        D
        K
            <Hobbies> Sports and Movies - 1/2 hour hobby every day.
                <Amusement>
                    Outdoors - Basketball, Badminton, Table Tennis, Cricket, Handball, Football, Lawn Tennis. Hockey - name sake. Golf in SAP.
                    Foosball, footsall, billiards, carrom, Chess, etc.
                    Lawn Tennis, Vollyball, Bowling with colleagues and with roommate once.
                    Uncat - swimming, Uno, Cards, etc.
                </Amusement>
                <GamePlay></GamePlay>
                <Sing></Sing>
                <MusicInstruments>
                    Mridanga, Cymbals, Keyboard, Guitar,
                </MusicInstruments>
                <Dance>
                    Bhangra 3 moves, Bollywood Free style, Shuffle Dance (2 moves), Zumba (random 2-3 moves)
                </Dance>
                <Books>
                    Salted bread, Harry Potter
                    Subtle art of not giving a f*ck, Everything is f*cked, Speed reading. 101 ways to make every second count.
                    The monk who sold his ferrari, Awaken the giant within, Who stole my cheese. 1 minute manager.
					The alchemist
                    Think and Grow Rich.
					Awaken the giant within
					7 habits of highly effective people
					Men are from mars and Women are from venus.
					As a man thinketh.
					?How to win friends and influence people
						https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Win_Friends_and_Influence_People
                    Future - rich dad, poor dad, unlimited power.
						The power of now.
						Languages of Love.
                </Books>
                <Acting>
                    Bina PK, Narsimha Drama, Balramji, Sphurti Friends, CDS at NIT JSR, KV Fillers demands.
                </Acting>
                Driving Streaks - 100 Kms on Bike inside bangalore across temples; Bangalore International stadium.
                    Bike - Pathankot (250 Km) and Jalandhar (175 Km) inter-district travel.
            </Hobbies>
        B and J
            Educational Qualifications
                School - PT, Yoga
                Family - Yoga
                Swami Ramdev TV and Online Videos - Yoga
                Spiritual Atmosphere in Udhampur - Peer Baba, 1 temple multiple religion deities - helped recover from depression, Campus temple programs/ yajna
                ISKCON - Mental and intellectual stability thru principles
                Amritsar Gym under trainer, College Gym under trainer, Siemens Gym
                Online - titbits but no course, talks from sadhguru, on Kundalini, from robin sharma, sandeep maheshwari, Tony Robbins, etc
                Motivational Talks during work outs; Affirmations before sleep
            Skills
                Badminton (with national champions), Basketball, Cricket, Football, Table Tennis
            Case Studies and Projects
        D and K
            Projects
                Amritsar
                    Healthy Diet - Ghee, Lassi, Milk, etc.
                    Gym under trainer
                Jamshedpur - Yoga and asanas every day.
                Pune
                    Runs in nearby Technical Park, Runs to-fro in the lane next to VOICE.
                    Yoga Everyday.
                    Preaching Projects for intellectual health.
                Bangalore
                    Svadhyay - very rewarding in terms of getting to the heart of things; Discussion walks with spiritually inclined.
                    Morning runs alone, Evening runs with friends (discussion and exercise), Siemens Gym, etc
                    Puzzle Solving (for DS interviews)
                    Morning Runs in Society Campus, Yoga in morning formality, Saturdays reserved for full length yoga.
                Accolades
                    School Kabaddi when I got whole team out and survived
                    Basketball - Gold in ByD
                    Panja won with SCM team member giving overall win to SRM team.
            Personal Projects
                College
                OSS or Independent
            Other Projects
        Details
            Technical Skills
            Domain Skills
            Management Skills
            Additional Qualifications
            Personal Interests
		Uncat - Grand Story or Larger Narrative
			Udhampur - Video Games, Outdoor games many.
			Jamshedpur - Bhangra in Puri, Acting, singing, Books reading, etc.
			PIES Pune, Video Gaming Starts, ASR Gym. Finger Chanting powerful.
			IIITB and Siemens - Morning Yoga and Exercise, Evening Run, Gym stretch.
				Om Chanting, Long walks.
			SAP - Society Gym - Morning runs, Morning inspirations, night affirmations, Sports so many participated.
				Emphasized 10 MM. Shloka Recitation or listening.
			SAP ASR - Evening Runs and walks. Many indoor Games and Challenges. ABCD Planned and Starts. Book Reading starts.
				Foreshadow - ABCD Depth. Lots of books. Standardizations, etc.
    </F>
    <LifeLogs>
		About - What currently going on.
        SQ
            Bridge - NS Camps Collected; SMY and EBG Planned.
            BSC
                Isho, NOI, Isho, BG KY Section Done, NOD.
        SIOT
            General
                SVM Security
                    CodeReview, Version updates - Jmeter run successful.
                Libraries -
                    Hotfix Version updates from Libs
                        versions exclusions using maven dependency tree.
                Performance Job Run - Configure a file for a system run and collect the metrics. No Framework devp.
                Spark IO Health Check
                    UML Diagram Approved.
            Monitoring -
                Context Name added.
                    Cleaning - Consider only Running Jobs and not Gone ones.
                Code Cleaning for user messages and Refactoring.
            Code Generator App Code Refactoring
                Design Patterns. Code to Text file parse and generate.
        EQ
            About - Ashram related SocialErp, HomeErp and PersonalErp.
            Company
                4G Hotspot Change
                Laptop Standby and backup.
            Bank
                Debit Card Issued - activation by call. Bank Internet Access regained.
                Credit Card payments thru Amazon Pay and customer care based calling.
            Home reorg
            Cooking - Biryani, Paneer, Beetroot palya.
            Transport
                Car
                    Tyre Change
                    Driving Practice.
                Bike Home Service.
                    Self Start not working - kick start without trigger.
                    Leakage corrected, part fitted, battery issue.
        Foundation / Health - December walk streak.
        ===UPDATE===
        Monitoring Check Status. Abstract Learning Spark, Kafka, Spring, Lambda, Mockito, Log4J.
    </LifeLogs>
</PIES>