<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PIES>
    <About>
    Make Resume for all of PIES
            PIES - all of them require Bhakti while we are in material world - are they against KC - no, Krishna wants us do them. 
                    Of course, eventually all of them should stabilize (MOG) so that they are not impedance to KC but that's in very high stages of development
                    the basis of relationship can be client server or peer to peer (sadhu sang of stages of bhakti) on any of PIES.
                    B and J club together
                            B - act of making resume, Courses done for the same
                            J - Chakshu developed (ability to understand and make of sense of anything outside); Capability Developed (Standardized behavior invocable for some service)
                                    Case Studies fall under this (and not D - cuz they are not your own)
                                    Covers all the tools and techniques at your disposal
                    D and K club together
                            D - act of solving a real world problem in terms of capabilities
                            K - use case solved and the corresponding karmic reactions - which all customers benefitted, some user stories, etc.
            Interview Projects Stories
                    it is just expansion of the core philosophy of the thing - like Data Science stages of development and tell your trace thru them.
                    Ability to draw UML diagrams to explain specifications, architecture, tools used, validation, deployment, maintenance.
                    Also an opportunity to go into D and K specifics of the project 
                            like what challenges did you face during devp, what were your responsibilities, who all used your product and their reviews.
                    Plan some 10-15 mins story around it.
            EQ
                    B
                            Civics (politics, law are just specializations), History (Civics of the past though people focus a lot on politics)
                            Economics
                            Psychology, Physical Science (Geography), Biology
                            Metaphysics, Chemistry
                    J - All News, discussions are actually J case studies but simply explore the dynamics of the J. Even action and impact of others are case studies for us to understand.
                    D - What's new with you; what are you up to, how are you doing, what's going on.
                    K - study of your actions and impacts or stories in the world
            PQ - Health
                    BJDK
            B - Scrum -> Themes in there.
                Epics (yearly update), Backlogs (release or monthly update), Stories (sprint or weekly update), Subtasks (daily update)
                For the dhansu thing that comes after the year, what is planned this month. What to do this week to get there. Give daily status update on that weekly goal.
            D - (Logs --> IQGrats, Lapse --> Stories, Standardizations). All the routine IQGrats and lapse don't come here; only the ones that stand out. DMPM goes to specific XMLs.
            J - All the DMPM doesn't come here but only the courses done. Others can go in MS Notebook or some concrete sections (local cache for all online helps)
            K - All the Logs don't come here but their rolled-up information. Logs used in ego section to support narratives.
            Ego Specific - Logs view prepared for a narrative.
    </About>
    <S>
        BY - Scrum and Themes
        DY - Mantra Meditation, Naiti Meditation, Attention Meditation, Transcendental Meditation, Pranayama Breathing Meditations.
        JY - SMY, Bhakti Shastri, Sadhguru casual talks, Art of living casual talks.
        KY - VA Evolution Focus. 
            Sakaam - Services (social or trans-spiritual) Sacrificing fruits portion - Charity for spiritual growth, for social well being.
            Nishkaam - Services sacrificing fruit (partly or completely) and work portion - services that please but no tangible outcome eg - FFL
            Nishkaam2 - Services sacrificing fruit and work outside personal space - takes tapa and no tangible outcome eg - BG Book distribution.
            BKY - Services sacrificing oneself (there exists no other personal space) - only interested in work for others or Krishna.
                Eg - Camps Services like vessel washing - heavy lifting, Temple Services rendered. VOICE services all kinda (more like ashram or home in its worldly projection but trans in nature)
        <EgoSpecific> Covers Trans Spirituality
            Objective
                B and J
                    Educational Qualifications
                        NIT J VOICE - DYS, Sphurti, DD Series, VANY Courses
                        IIT KGP - Sankalpa, Utkarsh, VTW
                        Pune - EBG, BG Sloka Series, ISKCON Leadership Course by BGP Pr Course, TSS CCP listen streak
                            Nishtha, Ashray, GS / NS Camps
                        Bangalore - Bhakti Shastri Online (Isho, NOI, NOD, ToDo - BG)
                    Skills
                        Vaishnav Etiquette, Musical Instruments, Singing, 1-1 casual inspiration (preaching)
                        Services - Food For Life Distribution, BG Marathon, ?Fund Collection, Transcription, cleaning and temple services.
                            QA on class, Singing
                        Department In charge - 
                            Bulk Sabji/ Grocery Purchase (JSR, VIT) - Quality identification, Bargaining for bulk purchase, arrange auto, heavy lifting, Reimbursements.
                            Account management - Book keeping, reimbursements, personal fulfillment of gaps, etc.
                            Notice Board Department - Inspiring Articles from different sources procured and pasted, Quiz weekly for awards.
                            Book Distribution inventory management - Book keeping.
                            Deity Department - utensils, altar cleaning, morning puja schedule, decoration plans, etc.
                            Utensils - assignment to all devotees in round robin.
                            milk - procurement, delivery, PR, payments and devs advanced payments, boiling, mensuration, stage/ board inspiration.
                            Morning Program Incharge - Lect, Sr Devs request, QA, Orchestrating schedules, etc.
                            Garland Purchasing in JSR - Standardizing the rates, exploring all options, keeping them in fear.
                            Cylinder brining Seva in JSR and Hinjewadi - vehicles, personal, auto arranging, maneuvering thru crowd, advance booking.
                            ?Cleaning - Altar floor cleaning, 
                            Event Management - When all paraphernalia was carried to some camp and somethings got lost and I paid for them.
                    Case Studies and Projects - ??
                D and K
                    Professional Relevant Projects - 
                        About 
                            The purpose of any project is preaching (being essence or prayojan) - iow, culture of inspiration in DS.
                            basis is books (sambandha)
                            utility or engagement (abhidhyeya)
                            Vision success dependent on purity (oil that runs the machine - gratitude is internal)
                        Radha Govinda Kolkata
                            Jagannath Puri Voice - Rourkela Project intiative, M.Tech Preaching.
                            Krishna Gatipur Voice
                        Radha Kunjabihari Pune
                            Atmanivedan YOGA - Accounting, etc
                                Initiative Projects - Gurbarg, IISER, I2IT Pune, etc.
                            Atmanivedan Lotus VOICE - Cleaning, etc.
                            Atmanivedan YOGA2 - Deity Worship, etc.
                        Radha Vrindavan Chandra
                            Vraj Dham VOICE - Utensils washing, Milk Department, etc.
                        Jagannath Temple ICC Bangalore
                        Jagannath Temple Seshadripuram Bangalore
                        SLNT (Gandharvika Giridhari Mandir)
                            Whitefield Bhakti Center
                    Personal or other Projects
                        Visited Temples - Radha Gopinath, Radha Giridhari, Vrindavan temples, Jagannath Puri, Mayapur, Hampi, Udupi, Pandarpur, Dehu.
                Details - doesn't apply
                    Technical Skills
                    Domain Skills
                    Management Skills
                    Additional Qualifications
                    Personal Interests
        </EgoSpecific>
    </S>
    <V>
        About - Varna is about being best producer in the social ecosystem (career)
        <B> about - ego targets
            DevOps
                EPIC - ?; Backlog - Spark Streaming.
            DataScience
                EPIC - ?; Backlog - Spark ML.
            Systems
                EPIC - ?; Backlog - CF.
            Research
                EPIC - ?; Backlog - Book Reader.
        </B>
        <J> technologies I know
            <AppsUsed> SaaS - being client of to give some service
                AWS
                Outlook
                Word
                Photoshop
                Networking - TCP Dump, WinSCP, Putty, Moba, ssh.
                Postman, Slack, Browser Debugging.
                Tableau, etc.
            </AppsUsed>
            <Domain>
                FIN
                SCM - SRM, SCM, CRM
                HCM
                Foundations - Auth, Security, BC, etc.
            </Domain>
            <DesignTime> Regex, HW, POC.
                <Tools> can use an app as a server or for extension.
                    Excel, Browsers.
                </Tools>
                <CodeManagement>
                    Version Management - Github
                    Build Management - Ant, Maven
                    Integration - REST API, SOAP API, 
                    Parsing - Regex, CUP Parser, Lex/Yacc.
                    ByD Specific - Event Manager, Message Manager, Change Manager, PDAO.
                    Quality - JMeter.
                </CodeManagement>
                <Frontend>
                    HTML, JS, CSS, Bootstrap
                </Frontend>
                <Libraries>
                    UI Automation - Selenium
                    JAVA Email Integration
                    Clients - SparkClient, RestClient, etc.
                    API for Persistence - GSON, YAML, XML, JSON, Text Files, Properties, Cassandra, etc.
                        Properties
                    Log4J
                </Libraries>
                <Langauges> Scripts included
                    G4 - SQL (MySQL, Oracle, MS-SQL), Hive, Pig, Shell Scripting, NoSQL (Cassandra, MongoDB, HBase)
                    G3 - C, R, Java, C#, C++, Scala, Python, JS, TS, ABAP.
                        Functional - JS, TS, R, Scala, Python.
                        OOP - JAVA, C#.
                            Java Language Features - Generics, Threads, Lambda, etc.
                        Procedural - C, CPP, ABAP.
                        system calls,
                    G2 - Assembly Language
                </Langauges>
                <Frameworks> Everything is done - you need to only set properties or customize the code to suit you - using exits; Diagrams with explanations
                    <Tools>Struts, Swings, JSP, Hibernate</Tools>
                    <Misc>NuSMV (Model Checking or software verification), Hadoop, ByD Descriptive/Exploratory Analytics Framework, PD Framework</Misc>
                    <Testing>Start Scripting for testing, BOUM2 for Integration Testing, JUnit, ABAPUnit</Testing>
                </Frameworks>
                <IDE> 
                    UI - UIDesigner
                    ?IntelliJ, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Ginee, Netbeans, RStudio, Notepad++, Textpad, ABAP Logon
                </IDE>
            </DesignTime>
            <Platforms>
                Database Server - PostGres, MS SQL, MySQL, 
                    NoSQL - Cassandra, HBase, MongoDB, Neo4J, etc.
                    Data Models - RDBMS, XML, JSON, Text, Semantic Web, Data Warehousing, NoSQL, Spark Libs.
                Application Server - Express NodeJS, router, DOTNET 3.5, JSP, J2EE, etc.
                    Struts, Jersey, Spring
                Web Server - Apache Tomcat, Glassfish, LanguageSpecific Servers like NodeJS.
            </Platforms>
            <PaaS>
                Ops - Jenkins, Cloudfoundry, Kubernetes, Docker.
                Spark Server, Kafka Brokers, Hadoop Ecosystem, etc.
                RDBMS Servers, 
            </PaaS>
            <IaaS>
                Servers - AWS, Azure, GCP, Alibaba, SCP, Private Cloud.
                Virtualization - OS - VMWare, IOT, Arduinno, Raspberry Pi.
                Networking 
                Storage 
            </IaaS>
            <Misc>Kafka, Ambari, Hortonworks</Misc>
        </J>
        <D>
            About - 
                List of Problems Solved with ingenuity - smart and clever approach; engineering tested here (how excellently managed all techs to an end); POCs, Ideas proposed
                Can cover all engineering and architectural details
                List all the IQGrats.
            ADT and DS known - Set, List, Tree, DAG, Graphs; handling strings
            Algos - Brute Force, Divide and Conquer, Greedy, Dynamic Programming, etc.
            Design Patterns - Strategy, Singleton, Factory Design, etc.
            Courses done (or capabilities at disposal) - Compiler Design, Approximation Algorithms.
            Instances
                Debug surpassed to reset the version to old when NGAP transactions started failing
                ability to download data to analyse a ticket - like tracing the stacks of execution for 2 exits where data changed!
                Shell scripts for fast implementations of Hadoop execution engines.
                using java code to create API for custom queries on hadoop execution engines.
                web scraping for presto to read performance - cuz REST API was not known.
                    web scraping for desktop images.
                Subscript matching assignments
                excel vba for reducing efforts of manipulating data details from REST JSON response of ML based Leonardo API.
        </D>
        <K> All Projects Done - be able to tell tech, etc used, contributions, roles played; challenges faced - some really interesting problems you feel proud to solve
            NIT JSR
                Java Media Player
                SQL Administration
            Infy
                SEZONL
                Manual Testing for AT&T
                Expert Support for BT
            VIT Pune
                Teaching Programming
            IIIT B
                eBAY and REST on top
                ACT Project - Testing Automation using Scripts
                Semantic Web on NoSQL (Neo4J)
                Stackoverflow analytics
            Siemens
                Best execution engine for a given query - Data Science to metrics collection using program
                Space Optimization Engine for NoSQL Engines - Cassandra, HBase, etc
                Design Proposed for handling IOT sensor data
            SAP
                Business By Design - End to End ERP Business Suite
                NSME - End to End ERP Business Suite on NodeJS Express PostSQL tech stack.
                SAP IOT - Big Data Analytics for SAP IOT Data Streams.
        </K>
        <EgoSpecific>
            about - focus on how I am suitable for a role cuz my ego matches with that.
                also include friends and what they did is also a sign of what you are.
                anything you do must be a line in resume!!
            <Schema>
                Objective
                B and J
                    Educational Qualifications
                    Analytical Skills and Certfications
                        Highlighted Tools
                        Technologies
                    Case Studies and Projects
                D and K
                    Professional Relevant Projects
                    Personal Projects
                        College
                        OSS or Independent
                    Other Projects
                Details
                    Technical Skills
                    Domain Skills
                    Management Skills
                    Additional Qualifications
                    Personal Interests
            </Schema>
            <Research>
                //innovative ideas that saw the light can be quoted casually.
                    ideally, not just papers read but papers read on specific topic as knowledge part and for project part, papers read to solve a problem or write a paper.
                Objective
                    ???
                B and J
                    Educational Qualifications
                        M.Tech - 
                            RDBMS Criteria paper
                            ACT Project Paper reading and proposing ideas - what were they?
                            Semantic Web on NoSQL Ideas
                    Analytical Skills and Certfications
                        Highlighted Tools
                            All tools apply
                        Technologies
                            All technologies apply
                    Case Studies and Projects
                        ???
                D and K
                    Professional Relevant Projects
                        Siemens - Implementation of Paper on Minimize the storage in NoSQL using graph
                        SAP
                            ?multi-tenancy support for Software Defined Networks
                            ?Applications of physics in gaming
                    Personal Projects
                        College
                            ???
                        OSS or Independent
                            ???
                    Other Projects
                        ???
                Details
                    Technical Skills
                    Domain Skills
                    Management Skills
                    Additional Qualifications
                    Personal Interests
                Friends - 
                    ?Mayank Tiwari papers.
            </Research>
            <Systems> also includes frameworks development or utils development
                Objective
                    ???
                B and J
                    Educational Qualifications
                        B.Tech - Compiler Design - yacc and CUP Parser
                        M.Tech - OS, CN, TOC, Network Security(, Cryptography), Model Validation (nuSMV), ?Distributed Computing, IOT Seminar.
                            General - DSA, Data Modeling, OOAD, DP, etc.
                        online curious run on raspberry pi and arduino
                            !Cloud Design Patterns (eg - valet), etc.
                    Analytical Skills and Certfications
                        Highlighted Tools
                        Technologies
                            Socket Programming, System Calls - ability to make processes communicate, etc, thread management, semaphores locking
                    Case Studies and Projects
                        Implemented and added shell command for calendar
                        Socket Programming in JAVA - for sorting numbers (sounds like exercise and not project)
                        Updated kernel with a function of our own - Used VM for the same.
                        Cryptography algorithms and simulation
                D and K
                    Professional Relevant Projects
                        Siemens
                            a lot of linux command utilities for hadoop cluster maintenance; creating hadoop cluster
                            Shell script to auto-install presto and configure it fully on the system.
                            In Siemens, created a shell like program - which would take commands and run the commands we supported in java.
                            hadoop installation - thru VM directly, thru personal local set up, thru private cluster set up, thru AWS.
                            VMs networking, SSH, SCP, etc across VM, personal system.
                            Deployment of JAVA software on AWS for performance measurement on public cloud platform.
                            Threading in Siemens but used semaphores for critical section to ensure concurrency that doesn't overwrite existing records.
                            Siemens suggested a UML Design Document for IOT based Project for storage of the data.
                                Graph based trend algorithm following to minimize disk space consumed by IOT data produced by machines 
                                although it is DS but overall it's a framework also
                        SAP - Docker, Kubernetes, GIT, out of the box Tools for operations and testing
                            Training in Operations or deployment - Service Provider Cockpit (SPC), Regressions handling.
                            Used IaaS, PaaS out of the box to make our SaaS from SCP - changed to NodeJS to avail hyperscalers facility.
                                used SCP for Leonardo API for every system in ByD Product Space.
                            SAP Frameworks explored - ESF, BOPF, PDF, Oberon, Frontend JavaScript Framework, PI Framework - Message exchange across Deployment Units
                                frameworks used - let's call it application thing
                            SIOT - version updates of libraries cuz of security patches. MITM, Request Smuggling, Authentication, etc.
                    Personal Projects
                        College
                            ACT Project - created our own tiny language for web site abstracts - ability to parse it through yacc or CUP Parsers - ability to perform compilation.
                        OSS or Independent
                            Personal Practice - Operating System Programs, Networking Algorithms like Sliding Window Protocol, DNS, DHCP
                            ?Implementing the algorithms used by OS.
                    Other Projects
                        //should come under application perhaps but lots of thingy stuff here. Still call it extensions Programming - comes under Applications.
                            VLC match subtitles file
                            automatic desktop background changer
                            ?Google extension code - not done but to change the URL from silverlight to UI5.
                            convert transcript to text notes.
                Details
                    Technical Skills - vs on top - this is more casual and exhaustive and top one is only highlights for the specific JD role
                        Tools for Network Security.
                        ?Blockchain
                    Domain Skills
                    Management Skills
                    Additional Qualifications
                    Personal Interests
                Misc
                    //Interview call for every system company that visited - Arista, Cisco, etc.
                Casual
                    Shell Scripting (using git) - Find Lines, words or characters of Code implemented till now in SME. Also number of files.
            </Systems>
            <DevOps>
                Objective
                    ???
                B and J
                    Educational Qualifications
                        IIT Kharagpur Certification in C++ and JAVA.
                        M.Tech - OOAD, Design Pattern, Data Modeling, ?Distributed Computing
                        Online Lynda Courses - Javascript, Typescript,
                        LinkedIn - NodeJS, Express, GITHUB, Microservices Foundation (assignments remaining), 
                        JavaBrains - Spring, Lambda, TS, Maven, JS, Struts, 
                    Analytical Skills and Certfications
                        Highlighted Tools
                            DOTNET, C#, ?CPP, JAVA, SQL, NoSQL Databases like Neo4J, Cassandra, HBase; Struts, JQuery, Bootstrap; Jenkins, JMeter, ?Cloudfoundry / Kubernetes / Docker,
                            Ops Tools, Java Lambda, OAuth, Log4j2, etc.
                        Technologies
                            Algorithms, Approximation Algorithms, Data Structures, Design Patterns (Frontend (UI, Persuasive) and Backend(Java, JS)), OOAD/ UML, Data Modeling
                    ?Case Studies and Projects
                        Algorithms - 
                            Fibonacci series number generation; multiplication of 2 very large numbers - beyond the storage capacity of the data type.
                            ACT Project - Traversing all paths in Test automation of a system
                        Approximation Algorithms - ??
                        Data Structures - ??
                        Design Patterns - ?SME Solution Model
                        OOAD - EBay Prototype
                        Data Modeling - Semantic Web Modeling in Neo4J
                        Javascript - ?Analog Clock, ?Typing Speed Test App (can merge the two)
                        Typescript - ?ToDo List App
                        NodeJS 
                D and K
                    Professional Relevant Projects
                        Infy - Systems Engineer
                            Trainee
                                C, JAVA, SQL, LINUX, UXD.
                                DOTNET
                                Some Case Studies - Airline Booking System
                            Infy - SEZ Online
                                what - windows, IDE VS, asp dotnet, c#, ms sql
                                Traceability - SRS Requirements to Implementation mapping - Sequential Diagram for faster development, better maintenance thru easy debugging.
                            ATT Testing
                                what - LINUX, QTP, Citrix, Excel, Internal Tools.
                                LINUX scripts for data generation, QTP or selenium for data generation for stress testing
                                running UI scripts for scenario coverage
                            BT Support
                                what - PL/SQL, Internal Tools.
                                Message management
                                SQL scripts writing for application data consistency.
                        VIT Pune - Assitant Professor
                            Teaching Computer Programming - Structured and OOPS.
                                invented ideas - online google form based quiz, etc.
                            Guide for Projects - Tic Tac Toe, Console Based Marketing Software, 
                        IIITB - Student
                            EBay Prototype and REST Services
                                what
                                    Bootstrap, Jquery, JSP, AJAX, Windows, Eclipse, Apache Tomcat 9, Structs, Java, Mysql, MVC.
                                contribution
                                    Management - work assignment dynamics, etc.
                                        //ability to list all management lessons learnt from professor
                                    Schema Design, and UML Diagrams - Use Case, Sequence, DFD, etc on paper and StarUML.
                                    Purchase Scenario Coverage - division by application areas (and not technologies - cuz e1 wants to learn)
                            ACT Project - Abstract to Concrete Testing Framework
                                what - CUP Parser, JAVA, Selenium, Solvers (Linear Programming), Paper reading.
                                contribution - architectural ideas, Random data types generations, Web Design representation in invented format, Parsing the format to build a graph
                                    navigation thru the graph for finding all the paths, formulation of equations for all the paths, using solvers to come up with answers.
                                    build test cases using the answers, abstract to concrete conversion, running selenium scripts on the concrete test cases.
                            Semantic Web modeled in Neo4J
                                what - XML Parser, XML, Neo4J, MongoDB for evaluation, OWL for semantic web, Bootstrap, Apache Tomcat.
                                contribution - 
                                    Application of Rules of Reasoning to infer based on existing edges - eg - isFather and isBrother means isSon relationship, etc.
                                    Modeling of a college data model
                        Siemens - Research Scientist - proves capability of making a framework
                            what
                                VM - VMWare, Hortonworks HDP2.0, CentOS, Windows SCP, Moba for SSH, etc.
                                Libraries - Properties File, Logger, Random Number generation Types.
                                UML online Softwares like Visual Paradigm
                                Hadoop Technologies - HIVE, Spark, Drill, Presto, Ambari REST API.
                                NoSQL (Cassandra, MongoDB, HBase)
                                JAVA, REST API, Bootstrap for display, JUnit for Testing, Threading for faster access
                                Factory Design Pattern, Singleton
                            contribution
                                Benchmarking Studio - Best execution engine for a given query
                                    TPCDS, customizing queries as per syntax (using regex)
                                Query Metrics Collector - Space Optimization Engine for NoSQL Engines
                                    Ideas - compressors, trend avoiding algorithm based on a paper, distributions that perform best.
                                    randomly generated data of different data types as per specific distribution.
                                    collection of running the application on AWS with specified data besides local cloud.
                                Design Formulation for IOT based Project
                        Associate Developer at SAP Labs
                            BYD
                                what and contributions
                                    Specification
                                        Exposure Large scale ERP applications, Suite in a box - end to end business processes support
                                    Design 
                                        Experience of NGAP Application Platform, Multiple Application Frameworks, Communications across Application Areas; SRM Application Area Development
                                        Trace framework thru debugging to tell which configuration is missing or where the data provided for next exit was insufficient or if framework needs a change
                                            very small changes like variable retaining old value so clear - very corner case like unit price rounding followed by total price rounding 
                                            loss of precision causes PO for approval to take place although shopping cart said otherwise - business scenario suffers.
                                            ?exposure to real world scenarios for design patterns - command pattern, factory, singleton, Strategy, Subscriber, etc.
                                    Implementation
                                        Tools
                                            Eclipse on ABAP, SAP GUI IDE for Web based IDE development
                                            HANA DB, MAX DB - Materialized Views for Analytics
                                        Features
                                            Fully Model Driven Software Development (configurations at different levels Developer, Key user, end user, etc)
                                            Analytics - Managing OLAP Systems - UI, Internal development tool, framework, MAX DB Materialized view secondary storage.
                                            Task Management - for end user attentions from messages failed across applications, etc.
                                            Output Management - pdf generation and sending by email. Using XML and Template (Adobe LiveCycle Designer) to Adobe Server.
                                            Workflow management - Approvals based on configured BO conditions, mapped to task management, Exception Handling in SIV, etc.
                                        UI
                                            ABAP, Fiori, UI5, Silverlight, Inbuilt version management, Transport Requests Management for DevOps.
                                            UI Development thru internal tool
                                            RUBY Scripts on internal tool, javascript, html;
                                        Integrations - Synchronous (A2X for tools like excel, etc) and Asynchronous (within or outside tenants)
                                            RMI or RFC as SAP calls it.
                                        ABAP to Typescript conversion - regex to create templates ready to use. (but didn't use it)
                                        User Stories (in short and incomplete - refer to byd for details)
                                            GDPR LXP, eInvoicing, Scanned Invoicing from text (support for intercompany), Scanned Invoicing from pdf, PO Reminder Letters (dunning), Manual PR, 
                                            Link PRs to PO, PO Schedule Lines, IFRS, OLAP Reports (GDPR Data protection related, and more)
                                            Scanned Invoice to SIV BO - from text, from pdf (REST API, using OAuth1), from pdf on email, from pdf on folder thru collaboration window
                                            Manual PR QAF ECO
                                            shopping cart mobile app
                                            GDPR implementation adoption - writing code for BO exits - filtering and bo name.
                                            delivery sch lines
                                            Link PR Items with PO - action
                                            Document Destroy GDPR implementation
                                            Background job filtering out for health checks
                                            PO root price components in Output Form           
                                            Kit items price calculation issue
                                            Invoice scanning review screen
                                            Master data PPS gaf.
                                            Create SIV From SIS - BO Updates Determinations, etc.
                                                    date User Fields from API fields in SIS BO - regex
                                                    PO reference so SIV created from SIS
                                                    Able to delete PDF files 1 or multiple.
                                            Update A2X Web Service - Read PO. A2A etc updates.
                                            Invoice scanning from text - Pattern Correction for Scanned Invoice from Text - problem of image having a pattern - that matches ditto fine tuned the regex.
                                            Email PDF to SIS BO Changes
                                                    SIS only permit PO that exist in system
                                            Data Source fields addition, updates.
                                            GDPR - BO Retention supplement
                                                    GDPR Person Deletion adoption.
                                            IFRS16 Lease Contract Payment Schedule Status Handle - Authorization handling included.
                                                    Lease Contract Run Remove Unauthorized Companies
                                            Excel integration - catch exceptions
                                            Cost Distribution for Goods Returned, All kinds of scenarios coverage. Additional cost distribution items
                                            Translation - OneChina Adoption also, otherwise b4 also.
                                            SIV Attachment Update (EC mappings)
                                            SIV Template supress errors
                                            BTM Task for ISI GSA request with bad PO Item ref - XML fails, inform user on UI with expected action.
                                            GSA expected read only flag as per business scenario state. IMAT, Finish resume PO properties. Shopping Card Retrieval COBL SO ref for Proj        
                                            SME - Create SIV From PO, Make Payment on SIV and message handling.
                                                    SIV OWL Filters - selections and filters on CIP.
                                            Lease contract not found error messages - many such.
                                            Intrastat added error message for clarity
                                            Avoid dump for convert key to node id on item node - lots of framework level changes or adoptions even in PD - like clear the buffer.
                                            Product Category w/o Product Assignment not possible;
                                            Z-prefix CDT Days Due and Fixed Date both active together - Enable parameters of days, month and fixed date for payment terms maintenance
                                            More - 
                                                management very well understood roll up, drill down.
                                                Consulting related discussions for end desirable product for end users, AUnits creation, JS Mocha Tests created and suggested.
                                                Design discussions like e-invoicing using word cloud
                                                Testing - BOUM2 and START scripts creation, run, correction - CRUD.
                                                Deployments - Hotfixes, patches, VP, EP.
                                                    Bug fixes and extensions in practically every BYD implementations, deployment assistance once using SPC (Service Provider Cockpit)
                                                Maintenance at all levels L1, L2, L3 - 
                                                    Consulting - helps thru call 1:1, 1:n, consulting; Customer concerns directly visible. VH and over weekend support.
                                                    corrections - UI work arounds, runtime corrections (debugger), back end DB corrections; 
                                                    code corrections, customer influence or extensions or future commits.
                                    Testing
                                        Unit Testing (AUNIT), Internal Tools for Testing - Integration testing (BOUM2), System Testing (Start WebIDE, Stand alone), Regression Based Testing (RBT)
                                    Support
                                        Creation and maintenance of tools for maintenance and support - along with custom reports writing for backend correction, DB Corrections.
                                        Consultations to customers for adapting software to their business needs or suggesting work arounds
                                        ABAP Debugger, User change log and few days interaction log for code correction
                                    Misc - communications
                            NSME
                                what and contributions
                                    Specifications - Fresh scoping the application for different packages.
                                        Cross Functional works - Pricing, Master data, Foundation task creation, FIN coding block.
                                    Design - Fresh implementations so usage of many design patterns - singleton, strategy, template method, DAO, command, etc.
                                        ?saw working of an application server end to end.
                                        raising bugs, working on systems that are still stabilizing and not robust (eg colleagues on UI)
                                        Creating many stubs and skeletons.
                                    Implementations - GIT, VS Code, NPM, Node Express, REST API.
                                        Promises, callbacks, decorators, Postgres, HANA, etc. Debugging in TS, JS.
                                        Implemented Determination, validation, action, folder structure organization; used libraries like request.
                                        ML API integration for shopping cart approval - confidence as input for user and auto-approve as per user's choice. Configurable to write into a file.
                                            Mass Approval (set confidence in process map and play approvals in 1 go)
                                    Testing - Mocha Chai Unit Testing, Integration Testing, Sys and UAT by different teams in china.
                                        Unit Test also across lcp calls assuming all validations and determinations in place. Not class specific.
                                            UT cuz of less granular tests at attribute level 
                                            integration test should focus on less granular stuff - PR is created, PO is in this status - scenario specific.
                                    Support - Logger Service for us to read the logs and tell what went wrong.
                                    Misc - start up feel, Manager roles understood better. Concept of Time recording better understood for billing and planning.
                                User Stories - 
                                    SRM POC for the NSME foundation - doable.
                                        IR - HEADER_CURR_CHECK - migrating validations and determinations.
                                            /SRMAP/CL_LREQ_IR_MODBO_PARTY
                                            Action: ITEM Copy
                                            /SRMAP/CL_LREQ_IR_IPROC_PRCT_E
                                            /SRMAP/CL_FND_C_FILL_ITEM_ID
                                            Incident solving or maintenance in NSME
                                                Date handling and changing dates
                                                Save not rejected for shopping carts w/o items
                                        ML API for Auto approvals of IR - REST API asynchronous calls to deployed models, data formatting and manipulations.
                                    SRM on NSME - all 3 tiers
                                        SIV OIF - all the layers - front, middle, back tiers.
                                            Done and remaining update regularly - hours recorded and task level tracing for updates.
                                        PurchaseOrderFactsheet - all layers - added task tracing at bugs and fixing level - 
                                            cuz many at that time and micromanagement so would tell them where the error in framework is 
                                            or use workarounds like adding codes to framework or DB query running after run.
                                            Creating pending user stories for transparency of bottlenecks.
                                        Migrate Purchase order Factsheet
                                    FIN UI And CIP mapping from BYD to NSME
                                        SplitOpenItemsFactSheetEnhancedController - UI and CIP.
                                        CheckDepositOWL - CIP
                                        txecslfactsheet - UI - Europe Community Tax Returns based on sales list.
                                        PaymentAllocationEditQAFEnhancedController_QAF_V2 - Allocate payment to SIV or CIV etc.
                                        IncomingFileOWL_V2 - Files for Bank or partners interface - bank statements, cheque deposits, etc.
                                        CostObjectsSettlementRunCreate_QAF - EC for background job creation.
                    Personal Projects
                        College
                            SQL Administration
                            JAVA Media Player
                        OSS or Independent
                    Other Projects
                Details
                    Technical Skills
                    Domain Skills
                    Management Skills
                    Additional Qualifications
                    Personal Interests
            </DevOps>
            <DataScience>
                Interview
                    Techs    ----> Knowledge of architecture and Ability to demo thru a challenge
                    Projects ----> Ability to convince about your best architecture
                <Objective>
                    To pursue a challenging and growth-oriented career in a Progressive Organization 
                        and to engage/ enhance the level of my technical knowledge, domain expertise along with skills and ability to work in-group
                </Objective>
                <BAndJ>
                    <EducationalQualification>
                            ToDo - Online Course - Udemy - PySpark, Spark Streaming.
                            TODO - LinkedIn assignments for - Hadoop, Microservices foundations
                            ToDo - Online Course - Analytics Vidhya
                                Specialization - NLP
                                Year and credits
                            Online Certification - Coursera
                                Specialization - ML
                            Online Course - Jigsaw Academy
                                Specialization - Machine Learning in R
                            M. Tech - IIIT Bangalore
                                Specialization - Data Science
                                Optional - Data Analytics, Data Modeling, Data Visualization, Distributed Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning
                                    Future - Network Science for Web, GIS, Deep Learning.
                            B. Tech - NIT Jamshedpur
                                Specialization - Computer Science
                            H.S.C. - K V No 1, Udhampur
                                Specialization - PCMB
                            S.S.C. - K V No 1, Udhampur
                            Specialization - NA
                            Future - DL RNN LSTM, AI, DC, NLP, etc.
                    </EducationalQualification>
                    <AnalyticalSkillsAndCertifications>
                        <HighlightedTools>
                            R programming
                            Python
                            Hadoop
                            Spark - PySpark Batch, Spark Streaming, ?SparkML, ?GraphX
                            Kafka
                            Hadoop Ecosystem Tools (HIVE, Drill, Presto, etc.)
                            Tableau
                            Advanced Excel (VBA)
                            Cloud Platforms like AWS, Private Cloud
                            SQL Tools (MS, MySQL, Oracle, etc.)
                            NoSQL Tools (Cassandra, HBase, Influx, etc.)
                        </HighlightedTools>
                        <Technologies> Techniques, algos, etc
                            Data extraction, cleaning, Data warehousing
                            Statistical Techniques, Data Visualization
                            Big Data Mining through Hadoop Tools
                            Hypothesis Testing
                            Regression Analysis (linear, logistic, etc.)
                            Classification (Random Forest, Ensemble Modeling) - Predictive Modelling
                            Clustering techniques (k-means, agglomerative, RFM analysis)
                            Association Rules
                            Neural Networks
                            Time series Forecasting
                            Strong Analytical and presentation skills
                            Optimization and simulation models
                        </Technologies>
                    </AnalyticalSkillsAndCertifications>
                    <CaseStudiesAndProjects>
                        <Techniques>
                            Statistics, Visualization
                                Visualizations based on Stack overflow data survey
                            Linear regression	
                                Predicting food truck profits from the city population
                                House Price Prediction of a locality from house size and number of bedrooms.
                            Polynomial Regression (regularization included)
                                Prediction of the amount of water flowing out of a dam using the change of water level in a reservoir.
                            Logistic regression
                                Predict Students admission into University based on marks in 2 exams
                            Support Vector Machines (SVM)
                                Spam Classifier  predict if a given email is spam based on the training over a dataset.
                            Neural Network
                                Digits recognition from handwritten image
                            Clustering
                                Image Compression using K-means clustering on RGB pixels.
                            PCA (Principle Component Analysis)
                                Dimensionality Reduction of an image of 1024 pixels to 56 without significant loss of data and speed up learning.
                            Anomaly Detection
                                Detecting anomalous behavior of computing servers in terms of latency and throughput.
                            Recommender System
                                Suggest a movie based on different ratings given to movies by various users
                            Time series
                        </Techniques>
                    </CaseStudiesAndProjects>
                </BAndJ>
                <DAndK>
                    <ProfessionalRelevantProjects>
                        <Siemens2016>
                            Research Scientist (internship):
                                R&D, Siemens, 
                                Electronic City, Bangalore.
                                Total Experience: 7 Months (Dec 2016-June 2017)
                            <ProblemsAndSolutions>
                                Runtime Selection of Best Hadoop Execution Engines for a query on Big Data
                                    Skills - HDFS, HIVE, Drill, Presto, Spark, JAVA, JAVA Regex, JUnit, REST API, Bootstrap UI
                                    Solution
                                        Runtime Selection of Best Hadoop Execution Engines for a query on Big Data
                                        HDFS, HIVE, Drill, Presto, Spark, JAVA, JAVA Regex, JUnit, REST API, Bootstrap UI
                                        Knowledge of Design Patterns, Logger, Property File employed to create the framework.
                                        Used TPCDS data store to test the execution metrics for queries run on candidate Hadoop ecosystem tools.
                                        REST API used to fetch results from AMBARI after every query run.
                                        Handled multiple formats like text, JSON/ XML, CSV
                                        Regression didnt seem to be the best technique to be employed and hence classification was proposed for the same.
                                Selecting best NoSQL Database for storing stream data from sensors and algorithms to minimize the disk storage for the same	
                                    Skills - Cassandra, HBase, Influx, JAVA
                                    Solution 
                                        Adding another NoSQL tool influx to the existing framework.
                                        Generation of random data types (numbers, strings, etc) following a certain distribution to simulate the sensor behaviors.
                                        Collection of metrics and visualization in excel
                                        Creating types of queries in java which are not supported by the tool out of the box. Eg  Hbase total records.
                                        Implementation of slope algorithm to minimize the data objects instances stored by HBase.
                                Design Proposal for handling IOT Data Stream
                                    Skills - Diagrams- starUML, LucidChart Online	
                                    Solution
                                        Proposed a Design for the upcoming application.
                                Uncat - Kafka 
                            </ProblemsAndSolutions>
                        </Siemens2016>
                        <SAP2017>
                            Associate Developer
                                Business ByDesign (ERP Business Suite), SAP Labs
                                Whitefield, Bangalore.
                                Total Experience: 2 years 1 month (July 2017-Till Now)
                            Requirements and Responsibilities
                                Real Time Analytics (OLAP) for Business Users
                                    Skills - Knowledge of Data warehousing, Understanding of existing data model
                                    Major Responsibilities
                                        Creating materialized views for storage of transactional data to HANA data base on the fly.
                                        Modeling the mapping of dimensional features and fact variables from user view to the materialized views.
                                        Handling the change in user requirements through customized reports and design time modeling changes.
                                Conversion from Supplier Invoice PDF from multiple sources to a Business Document
                                    Skills - Excel, VBA, Data Cleaning, JSON to CSV conversion, Validation metrics against ground truths, REST API, ABAP Regular Expressions		Availing the exposed REST based Machine Learning Service for reading pdf in different used formats.
                                    Major Responsibilities
                                        Availing the exposed REST based Machine Learning Service for reading pdf in different used formats.
                                        Giving feedback on the results in validation metrics through comparing grounds truths with obtained results though excel, visual basic, data cleaning.
                                        Handling pdf from multiple sources like folder though internal tool, email, or UI.
                                        Handling the obtained results through proper transformation of data types and formats so that the returned data is compatible with DB storage.
                                Domain expertise in Supplier Relationship Management
                                    Skills - Requests Creation (Shopping Cart), Contracts, Request for Quotations, Quotes, Purchasing, Goods and Services delivery, Supplier Invoicing and Credit Memo for Payments
                                    Major Responsibilities
                                        Handling business transactions for internal requirements, supply chain management, and supplier contracts.
                                        Handling exceptional scenarios from customers through work arounds, corrections or suggestions.
                                        Creating traceability of the transactions for a business scenario through document flow and cost accounting.
                                Routine User Experience of Cloud Reporting
                                    Skills - Knowledge of the data model
                                    Major Responsibilities
                                        Identification of existing problems across the customers.
                                        Rolling and Drilling down for problem identification.
                                        Grouping customers with similar issues or problems
                                ToDo - Write NSME Experience within this. Start Adding Data Engineering work here.
                        </SAP2017>
                    </ProfessionalRelevantProjects>
                    <PersonalProjects>
                        <CollegeProjects> Only Relevant Ones
                            Deriving Insights from Stack Overflow data survey
                                Visualizations on tableau with different combinations of features.
                                Clustering of related technologies that tend to go together based on users interests.
                                Clustering of users that are very similar to each other in terms of the specified details.
                                Classification  Predicting salary bracket for any set of specified details for a new user.
                                Association Rules  suggesting best country for a given technology toolset.
                            Semantic Web on NoSQL
                                Skills - OWL, MongoDB, Neo4J
                        </CollegeProjects>
                        <IndependentAndOSS>
                            Given a set of Purchase orders suggest and a given item, suggest user with a new item.
                                Proposed usage of association rules with support and confidence evaluation for the same.
                                No ABAP library is available for association rule mining and so implementation of algorithm suggested.
                            Given items with free text description suggest a category - Supervised Learning on the text. 
                                Project Detail - 
                                Role in Project - 
                            Club free text items together based on descriptions to suggest customer to make a product id.
                            CDT at risk.
                            POC Suggested - e-invoicing - multiple xms - 1 xml which one does it belong to. Learn thru tag wordcloud clustering. 
                                Rather than running the xml for each xms one by one as long as match ain't found.
                            given a ticket description, suggest the best user to be able to handle the ticket.
                            Smarter XSearch for tickets - instead of doing free text search - given a ticket, tell what it most resembles with.
                        </IndependentAndOSS>
                    </PersonalProjects>
                    <OtherProjects>
                        <Infosys2010>
                            Systems Engineer
                                SEZ Online, Infosys
                                Hinjewadi, Pune.
                                Total Experience: 2 years 7 months (July 2010-Feb 2013)
                            Contributions
                                Traceability Matrix from Customer Requirements to Implementation
                                Application Testing - Regression Based Testing, System Testing, Test Case Generation.
                                Maintenance  Customer Issues Handling, Process Integration Message Handling.
                        </Infosys2010>
                        <VIT2013>
                            Assistant Professor
                                Vishwakarma Institute of Technology
                                Bibwewadi, Pune.
                                Total Experience: 7 months (June 2013- Dec 2013)
                            Contributions
                                Computer Programming Concepts
                                Guide for Programming Projects
                        </VIT2013>
                    </OtherProjects>
                </DAndK>
                <Details>
                    <TechnicalSkills>
                        <Knowledge>
                            Relevant Courses  Machine Learning (By Andrew NG), Data Analytics, Data Modeling, Design Patterns [, Distributed Computing, Artificial Intelligence]
                            Ongoing Self Study Courses  NLP in Python (Analytics Vidhya), ML in R (Jigsaw Academy)
                        </Knowledge>
                        <HLDRelevant>
                            Data Modeling Representations - SQL, Excel, XML, JSON, CSV, Semantic Web, Object Oriented Databases, NoSQL, Temporal DB, Stream DB, Relational Data warehouse (Star Schema)
                            Frameworks worked on  Hadoop Ecosystem, Many Proprietary Frameworks.
                            Optional - Ability to Scale - Knowledge of Design Patterns, Exits/ Frameworks, Property/ Configuration Files, etc.
                        </HLDRelevant>
                        <LLDRelevant>
                            Libraries worked on - Spacy, Pandas, NLTK, stemmer, etc.
                            Algorithms  Induction based, Divide and Conquer, Greedy, Brute Force, Branch and Bound, Backtracking, Dynamic Programming, Artificial Intelligence, Approximation Algorithms, etc.
                            Optional Advanced Algorithms - Approximation Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence
                            ML Algorithms - classification, clustering, association rules, regression
                        </LLDRelevant>
                        <Environment>
                            Clouds Used - Private Cloud, AWS (EC2, EMR, S3).
                            IDE  RStudio, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook, Spyder, Eclipse for JAVA.
                        </Environment>
                        <ImplementationsAndTechnologies>
                            Hadoop Technologies - HIVE, Spark, Drill, Presto, Ambari REST API.
                            DS specific Languages - R, Python, Octave, Matlab, JAVA for big data.
                            Data Analytics Technologies  Excel, VBA, SQL.
                            Optional Tools - SQL, Excel.
                        </ImplementationsAndTechnologies>
                        <Experiences> Optional
                            Datasets worked on (for experimentations or specific exercises)
                        </Experiences>
                    </TechnicalSkills>
                    <DomainProficiency> like Requirements or Functional Specification but kept separate cuz important but after technical skills
                        ERP Application Areas Familiar With  SRM, SCM, CRM, FIN, HCM.
                        SRM Involvements  Shopping Cart, Contracts, Request for Quotations, Quotes, Purchase Orders, Goods and Services Receipt, Goods Return, Supplier Invoicing, Credit Memo.
                    </DomainProficiency>
                    <ManagementSkills> like Problem Solving before Functional Specifications but important separately but less prior than Technical and Domain.
                        Undergone training on Scrum based software development with day today observations of scrum practices.
                        Good Communication skills with sound experience at interactions with different stakeholders. 
                        Ready to shoulders responsibilities, resourceful with a pro-active approach in accomplishing targets.
                    </ManagementSkills>
                    <AdditionalQualifications>
                        ???
                    </AdditionalQualifications>
                    <PersonalInterests>
                        YouTube Technical Channels, Reading, Sports, trekking, Cooking
                    </PersonalInterests>
                </Details>
            </DataScience>
        </EgoSpecific>
        <Uncat>
            Sume 
                    UI Handling - usage level not framework level
                            UI Discussion with other teams, where some configuration element has to take over. some values are already not coming to inport of OVS.
            Sume JS World
                    react.js - library to create ui components - create html page on client side.
                    angular.js - framework for creating (?single page) web application - MVC (Model and view congruence) -> create routes for views and corresponding controllers - change in controllers refects changes in views and vv.
                    Servlets - is backend creation of html page thru code.
                    JSP - is a backend creation of html page not front end. This also converts to code but looks like html so easier to work with.
                    express.js - server side framework (not library as per lynda) to better manage request and response thru routes, middlewares.
                    vue.js - framework to build fullstack application
                    bootstrap.js - frontend dynamic ready-made ui components to consume (for beautification) - css and js libraries.
                    D3.js - visualizations ?Library
                    tensorflow.js - library for ML.
                    ajax - ?library for contacting server.
                    gulp to start code in default browser.
            Sume - Data visualizations D3, DC, Tableau, Excel.
            Sume DS Scope
                    Analytics, ML Course, R, Python, Excel, SQL, D3/DC, Puzzles, Hadoop. Descriptive Stats (Excel)
                    Curiosity - DL, AI, Maths parts etc.
            Sume - background jobs creation and run.
                    https://stackoverflow.com/questions/7814089/how-to-schedule-a-periodic-task-in-java
                    ScheduledExecutorService, Quartz, TimeTask, AbstractScheduledService.
            Sume
                    OpenCV Intro, 
            Sume - Project Management Views.
                    the view in project OIF is aggregated view of all time recordings.
            Sume - I have worked on following topics in past 4 months.
                    1.	SME Express  Invoicing from PO screen (UI and backend).
                    2.	SME Express  Payment from Invoicing screen (UI and backend).
                    3.	SME Express  bug fixes across process components.
                    4.	S4One  Shopping Cart Action Implementation  submit for approval with confidence determined by ML API, copy items, etc.
                    5.	S4One  Shopping Cart Validations Implementation  currency check, etc.
                    6.	S4One  Shopping Cart Determinations Implementation  Item ID determinations, Item Product determinations, etc.
                    7.	S4One  Test Cases creation and maintenance, etc.
            Sume
                    Tell more than asked - you drive what they will ask - you should drive the interview.
                    I have worked on that. I know this and also that.
                    Insult immune - karni hai karle ek hi baar to milenge if that's the case.
                    Farzi - for practice. Guaranteed you will leave cuz more money. Why not face economics - the fact.
                    Prep <==> Face I/v. the latter is more dependable than former. Any wrong will be one time and won't repeat itself so face it.
            Sume
                    Siemens project - Not a good idea to apply regression on queries but classification of which execution engine is best thru decision tree will be a good idea - this knowledge can be helpful at rule based dispatch to apt execution engine and not apply prediction to find numbers or find execution engine.
            Sume 
                    LinkedIn useful for others - e1 has their accounts so so many results for a request. Primarily for CEO, etc levels.
                    Naukri - means you really need job right now.
            Sume - Tableau
            Sume
                    git website
                    linkedin link
            Sume
                    SAP Role Descriptions (truly - outside of DS role)
                            ERP Product Development for the Application Area of Supplier Relationship Management
                            Support Real Time Analytics (OLAP) for Business Users
                            Maintenance - Debugging and support in resolving customers issues. Using cloud reporting OLAP system to roll up for finding generic issues.
                            Testing - ensure robustness and "no regression" all business scenario - TDD.
                            Support Integration (SOAP, REST, RFC based) across application areas, applications and businesses.
            Sume - JDA Mahatmya
                    JDA Software provides the leading AI-driven supply chain management (SCM) platform.
                    Our end-to-end solutions span supply chain and retail planning, execution, delivery and workforce management.
                    Our mission is to empower companies to better predict, make and deliver exactly what their customers want  when, where and how they want it.
                    We power free-flowing, connected global commerce - without wasted materials, energy, costs or time  to accelerate economic growth, sustainability and prosperity.
                    JDAs delivers a more Autonomous Supply ChainTM for 4,000 of the worlds leading companies 
                            including 75 of the top 100 retailers, 77 of the top 100 consumer goods companies and 8 of the top 10 global 3PLs.
                    Running JDA, you can plan to deliver.
        </Uncat>
    </V>
    <A>
        About - Ashram is about being best Social Consumer.
        <B>
            SocialErp - Services Customer (social interfacing)
                Adventure Management - Plan in terms of resources
                Epic - ?; Backlog - Kerala, ITR.
            HomeErp - Products Customer (base camp grat streaming)
                Epic - ?; Backlog - Chair.
            PersonalErp - Amusements (Me time) 
                Hobbies, Skills, Sports (1 challenges, 2 games, n races).
                Epic - ?; Backlog - Car, Chess.
        </B>
        <J> Talk Capabilities you can take resp for (not just what all I have read)
            Science - physics, chem, bio; maths (Intermediate)
            Sociology - history, politics, Psychology, economics, civics, geography; (Secondary School)
            Home - MBA - Stage Presentation, Group Involvement (SAP Labs BYD, LinkedIn courses)
            Personal - skills and psychology - Singing, Joking, Games, Philosophy (Charisma On Command, Self Help Books)
        </J>
        <D> Challenges and stories and Grats during projects for instances
            Instances - Goa Trip Bike petrol finish story; Heavy rain in Kharagpur story; Left home in yol story;
        </D>
        <K>
            Social Standardizations
                ITR, Banking - Shares, MF, etc.
            <Products>
                FIN - Balance sheet todo.
                    4 bank accounts, debit card renewed.
                ESCM
                    CRM - Guests and Hosts (Networking DMPM Themes - Plans and Stories shared)
                        <Network> People (Visitors, Lead, Prospects and Customers) standardizations and Services
                            Standardize all people (especially yourself) are associated with - in terms of body / health, Senses (likes and favorites), mind (stories and experiences), intel (career; do you know driving, etc - stuffs to be leveraged later sometime), ego (nature).
                            Relatives
                            Nanaji - Postman. Naniji - Home Maker. Dadaji - Chemicals Industry. Dadiji - Home Maker.
                            Mama - Yoga Teacher KV. MA in Languages, etc.
                            Kamal Mausi - Yoga Teacher KV.
                            Mausaji - Army Major then broker business for supplying maids, cooks, etc.
                            Ruhi - Yoga Teacher personal.
                            Sammy Bhaiya - MTV b4.
                            Charu Mausi - Yoga Teacher KV.
                            Mausaji - Engineer. Textile - very vast contacts and spiritual interests. Explores lots of places.
                            Anku
                            Shivam
                            Upinder Mamaji - Yoga Teacher KV. Very funny and endearing.
                            Mamiji - Principal in HP state govt school. Bio Teacher before.
                            Rajan
                            ...
                            Pushkar Mamaji - Vice Principal - Hindi teacher before. Funny and evaluative.
                            Goldie Mamaji - High Court Superintendent in Chandigarh. MA in English.
                            Vandana Mamiji - Home Maker. Very good nature.
                            ...
                            Papa - Ph.D in biophysics. Jammu Medical College research. Chemicals business.
                            Baldev Papaji - Textile before. Then Ravi Bhaiya - Aquaguards?, etc.
                            Ravi Bhaiya, Shakti Bhabhi
                            Aruna didi, ?poonam didi
                            Jugal Kishore Papaji - Pharmacy Chemicals Industry.
                            Kamlesh Rani Chaiji - Home Maker.
                            Sonia didi (?), Mona didi (NIT Jal), Rashmi didi (Medical, ), Rajni didi (Car Sales b4, Works at HDFC Bank)
                            Vikas Vashisht Jiju (?), Vijay Jiju (Works at PHF Leasing Ltd), Riju Jiju (Sales Officer at PATEL AIRFREIGHT, self employed now), Karan Manan (Sales Manager at HDFC Bank Ltd)
                            Mehak, Muskaan, K, Zeeshan, Leeshan,
                            Tilak Chachaji - Colonel in Army.
                            Chachiji - PGT Biology Teacher in KV.
                            Ronny Bhaiya
                            Rini
                            Kunti Buaji
                            Fufaji
                            Rajan Bhaiya
                            Poonam didi
                            Nagpur waale Buaji
                            Fufaji
                            ...
                            ...
                            Surabhi Didi
                            Jiju
                            Rishi, Uncle, Aunty, etc.
                            Adhrit
                            Samant
                            His friends that I know
                            Misc - Vinarani Aunty (Vanita, Vikas Bhaiya, Gorkha Bhaiya)
                            Friends - Devs, School friends, college friends, professor friends, etc.
                            ToDo - Networking everyday and new person a week even thru whatsapp.
                        </Network>
                        uncat
                            ASR Visit.
                            Didi Jiju.
                            Jalandhar Trip.
                            Marriage Leads.
                    SCM Production - Kitchen Cooked Dishes (Foodie life DMPM Themes)
                        Snacks - Dhokla, etc.
                        Made by me - ...
                        <Foods>
                            Breakfast Light
                            Idli, Vada Sambhar
                            Dosa 99 variety, Set Dosa (Uttapam), Pesarattu, Pan Dosa with veg stew, Paneer, Corn Dosa, Matar Dosa, etc
                            Parothas - Variants - Alu, Gobhi, Mooli, Methi, Palak, Pyaaz, Cheeni walla.
                            Particles (Khara Bath (Upma), Seviya, Poha, Daliya),
                            Veg
                            Ghiya - Ghiya vadi, Daal Ghiya.
                            Bhindi - bharva bhindi, bhindi onion.
                            Bengan - bharta, alu baingan, cutlet, bharvan baingan
                            Shalgam
                            Palak,
                            Chilli Potato
                            Mix Veg, Sukhe Chane, Alu Sabji, Tondli, Patta Gobhi,
                            Veg Gravy
                            Shimla Mirch Alu, Manchurian,
                            Pulses
                            Kabuli Choole, Moong Dal, Rajmah, Kaali Chane, Masar Daal, Chane ki daal, Paalak Soppu,
                            Fruits and Juices
                            Sapota, Banana, Orange, Mango, Apples, Grapes, Pomegranates, Guava,
                            Group Fruits - Water Melon, Papaya, Kharbuja, Seetaphal,
                            Breads
                            Chapatti - Tava Roti, Fulka, Tandoori Roti, Parotha, Rumali, Missi, Naan, Kulcha (Garlic, Butter, normal); Kerela Akki Roti, Dosa
                            Rice - Lemon Rice, Coconut Rice, Masala Rice (Poliogare Rice), Biryani (spicy rice with veg), Pulao (sada rice with veg), Khicadi (Bisibele Bath)
                            Snacks / Fried/ Atram Patram / Meeting delights - Samosa, Pakoda (Bread, Paneer, Gobi, Mirchi, etc), Burger, Momos,
                            Rolls - Caliphornia Burrito, Kathi Roll (home rolls)
                            Sandwich - Paneer, Bhurji, Veg, Palak, multi-layered veg sandwich, etc
                            Pizza - Pizza on Papad,
                            Lasagne, Spaghetti
                            French Fries
                            Chinese - Chowmein, Manchurian, Spring Roll
                            Maharashtra - Paav Bhaji, Misal Paav, Vada Paav, Dhabeli,
                            Sweets - Gulab Jamun, Rasagulla, Barfi (Dodda, Milk cake, Normal, Kaju), Choori Kutti, Laddus (Motichoor, Besan, etc), Halva, Kheer
                            Icecream, Rasamali, Rabdi, Seviya (with or w/o milk), Custard
                        </Foods>
                    SCM Logistics - Home DMPM Themes - Home Decor. Cleaning.
                        Kitchen
                            Chimney, etc.
                        Bedroom - Queen size bed, Memory mattress 1 gadda, 2 full length chadars, 2 small chadars, 2 kambals.
                            Store - 2 attache.
                            3 wardrobe.
                            Room Heater.
                        balcony - ropes, clips, plants.
                    SRM - Shopping Experiences.
                        About
                            XRoutine To Stock, Assets Stocks,
                            What was bought from where. Logs of experiences.
                        Punjab - Amritsar, etc.
                        JnK - Udhampur, Jammu, Katra, Gulmarg.
                        Jharkhand - Tata Nagar, etc.
                        Maharashtra - Mumbai, Pune - Shanivar Peeth.
                        Karnataka - Mysore, Bangalore (nandi hills, wonderla, gardens, bannerghatta), Coorg, Goa, Mahabalipuram.
                HCM - Happy Family Members (life events, entertainments, etc)
                    Life Events - new year, birthday, anniversary, party, etc.
                    Eating - Ghoomar at Amritsar, Haveli experiences, Brothers dhaba.
                        Ice creams, etc.
                    Gediyan - going to malls, visiting places.
                    <TV>
                        Books -
                        Music - songs.
                            Singers, time, feeling (love, motivation, etc)
                            Pop, Evergreen, personal favorites, Nostalgia, Remix.
                        Movies
                            Comedy -
                            Scary -
                            knowledge -
                            documentary -
                            Spirituality or History - Mahabharat, Ramayan, Chanakya, Chandragupt Maurya, Pradhanmantri.
                        Sports - Challenges, Games.
                    </TV>
            </Products>
            <Hobbies> Sports and Movies
                <Amusement>
                    Outdoors - Basketball, Badminton, Table Tennis, Cricket, Handball, Football, Lawn Tennis. Hockey - name sake. Golf in SAP.
                    Foosball, footsall, billiards, carrom, Chess, etc.
                    Lawn Tennis, Vollyball, Bowling with colleagues and with roommate once.
                    Uncat - swimming, Uno, Cards, etc.
                </Amusement>
                <GamePlay></GamePlay>
                <Sing></Sing>
                <MusicInstruments>
                    Mridanga, Cymbals, Keyboard, Guitar, 
                </MusicInstruments>
                <Dance>
                    Bhangra 3 moves, Bollywood Free style, Shuffle Dance (2 moves), Zumba (random 2-3 moves)
                </Dance>
                <Books>
                    Salted bread, Harry Potter
                    Subtle art of not giving a f*ck, Everything is f*cked, Speed reading. 101 ways to make every second count.
                    The monk who sold his ferrari, Awaken the giant within, Who stole my cheese. 1 minute manager.
                    7 habits of highly effective people.
                    ToDo - Think and Grow Rich.
                    Future - rich dad, poor dad, think and grow rich, how to win friends and influence people.
                </Books>
                <Acting>
                    Bina PK, Narsiimha Drama, Balramji, Sphurti Friends, CDS at NIT JSR, KV Fillers demands.
                </Acting>
            </Hobbies>
        </K>
        <EgoSpecific>
            About and Future Plans
                //Jolly and Scientist - ego cultivation desires indpendent of spiritual pursuits
                ego in EQ is mixture of a lot of things - it is width exploration and not depth - ego targetted can be seen as overall culture of mind - the feel that it elicits.
                think of including discussions also (kinda discussions participated in) eg WW, Modi Govt Performance, etc.
            Objective
            B and J
                Educational Qualifications
                    Communication
                        School - Vocab, Grammar, Poetry in Hindi
                        SSC, HSC - Personal and Interpersonal skills, Grammar, Contextualizing etc
                        NITJ - Phonetics, Vocab
                        Infy - Speak Up, Telephone Conversation
                        SAP - 
                            Take a More Creative Approach to Problem-Solving
                            Bystander Training: From Bystander to Upstander
                            How to Manage Your Manager
                            Improving Your Thinking
                            The Mindful Workday
                            Time Management: Working from Home
                    Social and Science - SSC and HSC respectively.
                        Online Content - dedicated channel - Interviews, comedy, songs, poetry, etc
                Skills
                    Communications - 
                        Languages - English, Hindi, Sanskrit (Vocab + Grammar), Body Language (NITJ), Voice Tone (matters 2nd to BL)
                            Figures of speech, idioms, proverbs, adage, etc.
                        Arts -
                            Personal abilities - Notes making, summary making, fast reading, grammar correction (School), phonetics (NITJ)
                            Abilities wrt people - Ads/ Pamphlet or brochure writing, essay/ report writing (School)
                            Unicast - CV / Interview (NITJ), Telephone conversation (Infy), email etiquettes (IIITB), Speak Up (Infy)
                            Multicast - Stage or public Presentation (ISKCON)
                    Social Studies - Civics (wrt Natural Conditions), Economics, History.
                    Science - Physics (astro, geo included), Chemistry, Biology
                Case Studies and Projects
            D and K
                Professional Relevant Projects
                    Amritsar
                        Places - Golden Temple, Durgyana Temple, Valmiki Ashram, War memorial, Jaliyawala Bagh
                            Chandigarh - Rock Garden, Pinjore Garden; NIT Jalandhar, 
                        Food - Kesar Dhaba, Bhrava da Dhaba, Kulche Chhole, Chhole Bhature, Lassi, etc.
                        Activities (wrt to city or without) or experiences - Gym, Suncity, School Kabaddi, School competitions, etc.
                            Stage presentations - in school for declamation, poetry, fancy dress, etc.
                                declamation, story telling;
                            Poetry - in school, on topics ranging motivation, morality and natural experiences.
                            Specially invited to senior class to sing payo ji maine naam ratan dhan payo.
                            dancing in festivals - marriage occasions, ability to accompany - home festival of dd shadi, Palace hall.
                        Purchases - Cable, etc.
                    Udhampur
                        Places - Kargil Park, Chinar / Dhruva Complex, ISKCON, Vaishno Devi Temple, Patnitop, Gulmarg, J & K tour, etc.
                        Food - Dum Alu, Shehtoot everywhere (white, purple, black), amrood from trees, katcha Papita Sabji.
                        Experiences - Naala, Army Campus, Campus experience, 90% claim successful, training sounds, chill cold, weather, etc.
                            Acting in school
                            Singing in front of crowd
                        Purchases - TV, etc.
                    Jamshedpur
                        Places - ?Dimna Lake, ?Jubilee Park, ?XLRI, Bistupur, TELCO, TESCO, Sakchi
                            Mayapur, Jagannath Puri, Remuna Kshir Chor Gopinath's khir.
                        Food - Bengali Impact
                        Experiences - Gaudiya Math in Sakchi
                            Devotee's hospital experience twice, etc.
                            college VOICE drama, member of CDS - Balaram Lila in JPV, Role of Ravan, Narad Muni, etc.
                            Singing Bhajans and Kirtans, etc.
                    Mysore
                        Places - Mysore Palace, Brindavan Gardens, Chamundeshwari Temple, Sand Art, Dushhehra Celebrations, etc.
                        Food - Food Courts in Infy
                        Purchases - Hearing device, ISKCON Mysore Ritvik
                    Pune
                        Places - ISKCON Katraj, Shanivarvada, Dehu (camps and for IAS exam), Pandharpur, Lonavala weather, Sarvateerth Taaked (Jatayu place), Nashik (Panchvati - BGP camp).
                            Bhopal, Indore, Mumbai visits - SP Stay, Gulbarg
                            Vrindavan, Mayapur, Jagannath Puri, Hampi, Udupi.
                        Food - Misal Paav, Paav Bhaji, Vada Paav, Kachhi Dhabeli, etc
                        Experiences
                            Bina PK Drama participant, Narsimha Drama dialogs, choreography, acting, etc.
                            Temple Dance, etc.
                    Bangalore
                        Places - Wonderla, Art of Living, ISKCON, Bangalore Palace costly ticket, Cubbon Park, Lal Bagh, MG Road, Bannerghatta, Phoenix Mall
                            Nandi Hills, Coorg, Goa, etc
                            Wonderla with college friends - water sports, high rides
                            ?Trek, intercity bike ride, 
                            Coorg - Abbey Waterfall and Raja's Seat Sunpoint; Madikeri; Omkareshwar Temple
                            Goa - Drive adventures, beaches
                            Shivan Samudhram - water fall, 
                            Sri Ranga Pattna, Devarayan Durga, Melekote, Madhva/Ramanuja places
                        Food - South Indian Meals
                        Purchases - Fridge, Mattress, Bed, TV, Smartphone, etc.
                            Pillow, Sports equipments, 
                            Online Streaming - YT, Amazon Prime, Netflix, Jio, Hotstar, etc.
                        Experience - ITR, Company Coupons, RSA Card, etc.
                            Siemens outbound sports - climb then free fall, mountaineering, xorbing, rope slide.
                            SAP
                                Inside resorts for sports, adventures
                                Team Lunch, Team movie (Deadpool), Team bachelor parties
                            Horror House near Wonderla - who initiated, my response to fear was punch the diaroma, etc.
                            Health Check up, etc.
                            Singing in temples - VOICE, Bangalore Seshadripuram temple Janmashtami and Sunday Kirtans.
                            Cinema - 3D Avengers Infinity War, 4D Avengers End Game2, 
                            Mall - Fish Spa, Body Spa or massage (oil, machine), Simulated Virtual Reality (Dragon on tracks, Scare on tracks, swinging with 3D views)
                            Barber - head massage, face wash,
                            YT Channel and Playlist formalization especially Music.
                    More - 
                    Uncat
                        Purchases 
                            Regular - toothpaste with Fluoride, soap alkeline and removes oil, vs go ark, etc
                        Entertainment
                            Movies
                                Bollywood - Anand, 
                                Hollywood - Shawshank Redemption
                            TV Series - GOT, Breaking Bad, etc
                            Comedy - Kapil Sharma, Bachao, etc.
                            Music
                                Old
                                New
                                Remix
                Personal Projects
                    Invented many games and challenges at home, udhampur for fun - tt on normal bench, basketball into havan kund, 
                        carrom board new games and upside down with spoon, chess hits, etc.
                        from inside room to parchhatti without touching the ground.
                        Jumping from roof to ground, badminton between 2 terraces.
            Details
                Technical Skills
                Domain Skills
                Management Skills
                Additional Qualifications
                Personal Interests
        </EgoSpecific>
    </A>
    <F>
        About - Personal Health (for best resources to be at their best) - sharpening the saw.
            Includes Everything MINUS (Spirituality + Social Production + Social Consumption) = Science + Abstract PIES.
            Layered Health
                Eg - Personal health of different layers (Gym, Video Games, puzzles, sports, etc), Study of PIES.
                Fit@SAP Challenge
            General Abstract Learnings (PIES) - May also involve social interactions but grat is not in its consumption but very pronounced in what it makes you.
                The abstract BJDK doesn't fall under any specific layer.
                Eg - Self Help Books, Motivations, Affirmations.
        Objective
            Health of different layers of existence and their Stability (MOG) is primary concern here.
        B and J
            Educational Qualifications
                School - PT, Yoga
                Family - Yoga
                Swami Ramdev TV and Online Videos - Yoga
                Spiritual Atmosphere in Udhampur - Peer Baba, 1 temple multiple religion deities - helped recover from depression, Campus temple programs/ yajna
                ISKCON - Mental and intellectual stability thru principles
                Amritsar Gym under trainer, College Gym under trainer, Siemens Gym
                Online - titbits but no course, talks from sadhguru, on Kundalini, from robin sharma, sandeep maheshwari, Tony Robbins, etc
                Motivational Talks during work outs; Affirmations before sleep
            Skills
                Badminton (with national champions), Basketball, Cricket, Football, Table Tennis
            Case Studies and Projects
        D and K
            Projects
                Amritsar
                    Healthy Diet - Ghee, Lassi, Milk, etc.
                    Gym under trainer
                Jamshedpur - Yoga and asanas every day.
                Pune
                    Runs in nearby Technical Park, Runs to-fro in the lane next to VOICE.
                    Yoga Everyday.
                    Preaching Projects for intellectual health.
                Bangalore
                    Svadhyay - very rewarding in terms of getting to the heart of things; Discussion walks with spiritually inclined.
                    Morning runs alone, Evening runs with friends (discussion and exercise), Siemens Gym, etc
                    Puzzle Solving (for DS interviews)
                    Morning Runs in Society Campus, Yoga in morning formality, Saturdays reserved for full length yoga.
                Accolades
                    School Kabaddi when I got whole team out and survived
                    Basketball - Gold in ByD
                    Panja won with SCM team member giving overall win to SRM team.
            Personal Projects
                College
                OSS or Independent
            Other Projects
        Details
            Technical Skills
            Domain Skills
            Management Skills
            Additional Qualifications
            Personal Interests
    </F>
</PIES>