<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SVAFConfig>
	About - How can I maximize my service at social (conditioned spiritual) and spiritual layers (constitutional spiritual)
		This is intended to standardize the standard practices to ensure my attainment of highest goal at higher layers of existence.
	<S>
		Begin with the end result in the mind thru the neutral network layers or stages of bhakti.
		Following sequence is not BY, JY, DY, KY but faculties or features or aspects.
		B - Proof of devotion. Associations (Sadhu sang), Devotion of TME.
		J - Shravanam and Mananam. see things as it is. Ashtanga preparation phase. All Courses done in BJDK Yoga and applied.
		D - Nididhyasanam (application API bits) or Bhajan Kriya or Dharana Dhyan (framework) - Active application of dhyan frameworks in BJDK Yoga.
			ensure framework consumes all application bits from J.
			Ashtanga Yoga discipline which would include Mantra meditation
			All before stages make it powerful and most rewarding.
		K - VA for aligned life with experienced realizations and oneness. Lifestyle and achievements measurements over time.
			Seva (Or pracar) - Sharing with world to give opportunity of evolution to e1.
		Perfection - Prema, Samadhi, Sakshatkar, Moksha.
			Perfection into Samadhi - oneness with the object of meditation. Sakshatkar - realization. Prema - love. Moksha - freedom or liberation.
	</S>
	<V>
		About - Begin with the end in mind. Arch phase. Then leader phase.
			Spending time with oneself discussion honest architecture.
		JIRA Onenote notebook
		2 hr slot standardization
		Daily Deliverable
		Weekly presentable.
		Aggregation into sume.
	</V>
	<A>
	PIES - Ashram serving grats thru 12 rasas (EQ only concerns with person vs SVAF with socially serving)
		Defined as follows
			NIC - Relationships (primary 4 rasas); Arts (Secondary rasas); Drama (Secondary rasas2)
			Priority - NIC Rasas X {Personal, Home, Social} X {Present, Past, Future}.
			Future story based on past narrative.
			All of this is super awesome but na utpadayet yadi ratim shram eva hi kevalam.
				So, do all the following with intent to serve them and inspire them align better with universal or spiritual principles.
		Viz Flow of thought as follows
			About - PPF means past present future.
			Talk about person's relationships with oneself (spiritual, body, mind health). PPF
				Eg - how is everything; How are you doing.
				Home work - Aware of health aspects of people and status.
			Talk about person's beauty wrt duties / activities (scale or quality) PPF
				Eg - What's going on with your gardening hobby.
				Home work - know hobbies or achievements of people and status.
			Talk about person's drama life. PPF.
				Eg - that must have caused lots of troubles, right. You solved that very well. He was the savior.
				Home work - elicit stories - ability to explore people's heroes, enemies, friends. Stories and Status.
			Talk about family relationships or ishta goshti enquiries. PPF.
				Eg - Hey how's your brother or friend doing.
				Home work - Who does dishes at your home?
			Talk about family's art beauty. Family Projects. PPF.
				Eg - We recently did the project of fiber installation - how awesome it was.
				Home work - List the family projects and status.
			Talk about family drama - politics, motions, etc.
				Eg - She does not like this. You know he will not let this go on.
				Home work - Recall our family together stories.
			Talk about social relationships.
				Eg - Our PM has ensured that e1 will get vaccinated shortly.
				Eg - citizens use platforms to convey their wants.
				Eg - I have done some donation for downtrodden's meals program.
				Home work - Official national or govt channels. Study of civics and political system official narrative.
					Economics micro (biz) and macro status.
			Talk about social arts.
				Eg - Did you see the dance performance of Hritik Roshan. MI has even more action than before.
				Eg - This new iphone has more features than before.
				Home work - List all fields in primary, secondary, tertiary sectors of economics. And standout political or civil achievements.
			Talk about social drama.
				Eg - You see they are opposing the motion cuz they want political mileage outta this.
				Eg - people of the country won't accept this new norm.
				Eg - Monsoon will be a little late this year.
				Home work - Private news fuss. catch up with political and business changes masala. Who's rising and falling.
	</A>
	<F>
		ABCD gotta be done in following sequence. AD / BC - 2 divisions of time as per international time system.
		A - Attitude And Aptitude - Prepare resources for best performance - qualities, health.
			ESMD ideal levels. SMIES best health. Spiritual health in terms of character ethics (or attitude).
		D - Devotion - Drilled down Scrum plan.
		B - Behavior - candidate sets of right sequence of actions which will deliver the scrum goal to you.
		C - Communication - Given a desired outcome from an interaction - how to use your body language, vocal and content resources aptly to arrive at a win win proposition.
	</F>
</SVAFConfig>