<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Bridge>
    About - For all phases, there is a bridge course to get familiar, intermediate course to connect or relate with vedic wisdom and core courses later.
        Eg - Personal Development for corporates followed by EBG for direct BG experience and then Bhakti shastri.
        Eg - SS for Youth followed by SMY and then to Bhakti Shastri. Of course, they eventually go to latter phases and so can be covered.
        Eg - Cultural presentation of temple visits, festival visits, grihastha home visits, etc are bridges; Cultural systematic presentations are interim and Bhakti shatri as core.
        There are professionals of every field - the idea is not be become a professional but have enough understanding for yourself and extending necessary help to others.
            Idea of KC is not become professional of eth or amateur and many things but engage as per interest for specialization and also consume all services for better spiritual life
            there will be many free services and many paid ones. Free services because soft corner for nishkaam seva or yoga yukta karma.
            REL - marriage NS camps can also be seen as a psychological expertise. We take what's necessary and serve.
                Spiritual science is full time job for intelligent design, Bhaktivedant academy, etc. But we take what's necessary and share.
                One time seminars is full time jobs for self help service providers (aaroh and avaroh) - but take what's helpful and share is what we do.
        This is important front of spirituality dealing with Shastra chakshu on real life - applications, analysing world, etc
            and is also lots of fun to see spirituality applied in the world or world seen in spiritual light.
            This doc focuses on only the avaroh aspects of applications and aaroh aspects are excluded though very important - eg - self help books.
    <PrahladSchool>
        About
            SummerSchool with arts and shloka recitation and camps.
            Only interested in its syllabus nothing more.
    </PrahladSchool>
    <SMY>
        About - Connect youth with bridging science to spirituality
            SS is the bridge and SMY is the intermediate.
        DYS - Journey of self discovery
            Can A Scientist Believe In GOD?
            Getting the Eyes to See God
            Vedic Wisdom: The Privilege of Humanity
            Science of Soul
            Substance and Shadow
            If God is one, then why so many religions?
            Appendix 1: Evolution or Creation: Let the Data Speak
            Appendix 2: The Universe: How did it Begin
        YBF - God detailed understanding
            Introduction
            Definition of God
            Vedas - Are they Relevant Today
                Only Source of Perfect Knowledge
                    How can we gain knowledge about him - 3 ways to acquiring knowledge.
                    Shabda is hearing from Vedic authorities since dawn of creation.
                    No Changes - Not revised (amendments), modified (change of opinions), updated - it's always perfect
                Faith in Vedas
                    Parallels with Modern Science (while no instruments existed)
                        Cloning of Kauravas - Dr B G Matapurkar
                            Churning of Vena to make Pruthu
                        Vimana Shastra, Brahmastra,
                        Kakudumi's experience of relativity of time.
                        Speed of Light, Mathematics, etc
                        Ontogeny, Living Entities are ew (fire bacteria), Plants have feelings, Cow dung is pure (antiseptic in 1940)
                    Vedic Predictions that have come true
                        Buddha, Chanakya, Chaitanya Mahaprabhu, Chandragupta/ Ashoka, Jesus and Mohammed.
                        Predictions about Kali Yuga
                            Food sold in public (vs charity), flesh of foetus, sex based relp (not sacred duty to inc service; livin'; court based)
                            Might will be right (wealth and brute force); Lavanya kesh dharanam; Brahmana by thread he wears (not qualities)
                    => Coming from person knowing past, present, future and all knowing.
                Seeing with ears
                    @Save from thief broke in.
                    Glass of Liquid - determine!
                        Chemical Tests - only medicine left finished in testing, mixture of 2.
                        ask the person who handed the jar.
                    Hearing is basis of life form cradle to crematorium
                        backtrack every knowledge - GRE, ABC, movie theater nearby, Einstein, Books are recorded sound.
                        born in ignorance - educational set up to gain more awareness to improve our life.
                    Questionability and Authentication
                        Authority of info - TV, news, magazines, journals - overflooded with questionable info
                vs Science
                    Real Mother vs Treacherous Witch (putana)
                Why
                    Relevance Today
                    Manual for Life
            Qualification of Guru
            Qualification of Disciple
            The Most Confidential Knowledge
            Krishna - The All Attractive
            Evidences for Krishna’s Supremacy
            The Singular Supreme and the Plural Subordinates
            The Controller of all Controllers
            Worship: Divine and Mundane
            Your Heart - To - Heart Friend
            Well Wishing Guide Who Always Accompanies You
            The Infinitesimal and The Infinite
            Love of God: The Culmination of Religion
            Appendix 1: Krishna’s Rasa Dance: Can We Imitate ?
            Appendix 2: Avatars : Genuine and Fake
            Appendix 3: The Position of Lord Shiva
            Appendix 4: The Golden Incarnation For The Iron Age
            Appendix 5: Meditation for the Modern Age
        YSJ - Purely materialistic explanations to alternatives
            Your Divine Identity- A Product of Chemicals
            Your Glorious Ancestors – A Pack of Apes?
            Your Cherished Emotions- A Biophysical Brain Function
            Where Reincarnation and Science Intersects
            You Never Die- The Verdict of All Religions
            Your Lost Home – The Kingdom of God
            Material Nature – A Temporary Prison House
            Your Secret Journey- Evolving Towards Perfection
            The Secret of Action – From Illusion to Reality
            Cloning – A Modern Miracle or An Ancient Method
        VOD - Transcend BODD cycle.
            Your Thoughts Create Your Next Body
            Break Free of Bonds
            The Quest for Happiness
            Becoming A Civilised Human Being
            Different Types Of Yoga
            Do All Paths Lead To The Same Goal?
            Art Of Living
            Cultivating Remembrance Of Krishna
            Art Of Dying
            Passing The Final Exam
        <MindMap>
            Abhidheya
                Qualifications of Guru
                Qualifications of Disciple
                Scriptures
                    The Most Confidential Knowledge (Vedas)
                        Vedas
                            Vedas - Are They Relevant Today
                            Vedic Wisdom: The Privilege of Humanity (DYS 3)
                            Cloning – A Modern Miracle or An Ancient Method
                    Religions - If God is one, then why so many religions? (DYS 6)
                Yoga
                    Different Types Of Yoga
                    Do All Paths Lead To The Same Goal?
                    9 Proc - Cultivating Remembrance Of Krishna
            God
                Definition of God
                Demigods
                    The Singular Supreme and The Plural Subordinates
                    The Controller of all Controllers
                    Worship: Divine and Mundane
                Jiva (mayavad)
                    The Infinitesimal and The Infinite
                Bhagavan
                    Krishna – The All Attractive
                    Evidences for Krishna’s Supremacy
                    Love of God – The Culmination of All Religion
                    Appendix
                        Krishna’s Rasa Dance: Can We Imitate
                        Avatars : Genuine and Fake
                        The Position of Lord Shiva
                        The Golden Incarnation  For The Iron Age
                        Meditation for the Modern Age
                    Your Lost Home – The Kingdom of God (can be thought of as prayojan as well)
                Paramatma
                    Your Heart – to – Heart Friend
                    Well Wishing Guide Who Always Accompanies You
            Jiva
                Can A Scientist Believe In GOD?
                Science of the soul (DYS 4)
                Getting The Eyes To See GOD (DYS 2)
                Where Reincarnation and Science Intersects
                You Never Die- The Verdict of All Religions
                Your Secret Journey- Evolving Towards Perfection
                Your Thoughts Create Your Next Body
                The Quest for Happiness
                Becoming A Civilised Human Being
                Art Of Living
                Art Of Dying
                Passing The Final Exam
            Prakriti
                Substance And Shadow
                Origin and Purpose
                Origin
                    The Universe: How did it Begin?
                    Your Divine Identity- A Product of Chemicals
                    Evolution Or Creation: Let the Data Speak
                    Your Glorious Ancestors – A Pack of Apes?
                Material Nature – A Temporary Prison House
                The Secret of Action –From Illusion to Reality
                Break Free of Bonds
        </MindMap>
        <More>
            Faith and Doubts
            Different Camps
                Utkarsh - DYS 5 and 6.
                Sankalpa
                    Faith and Doubt Sessions
                Sphurti
                    Me and Mind
                Nishtha
                    9 stages of bhakti
                Ashray
                    Diksha and Ashrams of life
        </More>
    </SMY>
    <GirlsVoice>None of my business</GirlsVoice>
    <EBG>
        About - Applications of BG with focus on corporate life.
            Busy life and they don't care whether science bridges to spirituality as much they value its applications.
            Although very spiritual centric - this can be thought of assisting Varna in KC.
            For corporates, Personal Development is the Bridge course and EBG is the intermediate course.
        SpiritualScientist
        PositiveThinker
            Identifying the Divine Guide
            The Spirit of Bhagavad Gita
            Qualifications of an Idea Disciple
            Reincarnation - Fact or Fiction
            Evolving Towards Perfection
        SelfManager
            Peace Formula
            Who should be the Object of My Worship
            God and gods
            Is God Personal or Impersonal
            The Art of Self Management
        ProactiveLeader
            The Three Ropes That Bind Us
            Surpassing Maya
            Our Lost Home - Kingdom of God
            Karma - The Law of InFallible Justice
        PersonalityDevelopment
    </EBG>
    <Applications>
        About - Personal applications of BG or vedic literatures OR its lifestyles.
        Ref: Prerana, TSS, Youth Encyclopedia, One Time Programs.
        <Varna>
            Lack of passion cuz easily satisfied - nothing happens without determination.
                Eg - SP passionate about spread. Firm stands and All personal qualities but motivation inside
                as far as motivating others - integrity, etc inspires others. So leaders they trust. Not easily busted with setbacks.
                Inspiring others or managing others by hearts vs by hands or heads. They become your representatives.
                Business or job - competition not snub others but decisions for growth within - why fall others - grow oneself - making enemies bad for business.
                Never cheat ur customers and they get trust. Crushing other is a short cut not worth taking
                    Mafatlal's father used to say reputation building takes years and breaking takes 1 day.
                    Taking loan and banker knows it will be paid back and we did.
                Not easily shattered on failures - seeing objectively what went wrong.
        </Varna>
        <Ashram>
            Center of attraction is transcendental means no intersection.
            From me to we - tolerance increased, purpose is evolution. Please God thru it - don't hate instrument
            Personal qualities are attractive and can withstand.
			Lecture - Languages of Love
			Grihastha Ashram Manual (from Radha Gopinath Mandir)
        </Ashram>
        <Personal>
            <Fearlessness></Fearlessness>
            <Love></Love>
            <SpiritualLustGreed></SpiritualLustGreed>
            <Tech></Tech>
            <Illusions></Illusions>
            <Engg></Engg>
            <EastMeetsWest></EastMeetsWest>
            <TitanicLessons></TitanicLessons>
            <CharacterWithCareer></CharacterWithCareer>
            <DoTheBestLeaveTheRest></DoTheBestLeaveTheRest>
            <LifeBalance></LifeBalance>
            <FromFearToHope></FromFearToHope>
            <TakeABreak></TakeABreak>
            <UTurn></UTurn>
            <ConflictManagement></ConflictManagement>
            <SeekerWithinAchieverWithout></SeekerWithinAchieverWithout>
            <TitForTatORTolerateThat></TitForTatORTolerateThat>
        </Personal>
		<Preaching>
			Facilitator Empowerment Course
				SP Vision for Devotee Care
				Vision and mood required of a facilitator to care for others
				How should a a facilitator care for those in his guidance by HH RNSM
				Putting the horse b4 the cart
				Taking shelter of hari guru and vaishnava
				Facilitator as a caregiver, rather than as an authority
				Ideal Vaishnava behavior of a facilitator
				Group Presentation - Qualifications and Responsibilities of a Facilitator
			How to read and make notes effectively
				Knowledge
				Understanding
				Personal Application
				Preaching Application
				Faith and Conviction
				Authority
				Theological Application
				Evaluation
				Mood and Mission
				Academic and Moral Integrity
				Responsibility for Learning
				Sastra Cakshus or realizations
			Become Deep By Sacinandana Swami M
			Presentation Feedbacks
				Avoid Unwanted use of humor
				Good Eye contact
				Avoid fillers like "You know"
				Good use of stage space.
				Invite Participation
				Good Voice variations
			Others - Infy
				Personal Brand Identity
				Personal Effectiveness
				Business English Course
		</Preaching>
    </Applications>
    <KCCulture>
        About - Intended for congregation. They want a culture and relevant guidance for a happy life. Expect a detailed ashram study.
            Think all the GS and NS camps.
        <Lifestyle>
        GS - Detachment inducing Talks - focus on temporary nature and Harsh truths - self centered-ness of eb vs spiritual paradigm, etc.
            Syllabus can jotted down but nothing more is intended to be done here.
            There is a possibility of jotting generic etiquette and culture here - which is general - cuz grihasthashram spawns from this phase.
			Vaishnava Training and Education Manual
			VTW Course
        </Lifestyle>
        <GrihasthaCulture>
        NS - Refer my google drive (nitjsr and vitpune shared) for content.
            <B2G>
                ...
            </B2G>
            <Attitude>
                About - Introduction (attitudes and mind map)
                TODO
                    Detox; Grihasthas vs Grihamedhi; ?Vedic View - Boat.
                    attitudes to VA and relp
                    Maturity
                Misc
                    Sanctity - dharma patni - dharma dvara vivahit.
                    Ashram is sadhan. Means shelter or complete effort.
                    envt for mood and do at best. Bhakti not at theater. Bath in kitchen, dining in bathroom.
                    No thanks or sorry - for granted, apna hi hai na but still an individual.
                    not prove duhkhalayam but offer sukh. World lacks good eg. First class philosophy but bad eg ppl put off.
                    Harmonious relp - lack of peace, children disservice. Cold war. Affects every aspect of life - can't focus on work.
                        Health affected,
                        shadi kyun karen - forget leave after shadi; first gotta tell do marriage.
                        no sanctity ppl think - some are still happy - daivi VA - God centered.
                        divorce and stress greater if not religious centered bond.
                        loving, respect, accepting as it is, accommodating, setting right eg for children, clean life.
                        altar at home. Protection so marriage for ladies - distractions at certain age so why window shopping.
                        not married ppl take to mean still available.
                Sankirtan Rasa Prabhu - Grihasta Ashram Seminar - Preparation for Perfect Grihasta Ashram by Sankirtanras Prabhu
                    Principles can't be broken
                        @warship captain - warning lighthouse to tilt else hit - captain asks lighthouse to shift.
                        principles you hit - no prob to them - we get affected.
                        seeing each other at marriage and not even name and face - gotta realize soul - eternal timespan and adjust for 60 yrs.
                        stabbing pain - surgeon paid - benefits. sue for other.
                        changing job cuz other's plate vs I have eth but lesser.
                    Svadharma important
                        I could have come 10 yrs b4 then brahmacari - blissful, recreation and creation.
                            better ur svadharma improperly than other's.
                        fire has smoke - every effort has some fault. Digestion and fire kills microbes but must be done.
                        Jiva thinks doer but MMN - fix faults on 7's head or ourselves - it's MMN.
                            being sad and make others happy - can't go on.
                            Hindi - meri padhai ho gayi. I finished studies. I am responsible for studies.
                            I must be small for grihasthashram.
                    Kali yuga qualities - always disturbed, etc. Quarrelsome. Lazy.
                        Vangbhatt lived for 137 and died cuz of fasting - 2mro work > today. We like lesser work 2mro.
                        don't blame person but kali but not misuse - kali so why satisfied with just you.
                        just see a person for a minute and he would say kya hai be.
                        Boiling - Milk, pot, fire - effect, reason, cause.
                            not by heart - pot is means or nimitta. fire is karma. we forget we are soul so when what wrong - who knows.
                    we break all laws of ashrams. old age and hospital is modern narka.
                        current situ - a-brahmacharya, teen age mothers, live in relationships, single parents, division of elderly, lonely oldage.
                        single parent caused by divorce also.
                        divisions of labor for parents like baghban.
                        Rights and responsibilities - shrink and grow resp with age or ashram.
                        piss in childhood no problem. Cry 7 comes; cleaning our shit.
                        urinary incontinence of old - chastised.
                        oldies more respect if do something social - only TV then nothing.
                        n-1 rights - you take care of e1's rights except ur own and your will be taken care by n-1.
                    Steps in social development of the person
                        brahmacarya - vyaktigat - personal.
                            Personal devp - as a person - not personality as showing what I am not but characteristics development or as a person - tolarance, humility, etc.
                        Grihastha - samashtigat - interpersonal.
                            Interpersonal - with max ppl and also with wife.
                        Vanaprastha - Srishtigat - Universal.
                            Universal - can think of cleaning colony. Grihastha can't think of not using plastic.
                        Sanyas - Parameshtigat - Spiritual.
                    Paths of developments
                        Brahmacarya - Tapasya - austerities.
                            austerities as student then better performance.
                        Grihastha - Santulan - Balance.
                            balance of office and work; kids and wife, etc.
                        Vanaprastha - Seva - service.
                            respect if service centered.
                        Sanyas - Samarpan - Surrender.
                    MB - worship mother, father, fire, guru, soul stays happy in this world and next.
                        shreyas or preyas but simultaneous is rare.
                    Purpose of human life
                        Freedom from sins
                        Enquiry about self
                        Freedom from karma
                        freedom from 3 debts
                        moksh (freedom from BODD cycle)
                        Love Krishna
                    Grihasthashram Definition thru etymology
                        Home vs building - griha vs vastu - relationships vs flats. That's how we start.
                            Griha - Ghar - home and not just mere building.
                        Stha - sthita - staying in or resident of.
                        Ashram - Ashray or aa + shram.
                            for protection, for executing responsibilities.
                        Defn - It is a system that helps human being to evolve to the ultimate goal of human life by satisfying all 3 debts
                            and by following all 4 purusharth under protection of family and society.
                    Glories of Grihasthashram - oh I came here - good maybe but unsuccessful if think so - right thing to do.
                        Wanted to be celibate but couldn't - then lost.
                        MB - As small and big rivers take support of the sea - all ashrams depend on grihasthashram.
                        how will others sustain - also in atharva veda.
                        sanskars for the ashram should be there else you stay as man animal.
                    Characteristics
                        right to earn livelihood.
                        Right to store as security - gotta donate and depend on krishna for next day celibates.
                        Right to enjoy under social and spiritual code (dharma aviruddha kaam) - dharma is what behoves society - don't disturb anyone else.
                        responsibility of 3 ashrams.
                    3 debts - b4 complete surrender we have debts but full surrender doesn't.
                        as beginner we serve eb and exalted anyways serves eb.
                    Dharma - focus on grihasthashram here
                        Brahmacarya dharma is follow guru anyways and guru has the onus.
                        Grihastha dharma - nice care of wife but not old parents or not kids or bad business or no taxes to govt - so many faces to be ideal.
                            @Sugar - Dharma - means nature, attribute, duty
                                Tongue - sweet; For water - soluble, for eyes - colorless crystals, for diabetic - poison.
                                sugar is relative - it is natural synergistic state developed by maturing mutual relations.
                                chastise children and may seem cruel but gotta do it.
                                so like sugar grihasthashram has so many faces to qualify.
                                not bad sugar or good sugar for seeing a face.
                                synergistic - for both not 1. Natural - not forced. Wife doing business and maid from jhopadpatti taking care of child and hence sanskars.
                                    maturing with time.
                        Dharma as responsibility or duties.
                            duty towards husband wife
                            duty towards parents
                            kids, family traditions, caste, society, country, humanity, universe, caste.
                        3 debts
                            dev rin - debt towards higher powers.
                                dev take little and give a lot. danav - takes a lot and repay little.
                                Repay - by DS, respecting demigods and natural powers.
                            rishi rin - debt towards sages and rishis.
                                meagre life but such great science for others.
                                all acaryas of past like sushrut, aryabhatt, veda vyas, etc.
                                Repay - By devp any knowledge stream and hand it over to next generation and society.
                                    so study it; add your experience to it and give back to society.
                            pitri rin - debt towards ancestors.
                                good training and lots.
                                Repay - by becoming excellent parents and create and devp ideal descendants.
                        Join Grihasthashram for repaying these debts not SG - of course that's a part of it.
                            breakups - less salary but ego probs.
                        Different stages in householder's life
                            Entrance - Vivah Samskar
                            Couple - Husband Wife resp
                            Adhijanan - Prep of parenting
                            Samskara - from birth to 5 yrs of life
                            Anushasan - Age of child between 5 to 15 yr
                            Mitracharan - From 16th yr till marriage
                            Vanprastha Mindset - After marriage of children
                        Purpose of marriage - in manu smriti
                            To have children, perform religious and social services, have sex life based on religious principles.
                            upgrade ancestors and oneself to higher planetary systems.
                        Blessings given in convocation ceremony (shikshavalli)
                            Satyam vada - always speak truth
                            dharmam chara - always follow dharma
                                simple defn don't interrupt other's interest in ur enjoyment.
                            matri devo bhava - respect mother as representative of god.
                                7 mothers you know.
                            pitri devo bhava - respect father as representative of god.
                            acharya devo bhava - respect eg teacher as representative of god.
                                not guru actually - married and not sanyasi but teachers.
                            atithi devo bhava - respect guest as representative of god.
                            svadhyaynma pramditavyam - don't be proud of knowledge.
                            prajatantu ma vyavachhetasi - don't discontinue the lineage.
                    QA - Little high standard
                        Excuses are there. Even if true. At least in my case - very sincerely you say it - not incapable but tough.
                        little steps to right thing - yogkshema vahami aham.
                        keep ego away. Adjustments are required. Know svadharma - not others opinions about me but mine.
                        Lord doesn't take resp of your head - but our problem - we do sakaam bhakti. Lord helps st but not to be looked.
                        3 things increase automatically if not resolved timely - loan, disease and doubts.
                        They come closer cuz of you - and fights also cuz of you.
                        You gotta balance and ensure good relp between the 2 - mistake then make them realize also.
                        make her understand time to time - you also get children. If both grihastha then double dose.
                        Ego kept aside - new bride needs time - thakur ke seva mein ahankar kyun.
                        Any fight then you gotta say that it's not ok - if not speaking anything then also problem.
                        you fella fight, what's my mistake.
            </Attitude>
            <Varna>
                About - Varna (work life)
                TODO
                    Financial planning, livelihood
                    Living vs revolution
            </Varna>
            <Ashram>
                About - Ashram (relationships) - different natures
                TODO
                    Mars vs Venus. World of Family.
            </Ashram>
            <Selection>
                About - Selection
                TODO
                    What to look for in life partner; marriage board.
                Vedic View - Selecting a right partner
                    Ref - Grihasta Ashram Seminar - Preparation for Perfect Grihasta Ashram by Sankirtanras Prabhu
                    so many concepts from western and indian books but I will give from vedic books
                    duty of girls father
                        spiritual credits of kanyadaan.
                            price-tags / brands vs values
                                REL raymonds brand but wearable in winter or summer don't ask. tight or loose.
                            considerations during marriage proposal vs reasons for divorce.
                            parameters of gratification vs parameters for relation.
                            short term gains vs long term progress.
                            Finding right boy is a resp - so kanyadaan blessings.
                            We check price tags - education, salary, flat, car, foreign how many times, settling plans in USA, single child - all the money. Pride in parties.
                            Divorce cuz losing jobs or no flat - less heard. So, questions asked b4 marriage are all the wrong questions.
                            parakram in man - history of boy - price he has paid and rupa for stri - not beauty but dealings - soft spoken, e1 wants to be around.
                        why parents and not children - we do most of things to calm the mind instead of mature decision.
                            issues come later and difficult to resolve them.
                    Qualities of bride groom
                        jnanai - knowing vedic principles of life. Intel, Wise (different between vidya and jnana)
                            vidya means knowledge to survive in this material world. jnani means apply knowledge for spiritual purpose also.
                        brahmacari - by action, speech and thoughts.
                        youth - right age
                        manhood - can fulfill all the resp
                        kul - family lineage
                        sheel - character
                        sharir - health, no diseases
                        vitta - financial stability
                        smmapannata - earning ability, prosperity.
                        anurupata - physical match.
                            average looks should marry to average looks else 80% times worried about others should not look at my wife in wrong ways.
                            chanakya - too much beautiful wife is also an enemy
                    Disqualifications
                        no inclination for charity and righteousness
                        non-vegetarian
                        hypocritical and hard hearted
                        cheat and with loose character
                        bald and with white hair
                        suffering from infectious and incurable diseases
                        wasting time in decorating externally
                        with weak eyesight - long vision of life. not daru now and later we see.
                        with corrupt mentality
                        having long hairs
                    Qualities of bride - sequence also taken as given in vedas (important)
                        jnani - knowing vedic principles of life
                        young
                        age should be less than that of bridegroom
                        with full of feminity
                        virgin - ananyapurvika, aprishtamaithura, akshatyoni.
                            like boy be brahmacari
                        beautiful - hansvani gajagamini, meghvarni vishalnetri.
                            sweet voice - pleasing not like crow shouting; like elephant - can lift child;
                            redding blackish than white - anemia otherwise. broad vision also not physical eyes.
                        kul - family lineage and etiquette
                        affectionate behavior
                        having a brother
                            pind daan to 1 gotra
                    Disqualifications
                        Having legs of deer - flickering mind, unstable.
                        having teeth like bull - over eater
                            how atithi devo bhava will happen.
                        moving like a cow - very slow in every action, lazy
                        short tempered
                            atom bomb in house - groom is still ok but bride is dangerous.
                        always want to look better externally
                            this can cosmetic industry badly - simple makeup is ok but hours in front.
                            boys won't see mirror and girls also.
                        sick
                        with problems of reproductive system
                        name is based on river, mountain or nakshatra
                            those times names given by forest dwellers - so as to remember. Does not apply now.
                        having no brother
                        unknown mother and father.
                    Selecting a right partner
                        Gotra, pinda, pravara consideration
                        Match making based on horoscope
                        Kundli kuta - max points
                        varna - 1
                        vasya - 2
                        tara or dina
                        yoni
                        grah maitri or rasyadipati
                        gana - 6
                        rashi - 7
                        nadi - 8
                    Devotee non-devotee consideration
                        As per BG 12.13-19 verse
                        quality of good devotee - yo me bhakta sa me priyah
                        non envious - kind friend to all
                        free from false ego - equipoise
                        tolerant, always satisfied, self controlled, determination, mind and intel fixed on me,
                        pure, not disturbed by anyone, expert, without cares.
                        problem comes when we think of devotee as a brand instead of value as discussed b4.
                            qualities are important.
                            LCM - person taken HN once is dev. SP - my disciples are gentlemen.
                            Consciousness matters more than externals. Devotee and non-devotee poroposals are respected and scrutinised equally.
                            Dev should be value and not mere price-tag or brand.
                        every day introspection is necessary - what to look for.
                How to choose Life Partner | Life Coaching With Namita Purohit
                    Part1 - Life partner choosing
                    sacred bandhan, arranged-love
                    16 yrs so much prep but for life we don't do any home work - read articles on tinder and Jeevansaathi.
                    Parents also useful that how to check - lots of changes in current times - so many facilities vs Ramayan parampara - what's vedic insight.
                    Marriage purpose - seasons and clothes; attitudes also.
                        lesser difficulties in life if we stay to original - if change with time - MOP and MOI like these days. So, better see with MOG - happiness.
                        My enjoyment - my needs and interests; enjoy and do nothing MOI. Duty and service consciousness is necessary.
                        Goal of life is God so elevate each other for spiritual focus.
                        Protect each other and take care of needs of each other.
                        SG in dharmik way. This is 1 goal not only goal.
                        procreate.
                        support all other ashrams.
                        pitron ka dhyan bhi.
                    Qualities - bank balance, family size, etc.
                        we try understand and ppl do change over time.
                        If only SG, then infatuation possible.
                        Nature match - bungee jumping I don't wanna do - language, nature - movies show they come together and happy but lots happen inside.
                        compatibility and respect are most important.
                        first gotta understand yourself and others.
                    Unhealthy relp reasons
                        when ppl are unhealthy.
                        prem hai but don't talk with love - need satisfied so radar don't see other things - infatuation so forget to see other things that should have.
                        psychological needs exploited.
                        marriage ain't between 2 unhealthy ppl but 2 healthy ppl making each other better. Heal each also.
                    Should we depend on arranged marriage
                        more experience and take advantage from parents.
                        even arranged how much do parents get to see - education, job, healthy family, earning, good looks.
                        So only needs or SG elements are only seen. Still same problem as love infatuation.
                        Karma philosophy, God philosophy reqd - probs come anyways in couple after compatibilities - guys be mature.
                        So education for purpose is more important.
                        Why pitri - don't do and have consequences.
                    Caste system - should we go for it
                        mappings - physical, cultural and mental.
                        cultural - eating, lifestyle and dealings in and outside family
                        No in love it doesn't matter - it does south indian told to eat only chapattis - can't carry on.
                        castes map to MMN - intellectual pursuits, desire and action and admin;
                        MOI - enjoyment and not responsibility taking.
                        caste maps to our physical element also - 5 bhoot elements also differences - even child procreation becomes difficult.
                        caste is diluted but not entirely - high low is not worth commenting right now.
                    horoscope
                        jyoti shastra - put light on life thru lights of star on your life.
                        which astrologer you refer is important.
                        astrologer also sees what ppl focus so only enjoyment.
                        Ask specific questions - how good for pitras, etc.
                        36 guna seen; what are those. reproduction is ok, etc. Physically and healthy child.
                        Child health affects marriage.
                        maitri - nature; nakshatra; nadi for child and yoni - reproduction compatibility.
                        vasha - leadership who takes.
                        spiritual focus can be understood.
                        even understand my nature. If not given in past, then karma affected in next life. Pashchattap.
                    Not astrology beliefs
                        this is scientific - sun on head it affects us; depressed if lesser; clothes, etc.
                        Moon also we understood - chandani raten, mind effect lunar and lunatic;
                        grah - grahan kar lete hain.
                        Planetary influence on body book.
                            disease increased in certain constellation.
                            same birth with same cities and dates - similar problems; 200 pairs they studied.
                            farmers - harvest as per nature
                            females hormones with nature.
                        epigenetic and gene expression.
                        rejecting is easy - so just evaluate not just follow fashion unthinkingly.
                    How to be ourselves what other is looking for
                        understand yourself - ayurved, feedback and horoscope.
                        every one has limitations. Learn from others.
                            eg - pregnant girl can be guided by a mother.
                        My needs and goals - spiritual focus.
                        Prayers are important - not enough I try my best but may fall short.
                    Material world problems
                        no promise that enjoyment after marriage.
                        commitment to service to each other, others and service to God.
                        blessings from all - demigods, parents when we marry. Invitees are all for blessings.
                        commitment withdrawn may have karmik consequences.
                        maturity gotta be increased.
                        Sita and Ram - after marriage only probs. Ramji world war after wife abducted. health problems in our case is equivalent of abduction in our case.
                        nala damayanti story narrated to convey that I tell story of person with more difficulties than you.
                        seva => more responsiblity. Probs come - can I face probs with him. No1 forced to marry on gunpoint so take responsibility.
                    QA - high divorce rate so fear. How to find suitable partner and how to find ppl with enjoyment.
                        have patience. Study all divorces and don't follow their patterns and selection criteria which caused divorce.
                        don't marry cuz lonely. qualify yourself.
                        Some HK and ISKCON - only focus spiritual and not other factors - nature compatibility is important.
                        Both have spiritual focus but not whole individuals.
                        When there is shadow there is also real thing.
                    Education with marriage compatibility
                        Varna and ashram interaction is the question.
                        profession demands, also in time and mutual respects.
                        compatibility helped by these.
                        kardam muni asks Vishnu for compatible wife.
                        Devahuti - quality, svabhav, achievement equality helps compatiblity.
                    Bad astrologer?
                        Informed decisions taking. but karma is bad then difficulties come nevertheless.
                        The session just make things better but probs freedom ain't happening.
                        Do best and leave rest.
                    manglik - I ain't astrologer. So gotta check with them. Health probs with them.
                    Neither marriage, nor brahmacari
                        purpose of marriage - protect ourselves is one of them.
                        rule based envt helps us do that - sanyasis etc do it without.
                        Mind wants MOG but easily affected by MMN around us.
                        structured routine and engagements - throughout so plan is chalked out
                        No ashram or like minded ppl - this path his somewhat undesirable cuz difficult.
                        We have masculine and feminine energy - dry otherwise and balance thru the other.
                        focus will go away - we have needs and desires so will get affected.
                        Prescribed duties regulate our mind.
                        2 yr you live and you will get insights but in general it is required.
                        relatives are to be taken care of.
                    How to check a dev or potential devotee
                        If spouse not spiritual inclined - as you serve, you will elevate.
                        first let us grow and try to search in right place
                        spiritual inclinations thru discussions, astrology and guru.
                        Our duty is to serve them irrespective we are dev or not - our dharma.
                    parents separated so how search parents
                        be spiritually strong. Mind works tricks - want a partner then marriage board. Ask sb even websites also.
                        take ur time.
                    how to make or devp sp partners
                        we will change eb - partner gets terrified always behind me.
                        ur personal qualities will be more attractive to them.
                        LCM - Krishna in Radharani's bhav - more happy.
                    How much patience if not right person meeting as per mindset.
                        Mindset and time - if can find a trade off then doable but if not, better be alone and have patience - don't marry cuz of age factor.
                        Loneliness or mindset tradeoff.
                    Livin relp and for bhakti and lost in material world.
                        HK TV - topics. Marriage ain't trial and error - exchanges psych and energy connection
                        try and test it out - so much divorce so better try it out.
                        rin bandhans come - not married but those things come.
                        break up session is there on HK.
                        fear of another partner - clean and purifying yourself. What's in your control - focus on that.
                        as friend and well wisher - bhakti rules and regs easy else difficult - rules and regs are principles of freedom. 4 regs - breaking 1 of them are unfavorable for DS.
                        don't judge choices so connected to astrologer - all details - as soon - aura, energy and intuition - seeing her said that your relp anti to DS, do prayashchit.
                    Can't focus on study cuz of parental fights
                        moving city ain't easy. language, culture, electricity - all of these are challenging.
                        challenges - which one to deal with.
                        too many unknowns ain't good in life.
                        no1 convinces other - only healthy dialogue is possible. Feels attacked.
                        don't give emotional presentation, logically present - if emotional then jot down.
                        covid increased fight ew.
                    Not willing to marry; push from family so as to get spiritual wife.
                        Ur need is spiritual wife so respect their needs and also your needs.
                        let's seek meeting all requirements.
                        we need blessings of even seniors.
                        they want money centered lady - take money earning one - they can also be spiritually elevated.
                    Final message - dharmik sanskar. So meditate on that - focus on svabhav of child.
                        2 circles having same center then no clash.
                    Part 2 - How to choose life partner
                    5 points
                        male female energy balance - SG in dharmik way.
                        Support and heal each other - support spiritual growth.
                        Child procreation - deliver another atma.
                        other ashrams - self care chinta removal.
                        all rins - 3 rins removal. Krishna supreme controller but our gratitude.
                    ayurved and jyotishastra but modern psychology - what to do and what not.
                    what to look when go to see
                        all jivas are prakriti, purushottam. prakriti energized by purush. We try to be purush in material world - I be controller. Resource thing.
                        Feminine qualities of being prakriti easy for this form - expand my purush. nurture, nourish. Purush qualities then male form.
                        simultaneous use of both brain by females but 1 by males and extreme.
                        women more democratic - emotions suited - satisfying senses. nourishing, raising children. Outside dealings need more analytics. Vaam svabhav of Draupadi - is needed but problem.
                        woman also develop analytical side cuz gotta go outside and males also creative side gotta.
                        solid, confident, responsibility as a man - wussification of man - don't display courage. Potential to grow? Dhan uparjan; spiritual focus.
                        What they do in free time -
                            Brahminical - books and study; kshatriya - admin; vaishya - money earning ways; shudra - enjoying how to.
                        Ideal woman - all women they role - look for what you want. Draupadi lots of admin work - do we like that - firey personality - cows, treasury, etc. Like CEO - but admin actually.
                    Leave my child cuz spiritually focussed
                        Spiritually focussed community - eth seems maya - gotta go far. Other things get neglected - parents are right to an extent.
                        show maturity to them. More importantly, be convinced that prescribed duties help purification and is reqd for me.
                    Finding devotee takes time
                        patience level should be known about oneself.
                        Overrated that we want spiritual person - MMN should be understood. Also be open to potential of spiritual partner also.
                        Be open to what your expectations are.
                        no option other than patience - you will stay as you lived for 25 years - not anxiety but personal growth and resolutions. and Development. Calibre, maturity levels increasing.
                    Age gap - boyfriend is 14 yrs old - tradition of shyness.
                        French prez's wife is 25 yrs older than her. Society is judgmental.
                        Be confortable with yourself. Don't want details - you are intel.
                        Confident then no question. ppl test boundaries.
                        Discomfort emotions try to understand - subconscious wants to convey thru discomfort - there is a source behind discomfort address that.
                    Physical violence so fearful of relp
                        the fear is natural and stays - goes slowly.
                        This fear protects us from similar bad experience in future.
                        empathy for yourself - what you understood from incident - many signs but ignored cuz wanted to stay with someone.
                        Visualize and heal.
                        Self respect. Visualize the situation again and how you would act differently.
                        Such signs of such ppl - gotta stay safe.
                    Bipolar Disorder - go for marriage or not
                        maniac and depression phases - marriage problems come. But compassion fatigue comes.
                        Full effort to heal oneself if I were in your place.
                        Sometimes real problem is sth else - 1 lady real problem was losing twin in childhood.
                    Mature woman , perfect age, do job or not
                        mature - role ki awareness.
                        perfect age - age when ready. Early childhood - circumstances have changed - will I be able to sustain myself - young then easy to understand oneself.
                        do job or not - Krishna fruitseller was a job; satyavati was fisher woman so job; gopis makhan and selling - Vrindavan economy and toll.
                            So stri also has varna. vaat pitta kafa - kaikeyi kshatrani.
                            agriculture economy - silk work in china - all by woman. Milkmaid in USA - so even centuries back.
                            cottage and handicraft - now machine for eth - so no engagement at home.
                            work is nature and stri means to expand - lone at home is making her mad.
                        stri - ghar ki lakshmi. Lakshmi devi doesn't stay if girl cries.
                    don't wanna marry - so marry a devotee says mom.
                        shadi ka laddu - khao ya na khao.
                        mind goes outta control very easily. So gotta focus - vyavasayatmika buddhi.
                        need to share life with someone - how will that be met.
                        Never say never - we change with time. Better to stay married or join ashram.
                    should have same nature - opposites attact works?
                        thand, garmi; scuba diving, etc differences do come - can we let go.
                        what can you adjust with - similar answers to many questions.
                        respect, support, encourage and adjust that's important.
                        similarities then easy to give support.
                    love marriages with bhakti.
                        object of love be Krishna - is it ok.
                        vertical and horizontal relp - both are important.
                        gandharva vivah ain't marriage - you can find partner for yourself or arranged - gotta love is important.
                    compatibility important - differences vs love.
                        love is deep word - mostly worldly is infatuation.
                        Mutual respect and care.
                        kali nature - quarrelsome, hypocrisy and all - can we accompany each other for long.
                        you can sacrifice for sometimes but not for lifetime so gotta see compatibility.
                    small disagreements vs love at sight and divorce at first fight
                        less tolerance we have. how can spirituality help
                        even in spiritual circles it is high - compatibility and mutual respect is important - how spirituality helps.
                        grihasthashram - kuchh kuchh hota hai type. But spirituality gives awareness that it is about 5 purposes not 1.
                        dharma is far more important.
                        Like pleasure is temporary, so is distress so spiritual focus helps.
                    High spiritual divorce rates - they have base but why high rates
                        mutual respect and compatibility is less.
                        spiritual life focus and other suffers their needs are not met.
                        Krishna takes care of eth - no why - you gotta give time to each other.
                    I like bhakti she does not
                        what's going on actually is hidden so gotta answer with few details.
                        you must be giving her lesser time. Why changing now.
                        What's important to you - you must be liking the lady.
                        escape mentalitya and peace in bhakti - don't do in haste like driving in mumbai.
                        should start sharing what he likes in bhakti - respect from her - can see. Show her - not for conversion
                        gotta balance self interest and other's interest.
                    Can't forget husband - high divorce rates
                        big tree - uproot and put another place - comfort and eth set - it's painful.
                        it feels like death cuz a life experience is gone. takes 3 yrs subjective.
                    Remarriage with divorce and remarriage
                        Yajnavalkya - but there are situations when it can be done not a license.
                    Marriage based on compatiblities - financial, intellectual, etc.
                        marriage be among equal says SP.
                        so that mutual understanding - status differences then vichardhara differences
                        thinking shaped by these details - feelings of scarcity vs generous at spending. 3rd class train vs flight flight.
            </Selection>
            <VivahSanskar>
                Vedic and western (christian) perspectives
                    1 of 16 sanskars - to be registered
                    spiritual arrangement - legal agreement
                    for selfless service - to guard rights of individuals
                    based on devotion - based on mutual enjoyment
                        scratch back down.
                    step to responsibility - step towards fall down
                    devahuti, kardam muni - adam and eve.
                        fall down from spiritual for adam and eve but not for former they never felt that way.
                    serious enlightenment - festivities and show off.
            </VivahSanskar>
            <GrihasthaLife>
                About - Married Life in KC
                TODO
                    samskaras. counseling, tree of life, home temple. Role of family in ISKCON. Eg of Grihasthas - devahuti.
                    Duties of husband wife.
                Dampati ashram - couple phase
                    Ref -  Grihasta Ashram Seminar - Preparation for Perfect Grihasta Ashram by Sankirtanras Prabhu
                    Time Frame - from marriage till desire to have a kid.
                        2-3 yrs, career oriented 5-6 yrs, for those willing to pay infertility clinic - it can be 10-12 yrs also.
                    Natural different qualities of husband and wife.
                        man - radiance, sacrifice, logic, intel, devotion, mental or emotional tolerance.
                        woman - forgiveness, affection, holding and supporting nature, physical tolerance.
                            man does not forgive, affection not cutting relations that done, emotions more than logic.
                            holds and nourish so nature gives motherhood. Husband work done - nothing but wife multitasking.
                        natural physical, emotional, mental and speech related differences must be considered.
                        Quota of words - man 2K and woman 20K of which man speaks 1.5K at office so left with 500.
                            must say yes no - wife thinks poor guy - speaks that much only.
                    Purpose - When the couple is completely satisfied then entire family lineage gets benefitted and entire family becomes blissful.
                    Austerities
                        Austerity - BG - Of the body - worship SPOG, Brahmins, SM, Superiors like father, mother and in cleanliness, simplicity, celibacy and non-violence.
                            violence is more verbal than physical. Physical is cruelty.
                        Austerity of Speech - truthful, pleasing, beneficial, not agitating to others, and vedic.
                        Austerity of Mind - satisfaction, simplicity, gravity, self control and purification of one's existence.
                    What to do there
                        It's more of interdependence - from dependence and independence.
                        Complete trust -> Mutual Respect -> Raise Together.
                        Visioning about life in this phase  - meditation on economical consideration, expectations based on personal commitments.
                            what to do in different phases of life 30s, 40s, etc - what are the expectations.
                            how you wanna die.
                            economical - if this happens then what; policy of donations, parental care, etc.
                        sets eg for children also
                        expectations are mutual - not one way.
                        Tad viddhi pranipaten - humble enquiry and service builds up a faith in relp where knowledge blossoms.
                            Love is not a noun but a verb
                            Quality of relations in this phase are indications of mental and emotional devp of a person.
                        After marriage - Vedic time
                            parents go to teerth for 3-4 months - proximity so 1 after another - time for couple to know each other.
                            Separate flat or no personal space - both are not as per vedas.
                        Other expectations
                            Training about family traditions, social etiquettes and responsibilities
                            Training about family structure, organization, family business and specific family rituals.
                            knowing nature of other family members.
                            if gel well than girl rules the family.
            </GrihasthaLife>
            <Parenting>
                Ref - Grihasta Ashram Seminar - The Principles of Vedic Parenting by Sankirtanras Prabhu
            </Parenting>
        </GrihasthaCulture>
    </KCCulture>
    <AdvaitaSabha>
        About - expect life retrospects and realizations from experiences and connect the experiences to spirituality.
            Urgency of spirituality in focus for preparation of exam. How to guide others with detachment.
        <SocialReflections>
            Why crime increasing in society
            How to deal with population explosion
            solution to ecological problems
            etc
        </SocialReflections>
    </AdvaitaSabha>
</Bridge>
