<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Bridge>
    About - For all phases, there is a bridge course to get familiar, intermediate course to connect or relate with vedic wisdom and core courses later.
        Eg - Personal Development for corporates followed by EBG for direct BG experience and then Bhakti shastri.
        Eg - SS for Youth followed by SMY and then to Bhakti Shastri. Of course, they eventually go to latter phases and so can be covered.
        Eg - Cultural presentation of temple visits, festival visits, grihastha home visits, etc are bridges; Cultural systematic presentations are interim and Bhakti shatri as core.
        There are professionals of every field - the idea is not be become a professional but have enough understanding for yourself and extending necessary help to others.
            Idea of KC is not become professional of eth or amateur and many things but engage as per interest for specialization and also consume all services for better spiritual life
            there will be many free services and many paid ones. Free services because soft corner for nishkaam seva or yoga yukta karma.
            REL - marriage NS camps can also be seen as a psychological expertise. We take what's necessary and serve.
                Spiritual science is full time job for intelligent design, Bhaktivedant academy, etc. But we take what's necessary and share.
                One time seminars is full time jobs for self help service providers (aaroh and avaroh) - but take what's helpful and share is what we do.
        This is important front of spirituality dealing with Shastra chakshu on real life - applications, analysing world, etc
            and is also lots of fun to see spirituality applied in the world or world seen in spiritual light.
            This doc focuses on only the avaroh aspects of applications and aaroh aspects are excluded though very important - eg - self help books.
    <PrahladSchool>
        About
            SummerSchool with arts and shloka recitation and camps.
            Only interested in its syllabus nothing more.
		Evolve Pune ?Radha Gopinath covers - Bhajan, Dancing, ?Drama, Shlokas, Ramayan, Mahabharat, Mridanga kartal instruments and Arti lessons, ?Value education.
    </PrahladSchool>
    <SMY>
        Abstract
			Application - Connect youth with bridging science to spirituality
            	SS is the bridge and SMY is the intermediate.
        DYS - Journey of self discovery
			Abstract
				Summary - Discover the spiritual realm.
				Application - Engage in cultivation of spiritual realm.
				Action Item - Sadhana.
            Can A Scientist Believe In GOD?
				Summary - We in aaroh pantha but God designed this world
				Application - so gotta align with him and world (creation) - whatever its purpose is.
				Action Item - Remember creation has a purpose.
					When it comes to loving or hating the world, remember - this world of duality has a purpose given from a creator person.
            Getting the Eyes to See God
				Summary
					Every pursuit is aaroh or avaroh - with pros and cons
					aaroh has its limitations but avaroh if proper can be very rewarding
				Application
					Use ascending knowledge in conjunction with descending knowledge for life practices.
				Action Item - Corroborate life decisions with aaroh and avaroh.
            Vedic Wisdom: The Privilege of Humanity
				Summary - In the title itself - Vedas is manual for the creation.
				Application - Manual for creation so align with it - aaroh should assist.
				Action Item - Refer to vedas for conclusive material and spiritual guidance.
            Science of Soul
				Summary - I am in worldly roles (have body and identifications not am) but constitutionally different.
				Application - So let me tap into constitutional self for highest well being.
					Shaky grounds can't make you happy but true id of self can.
				Action Item - Pick up practices for constitutional evolution.
            Substance and Shadow
				Summary - realms of existence with some perfection best match for constitutional self.
				Application - Let's strive for constitutional realm - (at least conceptual ideal but spiritual ideal is better).
					Tech does same thing but in a perverted way.
				Action Item - Lighthouse of life is to attain spiritual realm or world.
            If God is one, then why so many religions?
				Summary - All religions are different paths to same goal.
				Application - Focus on the end and see no conflicts.
				Action Item - E1 gotta improve not prove.
            Appendix 1: Evolution or Creation: Let the Data Speak
            Appendix 2: The Universe: How did it Begin
        YBF - God detailed understanding
			Abstract
				Summary - Detailed systematic understanding of God thru worthy guru worthy disciple parampara.
				Application - Identify God as your best friend in detail; accept guru disciple parampara.
				Action Item - Follow parampara to know God who is your best friend.
            Introduction
            Definition of God
				Application - Technical definition of God beyond worldly sentimentalism around God.
            Vedas - Are they Relevant Today
				Abstract
					Application - Vedas are relevant Today. Apply vedas in all aspects of life.
					Action Item - Read BG, etc every week.
                Only Source of Perfect Knowledge
                    How can we gain knowledge about him - 3 ways to acquiring knowledge.
                    Shabda is hearing from Vedic authorities since dawn of creation.
                    No Changes - Not revised (amendments), modified (change of opinions), updated - it's always perfect
                Faith in Vedas
                    Parallels with Modern Science (while no instruments existed)
                        Cloning of Kauravas - Dr B G Matapurkar
                            Churning of Vena to make Pruthu
                        Vimana Shastra, Brahmastra,
                        Kakudumi's experience of relativity of time.
                        Speed of Light, Mathematics, etc
                        Ontogeny, Living Entities are ew (fire bacteria), Plants have feelings, Cow dung is pure (antiseptic in 1940)
                    Vedic Predictions that have come true
                        Buddha, Chanakya, Chaitanya Mahaprabhu, Chandragupta/ Ashoka, Jesus and Mohammed.
                        Predictions about Kali Yuga
                            Food sold in public (vs charity), flesh of foetus, sex based relp (not sacred duty to inc service; livin'; court based)
                            Might will be right (wealth and brute force); Lavanya kesh dharanam; Brahmana by thread he wears (not qualities)
                    => Coming from person knowing past, present, future and all knowing.
                Seeing with ears
                    @Save from thief broke in.
                    Glass of Liquid - determine!
                        Chemical Tests - only medicine left finished in testing, mixture of 2.
                        ask the person who handed the jar.
                    Hearing is basis of life form cradle to crematorium
                        backtrack every knowledge - GRE, ABC, movie theater nearby, Einstein, Books are recorded sound.
                        born in ignorance - educational set up to gain more awareness to improve our life.
                    Questionability and Authentication
                        Authority of info - TV, news, magazines, journals - overflooded with questionable info
                vs Science
                    Real Mother vs Treacherous Witch (putana)
                Why
                    Relevance Today
                    Manual for Life
            Qualification of Guru
				Applications - Caution with guru.
				Action Item - look for guru with these qualifications.
            Qualification of Disciple
				Application - How to be a proper disciple.
				Action Item - Cultivate qualities.
            The Most Confidential Knowledge
            Krishna - The All Attractive
				Application - Be attracted to Krishna cuz that's natural.
				Action Item - ed sadhana to cultivate attraction.
            Evidences for Krishna’s Supremacy
            The Singular Supreme and the Plural Subordinates
            The Controller of all Controllers
            Worship: Divine and Mundane
            Your Heart - To - Heart Friend
            Well Wishing Guide Who Always Accompanies You
            The Infinitesimal and The Infinite
            Love of God: The Culmination of Religion
            Appendix 1: Krishna’s Rasa Dance: Can We Imitate ?
            Appendix 2: Avatars : Genuine and Fake
            Appendix 3: The Position of Lord Shiva
            Appendix 4: The Golden Incarnation For The Iron Age
            Appendix 5: Meditation for the Modern Age
        YSJ - Purely materialistic explanations to alternatives
			Abstract
				Summary - Evolve on your secret journey from irresponsible materialism to spiritual yogas.
				Application - Move from materialism party to spiritual foundation party.
				Action Item - Base life on spiritual foundations and not materialism foundations.
            Your Divine Identity - A Product of Chemicals
				Summary - Chemical origin denied. God seeded life (what about seeded thru chemicals?)
				Application - Don't trust theories provoking irresponsibility.
				Action Item - Act like God designed not chance origin.
            Your Glorious Ancestors – A Pack of Apes?
				Summary - Species seeded by God with purpose. Not misdirected natural forces showing random effects.
				Application - Don't trust theories provoking irresponsibility.
				Action Item - Act like our ancestors are Sages and Brahma.
            Your Cherished Emotions - A Biophysical Brain Function
				Summary - Metabolism isn't enough to explain subtle body.
				Application - Don't reduce emotions to brain function.
				Action Item - Treat subtle body as a layer of existence.
            Where Reincarnation and Science Intersects
				Summary - Some scientific studies indicate reincarnation.
				Application - Gotta be sober about reincarnation.
				Action Item - Take reincarnation as fact every jiva is going to encounter. Act to ensure good outcome from reincarnation.
            You Never Die - The Verdict of All Religions
				Summary - Soul's eternity in all religions.
				Application - Life is a journey.
					Make most outta life journey cuz I will exist after that in retrospect.
				Action Item - Spiritually responsible life - Sandhana.
            Your Lost Home – The Kingdom of God
				Summary - We belong to spiritual world.
				Application - Must strive for spiritual world.
				Action Item - Goal is spiritual world.
            Material Nature – A Temporary Prison House
				Summary - Material realm is prison house.
				Application - Don't hope very high from material realm - it's a prison.
					Make most outta what material realm is intended for
				Action Item - View of hospital not hotel - life not to enjoy but to get cured. Cultivate Cure.
            Your Secret Journey - Evolving Towards Perfection
				Summary - Evolve towards perfection.
				Application - Same as above.
				Action Item - Plan to evolve thru life.
            The Secret of Action – From Illusion to Reality
            Cloning – A Modern Miracle or An Ancient Method
        VOD - Transcend BODD cycle.
			Abstract
				Summary - Understand where we stand on cosmic map and where we gotta go and how.
				Application - Gotta rise from BODD cycle across lives and dualities within life.
				Action item - Pass the final exam thru cultivation of KC in life.
            Your Thoughts Create Your Next Body
				Summary - Thoughts create next body even within the life session.
				Application - Mind your thoughts.
				Action Item - Take Association for good thoughts.
            Break Free of Bonds
            The Quest for Happiness
            Becoming A Civilised Human Being
            Different Types Of Yoga
            Do All Paths Lead To The Same Goal?
            Art Of Living
            Cultivating Remembrance Of Krishna
            Art Of Dying
            Passing The Final Exam
        <MindMap>
            Abhidheya
                Qualifications of Guru
                Qualifications of Disciple
                Scriptures
                    The Most Confidential Knowledge (Vedas)
                        Vedas
                            Vedas - Are They Relevant Today
                            Vedic Wisdom: The Privilege of Humanity (DYS 3)
                            Cloning – A Modern Miracle or An Ancient Method
                    Religions - If God is one, then why so many religions? (DYS 6)
                Yoga
                    Different Types Of Yoga
                    Do All Paths Lead To The Same Goal?
                    9 Proc - Cultivating Remembrance Of Krishna
            God
                Definition of God
                Demigods
                    The Singular Supreme and The Plural Subordinates
                    The Controller of all Controllers
                    Worship: Divine and Mundane
                Jiva (mayavad)
                    The Infinitesimal and The Infinite
                Bhagavan
                    Krishna – The All Attractive
                    Evidences for Krishna’s Supremacy
                    Love of God – The Culmination of All Religion
                    Appendix
                        Krishna’s Rasa Dance: Can We Imitate
                        Avatars : Genuine and Fake
                        The Position of Lord Shiva
                        The Golden Incarnation  For The Iron Age
                        Meditation for the Modern Age
                    Your Lost Home – The Kingdom of God (can be thought of as prayojan as well)
                Paramatma
                    Your Heart – to – Heart Friend
                    Well Wishing Guide Who Always Accompanies You
            Jiva
                Can A Scientist Believe In GOD?
                Science of the soul (DYS 4)
                Getting The Eyes To See GOD (DYS 2)
                Where Reincarnation and Science Intersects
                You Never Die- The Verdict of All Religions
                Your Secret Journey- Evolving Towards Perfection
                Your Thoughts Create Your Next Body
                The Quest for Happiness
                Becoming A Civilised Human Being
                Art Of Living
                Art Of Dying
                Passing The Final Exam
            Prakriti
                Substance And Shadow
                Origin and Purpose
                Origin
                    The Universe: How did it Begin?
                    Your Divine Identity- A Product of Chemicals
                    Evolution Or Creation: Let the Data Speak
                    Your Glorious Ancestors – A Pack of Apes?
                Material Nature – A Temporary Prison House
                The Secret of Action –From Illusion to Reality
                Break Free of Bonds
        </MindMap>
        <More>
            Faith and Doubts
            Different Camps
                Utkarsh - DYS 5 and 6.
                Sankalpa
                    Faith and Doubt Sessions
                Sphurti
                    Me and Mind
                Nishtha
                    9 stages of bhakti
                Ashray
                    Diksha and Ashrams of life
        </More>
		GirlsVoice - None of my business; just FYI.
    </SMY>
	<PracticalKC> Yoga (Varna) and Temple (Ashram) Phase - See Culture of KC through many dev eg, inspirations and camps.
        About -
			<EBG> Yoga Phase - Spirituality for corporates or varna (Detailed depth study in Applied phase)
			Abstract
				Summary - Spiritual study with applications to corporate life.
				Application - Spiritual centered living.
			About - Applications of BG with focus on corporate life.
				Spiritual foundations enrich your qualities for varna - premise and convictions
				Busy life and they don't care whether science bridges to spirituality as much they value its applications.
				Although very spiritual centric - this can be thought of assisting Varna in KC.
				For corporates, Personal Development is the Bridge course and EBG is the intermediate course.
			SpiritualScientist
				Abstract
					Application - A life of harmonized aaroh and avaroh panth.
			PositiveThinker
				Abstract
					Application - Learn to align with positive best purpose - you end up thinking positive.
				Identifying the Divine Guide
				The Spirit of Bhagavad Gita
				Qualifications of an Idea Disciple
				Reincarnation - Fact or Fiction
				Evolving Towards Perfection
			SelfManager
				Abstract
					Application - Harness your and natural forces and resistance to align yourself to what your purpose is.
				Peace Formula
				Who should be the Object of My Worship
				God and gods
				Is God Personal or Impersonal
				The Art of Self Management
			<ProactiveLeader>
				Abstract
					Application - Help others reach conclusions and path in compassion like yourself.
				The Three Ropes That Bind Us
				Surpassing Maya
				Our Lost Home - Kingdom of God
				Karma - The Law of InFallible Justice
			</ProactiveLeader>
			<PersonalityDevelopment>
				Ref - Self Development Series Online By RSP
				About - Build Up Yourself Spiritually for Happy, Healthy and a Wealthy Living
				<SelfAwareness>
				Episode 1: Self-awareness – key to self-empowerment (soul, body-mind-intelligence mechanism)
				Applications - Change TAB or ABCD.
					Change Attitude
						Accept responsibilities - even at vocab level (personal)
						share blames, rewards and responsibilities - we need each other (?group thinking)
						learning - I know it all vs let me listen to others ideas too (balance personal and group)
					Change Behavior
						Know the right
						Do the right - ?dharma understanding reqd.
						Do the right consistently - Discipline - Rituals
					Change Thinking / ?Communication
						willing criteria - choices based on values not current feelings.
						group thinking - be open to others opinions
					Change Devotion - Clear goals and vision
						thru SMART goals with milestones
						connect with the field experts and community
						4 quadrants - do, decide, delegate, delete.
					Solve the real problems thru harnessing layers of existence.
				Flow of Thought - Problems, Solution - TAG, Vedic for real problems.
				Self Awareness
					?Problems - real and scriptural
						Selfish - I, me, mine centered so difficulties in nuclear families cold wars.
						Mother and wife fight st and you don't whom to side.
						What type of person am I and what do others talk about me.
							More - How can I improve and become a better individual?
							out of control vs cheerful - endearing.
							seeing thru specs and at the specs.
							Eg - material attachment to son wanting to make him the king.
								pampered so much that such atrocious activities supported.
							Eg - King Uttanpada's material attachment to beautiful wife and letting son Dhruva go to forest.
								could not reprimand his wife.
							Eg - Material attachment of Kaikeyee wanting to make her son the king.
							Eg - Arjuna - Material attachment to material bodies of relatives and friends.
								fight to establish dharma.
							Eg - Man in perplexities whom to pacify - mother or wife?
								Sucked into faults. Satisfied in yourself and care for others.
								Yudhisthrira respected to even cruel man, Dhritarashtra.
								Here, if girl could be a little more respectful and give affection and allow man to be his mother.
								Mother should think that she is experienced and grown up and she is young lady - she needs sympathy and affection.
							Eg - Parents in perplexities how the child should be raised.
								English medium or hindi medium - dictate terms to others.
							Eg - Couple forcing 1's opinion to others and suspicion.
								honesty, integrity, open heart, forgiveness, tolerance
								all qualities possible with self awareness.
								Atma or self means 5 things - be aware of self as body, mind, gradually to intel, etc.
					?Root Solution
						Thinking, attitude and behavior affects
							relationships at home.
							Results at workplace.
					Sambandh fundamentals -
						Thomas Huxley - There's 3rd thing in the universe, consciousness, which is neither matter nor force.
							We are spiritual beings with human experience vs humans with spiritual experience.
							Our body like Computer but need a user that's soul.
							Gross body - 5 tattva.
							Subtle body -
								Mind - Thinking, feeling, willing - conscious mind - likes and dislikes; subconscious mind - attachments and hatred.
							Soul - Eternity, Knowledge, Bliss.
								Qualities of soul should permeate our subtle body.
								soul is the real value - we save soul not car.
					Solutions
						Innate quality vs acquired quality - water in touch with mud.
							Eg - acquired bad qualities.
							Simple - Attached to my opinion, I know it all syndrome.
							Serious - Easily irritated. Inability to team playing.
							Grave - Bad mouthing about e1. I quit the team when I am not happy.
						Change your TAB - Thinking, Attitude, Behavior - cycle - Change thinking by self awareness
							Change thinking
								choice based on values not feelings.
									Attached to my opinion
										My team members say that I don't hear their opinions.
										They also say that I get very upset when they present their opinions.
										In 2mro's meeting, let me learn to speak less and listen more.
									Questions
										This habit is nectar in beginning but poison in end.
										How did I get into this habit.
										What can I do to defuse this.
										I refuse to let this hook me.
										I will give up bad company.
										I will replace with good companies.
									Be more amendable, flexible, understandable, cooperative, courteous, kind, friendly.
								positive outlook
									Positive - I will surely hear other's opinion - that'll improve my relationships in the long run.
									Negative - I can't stand people spending long hours in meetings. I will push and get things done my way.
							Change attitude
								by accepting responsibility (personal)
									I am what I am - not a good statement - be willing to change.
									I spent 3 hrs on him - instead of cursing - spend lesser time with them like 10 mins.
								What is your attitude towards learning (personal and group balance)
									I know it all syndrome vs I can listen to other's ideas too.
									Inability to team play vs We all need each other.
									I quit the team vs I will tolerate and watch.
									No matter what age, how busy are you in learning mode.
								Share blame and responsibilities (group)
									not blame on others and praise for me.
							Change behavior by
								Know the right
								Do the right
									What's right.
									Insulting speech puts off people and polite presentation conveys the point.
									Speak politely henceforth.
								Do the right consistently - Disciplined Practice. ?Rituals
									Watch my speech and give 3 complements daily.
									?feedback
							Clear goals and vision
								set milestones
								Connect with experts
								be a part of community of those with similar passion
						When Arjuna was in stress and perplexities => indecision => do duty of fight or give up and beg.
							Solution - surrendered to Krishna accepted as Guru.
							When in perplexed mind regarding duty and responsibility, take direction from higher authority.
							So, why should I study BG?
								B4 - Lack of confidence, anxiety, demoralized, stress, depression.
								After - emerged victorious.
								How - knowledge of the soul from Krishna.
					Self awareness for empowering yourself for all time to come.
						Now on lucid explanation starts not just TAB changing.
						Is youth meant for enjoyment or enlightenment?
						Nachiketa - King said don't disturb else would give to yama - yamadutas in queue for donation.
							yamaraj outta station so 3 days later and boons.
							send me back to my father and no anger - intel boy.
							heavens and hell - and pleasures - what yajna to get there.
								2 roads - 5 sufferings - SG and merry - only cause suffering. Sin is not free of cost - money, suffering postponed. Doctor's fee, police case. Death yama abode.
								path to god - very few ask so will tell you.
							beyond heaven and hell, people quit and never come back spiritual world - yes you are too small to understand even demigods don't know this.
						Living beauty
							after death - chemicals are same but
								no feelings
								no thinking
								no desires
								no movement.
								no consciousness - same body but soul is gone.
							soul is covered by gross and subtle body - life under garments and coat on top.
								subtle and gross body.
								@coconut - only coconut can make you happy.
							Mechanism of the mind
								Intel is decision maker.
								Mind is storehouse of thoughts, unfulfilled desires, previous experiences.
								5 jnanendriyas.
							Chariot of the body - soul is sitting back and intel is driver to control the mind ropes of horses.
								mind and intel are impure at present.
								trained thru reading BG etc.
								Think how to please parents by adjusting your behavior.
									train them in spiritual knowledge - meditation together.
								Controlled mind - best friend.
								Uncontrolled mind - greatest enemy.
								Mind is like knife
									in hands of surgeon - saves life.
									in hands or miscreant - kill 7 with it.
								Some people don't like mind control - it is like controlling cylinder with regulator - blass otherwise.
									garden thru growth of plants, trains controlled thru tracks, kite is not given full freedom.
								GIGO - Good in good out; garbage in garbage out.
									Books, movies, music, friends.
									Trains - magezine polluting their minds - not bringing animal not angel out of us.
								Mental dialogues - I am engr should know how to hold cigar; smoking makes me cool - how can fire make you cool.
								Intelligence thinks - Bad habit not good for you.
									You parents won't like to see you doing this. You may become addicted to it. Don't get into this wrong track.
						Western countries have reached the summit of material advancement.
							Jet planes, etc - mating in skyscrapers - but guided missiles but misguided men - Martin Luther.
							We are economic giants but emotional infants.
							Same activities of animals in sophisticated way - communication but what do we talk.
								What are we expected to do
								If ESMD - Defending also means fights or defending ego - how are we superior to animals.
								Animals never commit suicides but people do - best comforts but universities producing hippies.
								Animals can inquire about ESMD but Human can inquire about Life, Death and Beyond.
								Animals act mechanically based on instinctive behavior like machine.
									Middle of road waiting for lorry to go.
									He dog goes after she dog no1 arrests but even touch of hand of she human and she screams is taken seriously.
									Humans are not supposed to behave like animals.
									Animals get beaten in streets on eating veggies but human won't do that.
									Insults at home we don't go there again but no animals.
									can think before he speaks and acts; he can look b4 he leaps.
						Humans have higher intel to ask
							find out the cause of sufferings
							purpose of life
							harmonize our life with god and nature.
							to attain eternal happiness.
							Can't play football without goal post - likewise living life without any purpose.
						Your choice now will decide your future.
							Inquiry => Promoted to higher life.
							No Inquiry => Demoted to lower forms like animals.
							Siddharth saw BODD - e1 becomes old, e1 gets sickness. Doctor for every body part.
							Kripana - miserly - doesn't solve life problems but quit world like cats and dogs without understanding SSR.
								Suffers skin disease - attachment to family.
								wasted time in material bodily conception.
							Brahmana - cultivates knowledge of soul, god, relationship between the 2 and attains perfection.
								Intel and utilize human body to solve all problems of life.
					Summary - Self awareness exercise - how can I improve myself and become better individual.
						Remove acquired bad qualities by modifying TAB.
						Human life youth is meant for enlightened enjoyment.
						When perplexed in life, don't worry; take higher guidance from BG (from devs) like Arjuna.
						You are soul.
						Mind is store house.
						Animal body for SG.
						Material body is chariot.
						strengthen Intel BG.
						Kripana vs Brahmana.
					QA -
						Live like monks - like book Think like a Monk.
							camps take place - can join - healthy for body, mind, soul.
						BG by SP and which verses - very exhaustive.
							SSR and second chance and coming back.
						How to improve tolerance?
							tolerate thru wisdom - yell at him then lost to another company.
							Train him besides tolerate an employee.
							tolerate in marriage relationships.
							tolerating a dog of child.
							alienating 7 in meeting then loss in crores.
							4 defects in scriptures - so forgive others. Forgiven are those who forgive others.
						Practice to control senses besides meditation - will cover later.
						How to remain unaffected by negative, rude and ignorants.
							Gandhi reading book on train station and went with monkey picture - paper in dustbin.
							Keep valuable thing - I kept the pin with me.
							calm and collected then others are affected.
							What behavior of mine makes you upset - pls help me understand.
						How to stay positive and tolerant with so much negativity around. Easy to be distracted by material complexities.
							boat in ocean - is ocean enemy or friend to the boat.
							Depends if enters the boat or can move to the seashore.
							Let negativities in life propel us to our goal of life.
							2.14 BG - can't change the world but ourselves - we can wear shoe instead of thorns from world.
							There's negativity in world but also positivity - beacon light for the world.
							Westerns taking interest - associate with good people more.
							sapling is tender vs strong tree - when spirituality taken seriously.
							Dogs bark but caravan go on.
						How TAB will help our KC?
							very much - immediate action pointer.
							With KC and HK - easier to do these.
						Good and righteous attitude for short period of time is easy but sustain is difficult - solution?
							Done consistently then effects like habit after 22 days.
							Cleaning after sleeping bed - easy after a while - became consistent overtime.
						How to remember every moment that I am spirit soul?
							Act on that. Devotee students.
							Aham Brahmasmi or I am engr student repeating not enough - act on it.
							That acting on brahman is bhakti yoga.
							Servant of God is easy with 9 DS. Material world is alien place is easy.
							KY - of senses, AY - Intel. BY - Love - language of heart - body, mind, words.
						No affection for family after covid recovery - how to be normal?
							Affection is nature of soul - impersonal due to bookworms and not connecting with people.
							Develop affection for God then for all jivas we have reverence and love.
						Control senses in kali yuga without sanyas.
							Senses can't be artificially repressed but by purification thru spiritual engagements.
							3 monkeys formula of shut your eyes, ears, etc can't work for long.
								pressure for inside.
								But ear for deities of Krishna.
								tongue for prasadam, lecture, etc.
								Purified senses never attracted to impurity - impurity attracts impurity.
							Imaginative novels, cooked up stories, ghost movies - get rid of those things.
						How does KC help person control the mind.
							empty the mind in voidism or impersonal is not easy.
							neutral gases put inside vessel then easy.
							Mind flooded with Devotional NGRL - spiritual vibration calm, soothing.
							Material content - putrifies and agitates the mind.
				</SelfAwareness>
				<SelfCare>
				Episode 2: Self-care for long enduring success (Food, Exercise, Sleep and Harmless Recreation)
					Applications -
						Track stress
						Contemporary - PMR.
							yukta ESMD
								sensible eating - mit, hit, rit. vat pitta kapha. ingested food - excrement, body forming, consciousness forming.
								proper enough sleep cycles - regularly relax during workday also
								harmless recreation - music, massage. Positive mental scripts thru good books, movies, friends.
								exercises (yoga)
							V - grow in all aspects of life (not just work and money)
							F
								Positive attitude and avoid others negative attitudes
								don't bury emotions (anger, sadness, fear)
							A
								Neutral - empathic listening
								Positive - sincere compliments and smile.
								Negative - controlled response cuz we can't control stimuli triggered by others,
							S - Meditation, BY for all round health.
						Vedic - DAKM in life - don't sacrifice former for latter.
							Balance PIES of life to be good animal, friend, craftsman, saint.
							BY - meditation and 4 regs, yoga of love.
							NKY - perform eth for self purification for peace formula
							AY - meditate on super soul for connection to God.
							MMN - Cultivate MOG and avoid MOP, MOI.
					Flow of thought - Stress causes and workings, Contemporary solutions, Vedic solution - PIES, MMN, BJDK Yoga.
					Last lecture - TAG, Spiritual Guidance, Stay progressive, human life prerogative.
					Stress Problem
						Change causes stress - Eth changing - govt, COVID phase, companies and personnel, etc.
							so we gotta do self care.
						Stress is internal behavior for external stimulus - response mechanism.
							External causes - urgency addiction, unrealistic targets, unhealthy competition, interpersonal conflicts, job stress cuz of long working days.
							Sound, sight, gesture outside ---> Intellect --positive?--> no stress else stress for corrective action.
							corrective action then no stress.
							something unknown causes stress - financial crunch or marriage separation.
							adrenaline - unfavorable harmone but necessary.
					Solutions (corroborates with Vedas but not origin)
						Stress is good in moderation - Arousal vs performance - rises till Eustress or exhaustion then ill health afterwards till breakdown.
							Graph is just like elastic curve in physics.
						Keeping a personal record of stress - situation, person, emotions, levels, avoidance tactics.
							Hope for best and prepare for worst.
							Best - Delete the impossible. Daydreaming does not help.
							Worst - Deserves attention, not panic.
						conventional solutions
							deep breathing, massage, music, stretching exercises.
							Relax, enough sleep, pranayam and PMR.
						Practical tips
							Eat sensibly. avoid caffeine.
							Plan for growth in all aspects of life - not just work and money - relationships, spiritual interests, creativity, vacations, hobbies.
							Positive attitudes really help difficulties.
							Do not bury your anger, fear or sadness.
							Protect yourself from negative co-workers and relationships.
							can't control all ppl and situ - control your response.
							give sincere compliments freely and smile.
							Best communication technique is to learn to really listen.
							Use regular relaxation period for work breaks.
							Get regular exercise.
					Quick tips - How all - yukahar viharasya, etc.
						Food, exercise, sleep, harmless recreation.
						Stay pure and stay healthy.
						Exercise, Pranayam, Yoga.
						Early to bed and early to rise to be healthy and wise.
						Harmless recreation.
						Practice to be an ideal yogi
						Bhakti Yoga for all round health.
					Solutions from Vedic Perspective
						We are spiritual beings with human experience not vv.
							Innate Quality and Acquired qualities. Like water in mud contact.
							Is youth meant for enjoyment or enlightenment.
							chariot of the body.
							Higher intel - why suffer, purpose, harmonize, how to be happy.
							Some in study - join clubs but forget studies so the primary purpose of life should not be forgotten.
							Human life - Inquiry or no inquiry - evolve or degrade.
							Body like car so take care of it - petrol etc.
						Narad M - DAKM. Former not sacrificed for the latter is required.
							worldly pleasures at expense of health not good.
							St wealth but lonely.
						Lifestyle management - Work Life Balance - PIES - The zeal within for Physical, Emotional or social, intellectual, spiritual.
							Physical (8-9) - Good Animal - cuz they also take care of body.
								Diet 1, Sleep 6, exercise 0.20, misc (0.40)
							Spiritual (2 hrs) - Good Saint
								Sadhana, Svadhyaya, Contemplation / meditation, value clarification and commitment, realization.
							Social or emotion (2-3 hrs) - Good friend.
								Intrinsic security, empathy, service, synergy.
							Mental or intelletual - Good craftsman.
								Reading, writing, planning, visualizing, Skills devp, occupational duty.
							Some do only a few of these but not all.
								do all 4 to be happiest person.
						4 regs for happy life - Mercy, austerity, truthfulness and holy name (MATCH formula)
							meat, intox, gambling, illicit sex.
						Balance your life - G Harrison
							Faith of God is hub.
							4 Fs - Family, Fitness, Friends, Finances.
							without hub, the wheel collapses.
							if 1 or more spokes are weak or missing, wheel gets bent and hits bumps and potholes.
							with all perfect, it serves our needs for lifetime.
						Extremes
							Don't be prisoner of success
								I made lots of money but can't enjoy cuz behind the bars.
								addicted to make more and more money - never stop playing and empty shell game - honey comb and hunter takes it all away.
					BY
						BKS Iyengar - How to be a true yogi.
							Understanding self not just about physical and psychological states but down to our deepest levels of consciousness.
							Health is a state of complete harmony of the body, mind and spirit.
						Self awareness - being aware that I am eternal spiritual being in temporary material body.
							helps derive happiness from within. Making you resilient to the winds of change.
							Meditate - why?
							Improved mental and physical well being.
							Hence, Positive outlook on life and better relationships.
							Hence, Greater inner peace and happiness.
							Also, Improved concentration and focus in daily life.
							Hence, Reduced irritation, anger and frustration.
							Hence, Increased confidence and self esteem.
							Also, less stress, worry and anxiety.
						Self Awareness - teaches you to act as steward of resources and to protect your dependents and the vulnerable.
						Help you connect with supreme divine thru DS - Yoga of Love - by which you can invite the divine grace, doing things impossible.
					NKY and AY Combo - Perform all work only for the purpose of self purification
						what is self purification - purify mind of 3 mentalities.
							I am Proprietorship - Maps with greed.
								vs I am only custodian of God's property
								Hiranya - I am proprietor of e1 and eth.
								vs Yudhisthir - I am only custodian of SPOG's property.
							Controllership - I am boss and can do wonders by my brain - maps to Anger.
								like alexander, hitler, etc - or recent marriage so hubby belongs to me not mum.
								vs I am an instrument of God to serve those in my care.
								grateful to teachers and God can do neTh thru neb - not just me.
							E1 and eth is here for my enjoyment - maps with lust.
								All toys for me. Like Ravan for Sita.
								vs I am servant leader.
								Nelson Mandela - better to lead from behind and put others in front.
								In front to take the blame.
							Ravana vs Hanuman - Vihita karma, kaamya karma, nishiddha karma.
								God given instructions; not prohibited but like to like beach play; prohibited.
								Play in car, beach or ocean.
								Child needs fruit, choco once a week, regularly.
							LAG - 3 gateways to hell - lust anger and greed - give them up.
								Hiranya and Ravan only suffered.
						1 who purifies vision and activity by NKY can make further advancement by DY (Ashtanga) on supersoul.
							Eg - Janak M.
							Meditation on supersoul - develop devotion to him BY.
							understood as supreme enjoyer, ultimate controller, best friend.
							Advancement in DY - Aruruksa to Arudha stage.
								NKY + cultivate detachment and also practice DY 8 limbs - that purifies the heart of fruitive desires.
								Yama - Don'ts or phibitions.
									ahimsa, satya, asteya, brahmacarya, aparigraha.
									Natural for lion to jump on deer but not for us to jump on deer or cow or so.
									We can jump on carrot and eat but don't disturb co-brothers - all god's children.
									lies then tension to behave acc; steal then disturb; brahmacarya - body, mind, words - maintain purity in grihastha also.
									don't waste energy - use it for ojas, tejas - enlightened - vivek, vicar, dharana shakti. Sharp intel, make decisions in life.
									Not greedy to be billionaire and then trillionaire.
								Niyama - Do's or prescriptions.
									sauca, santosa, tapas, svadhyaya, ishvara pranidhana.
									body mind clean, surrender that god is master.
								Asana - Bodily or exercises - control senses.
								Pranayam - Breathing exercise to calm the mind.
								Pratyahara - withdrawing senses from sense object.
								Dharana - Fixing mind on Lord Vishnu's form.
									mind - the 11th sense should connect to intel and in turn to soul and supersoul.
									mind should not move outwards which is possibility.
									Yoga means to join or connect with God.
								Dhyana - Intensified meditation on supersoul.
								Samadhi - Complete Absorption Trance.
						BKS Iyengar - Inhale - taking strength from God, exhale then give service to the world.
					MMN - Smooth solutions thru sattvic lifestyle MOG behavior.
						Are you reactor or over-reactor to traffic jam or at office.
						Boss goes wild on incompetent employee.
						Know your personality type - MMN.
						Boss and emp happy, boss pressurizing and both panicking - MMN.
						Extremes and MOG is middle path.
							Sanskrit word - Ignorance for deficit, Goodness for stasis, Passion for excess.
							Temper - cold or hot vs warm.
							Attitude - fear or risk vs wise.
							Motive - Indifferent or Greed vs Service.
							Pace - Slow or Fast vs Balanced
							Outcome - Decay or Creation vs Sustaining.
							Mode - Inertia or Hyperactive vs steady.
							Information - Dull or lies vs truth.
							Disposition - Morose / lazy or restless vs satisfaction / peaceful.
							Contribution - Rest  or accomplishment vs Discernment.
					PQ
						Ideal eating - Mita bhuk, ritu bhuk, hita bhuk.
							Upanishads - food becomes 3 parts - stool and urine; absorption to become body and consciousness.
							Food pure thru offering to God - scientists doing great things but they can't cause rains and produce grains. Thanks.
							Eat as per vaat, pitat, kapha.
							Sattvic Prasadam - most suitable for KC.
							characteristics and results in BG - sweet juicy, fattening and palatable - increase duration of life. Strength, health, happiness and satisfaction.
							When animals cut for meat - they flight or fight so rajas tamas increases when we eat it.
							Diet - Dead, spicy, milk, veg, grains or intoxications - different MMN.
							eating too much, unscheduled times, junk or violent foods, too much palatable.
							disturb 1's meditation and self awareness practices.
							Tongue belly genitals in line - 1 is uncontrolled, next one is agitated.
							tongue tasty but harmful then overeating then stomach disorders and diseases and lowering our energy and efficiency in life.
							agitated can't do meditation properly.
						Sleep
							Regulate your sleep. 6-7 hrs
							Brahma muhurta
								manu smriti - destroys pious credits and good deeds - punya and satkarma destroyed.
								Bhaishajya saar - 1 who does gets
									beauty, wealth, good health, long life. Body beautiful like lotus.
								all flaws recovered like child in womb.
								divine personalities bless.
								mind intel positive and sharp memorizing.
						Recreation - Relaxation does not mean watching TV - we absorb the stress of serial characters.
							Kind of books, movies, music and friends give us scripts.
							Increase MOG - thru mind elevating wisdom literature
							Winston Churchill - university to teach wisdom not trade; character not technicalities.
					SQ - mantra - deliver the mind.
					QA - how to prioritize when so many things to do.
						Q1 - Do, Q2 - Decide. Q4 - Delegate; Q3 - Delete.
						Overdo then problem - overeat then sleep, policking, money chase, gossip, worrying.
						entertainment - some movies damaging to us. Guilt feel of extra time with 7.
					QA - sincere and insincere st in KC - birds of same feather flock together.
						get a mentor and associate once a week.
					QA - is having tea and coffee called intoxication - caffeine and process to come outta illusion.
						all agents that are harmful - fruits good but cold drinks bad.
						milk - health or alert.
					QA - love vs attraction vs possessiveness, caring, self respect, priority.
						with love for God all the others come.
					QA - bath, yoga exercise? Jogging, wash room, clear belly, brush, shower, yoga mat. B4 eating yoga.
					QA - is chanting part of AY - it's difficult in BG says Arjuna - constraints.
					QA - how to stop people over react - you become calm when 7 over reacts. Hand clap.
						colleague not in good mood then we can talk another day.
						what did I do wrong - st makes them more wrong - tap on body helps.
						there could be some truth in that person's anger.
					QA - prescribed duties st rajas grows - sattvik thinking.
						we st go overboard.
						Pandavas guided by dhaumya, Ved Vyas and Krishna.
					QA - Meat has problems costly, not condusive for health as per doctors, long track.
						you can say that you don't like it - academic choices then you have freedom after some time.
					QA - impurities for long - chanting of HK then darkness dissipated.
					QA - passion extreme is good but assertiveness in goodness and guided by passion.
						to start takes passion but maintain in MOG.
						We need right combination - raja rishis we become.
					QA - wake in brahma muhurta - Get proper rest and reduce gradually.
						Keep alarm on top of almirah.
					QA - overcome anger and short temper solution - lose friendships, losing VP, etc.
						anger is to protest against sth of my values.
						mismatch - so ppt go thru.
					QA - final goal of life is prema when love god then love e1. But love sb and not others st.
					QA - gotta kill cockroaches so no mercy - keep it utmost clean.
						they come for eatables - that's what they look for.
						Remove them physically - extreme case we put pest control - dengue. Why roasting them than mosquito net - then neighbors - they can also use.
					QA - faith in god varies with state of mind - use intel we are so dependent on god.
					QA - devp bhakti in family - be good in relationship and 7 else can do that.
				</SelfCare>
				<SelfManagement>
				Episode 3: Self-Management – six urges conquered by true heroes (managing emotions, proactive)
				Applications
					Chanakya - Proactive leaders should have self mastery b4.
					6 Competencies to be cultivated - STC AAI.
						self control (given a problem) - identify, determine, take action.
							negative emotions - avoid
								isolated focus, too much responsibility, expecting negatives, thinking in absolutes, etc.
						trustworthiness - communication skills. Listen, friendly, feedback, etc.
						conscientiousness - time management - 4 Qs.
						adaptable - learning agility - results, self, mental, people, change.
						Achievement orientied - Goal setting - SMART and measure, take advice.
						Initiative - Decision making skill - 7 steps.
							identify, gather info, compare alternatives, weigh evidence, choose, take action, review.
					Regulating body, mind, words.
						4 regs, worship SPOG, etc.
						words of wisdom, pleasing, etc.
						gravity in thought, satisfaction, simplicity, etc.
					BG - sthitaprajna - speak, sit, walk like him.
						principles b4 people.
						sense controlled life
							Rupa G - 6 urges tolerate. Be responsive not reactive - I choose.
						COI vs COC - Kamanyeva adhikaraste.
				Self Management
					Overview
						6 urges conquered by true heroes.
						What is self management.
						Self management in ed life.
						SM in BG.
						Self control to self management.
						Practical solutions.
					Recap
						This body can be fort or jail - painful body if tobacco is put inside.
						Yoga is connect with supreme Lord not enjoyment.
						MATCH formula - Mercy, Austerity, Truthfulness, Cleanliness and Holy name.
						Self purification from LAG - proprietor, boss, enjoyment mentality.
					Thrill in life
						Sanjay told Dhritarashtra in the end of BG.
						How to develop
							Develop Maturity of character
								boldness and sensitivity. Kind and considerate.
							Experience meaningful, lving, trustworthy relationships with others.
							enjoy harmonious relationship with the creation and the creation.
							express yourself thru abilities.
								7 intel - SLIM BIL - spirituo visual (artistic), Linguistic, Intra-personal, Musical, Bodily kinesthetics (sports), inter-personal, Logical (mathematical)
								Identify your talent and express it.
							fulfill our mission - spread your bliss around.
								self awareness else honey stolen from life.
								temporary body - no too happy or dejected.
					What's self management and why it's important.
						It is the competence to shape one's
							personal development.
							professional development
						independently of external influences.
						You create your own destiny without blaming others.
							This means it's up to you to find your place in the world and know when to change course.
							You do your duty at your best - karmanyeva adhikaraste. Tams-titikshasva - tolerate and decide what you should do.
							Don't let emotions decide you but you control your emotions.
							what's the root cause of emotion and how to address it.
							know my mindset and take apt action. Thus control your emotions.
						critical for a manager - no1 wants to work for 7 not controlled.
							thus making honest assessment of your own behavior will enable you to identify and address problem areas b4 they become damaging.
						3 step process for self control.
							Identify what you are feeling.
							Make an honest determination of the underlying cause.
							Take action to break the cycle of negative emotion.
						Self management doesn't mean to never become angry.
							There may be situations where anger is perfectly reasonable emotional response.
							The key is to have control over it so that it is channelled into resolving the problem at hand.
						Behaviors that feed your negative emotions.
							over-influenced by others.
							foreshadowing - eg - hanuman hopeless in lanka. There are always positive alternatives.
							dwelling on isolated events.
								unpleasant experience with friend but should not affect sth else.
							criticism and blame.
								share losses and profits together.
							thinking in absolutes.
								Hope for best and prepare for worst like sudden pandemic.
							focus on or expect negative feedback.
								constructive criticism can be welcomed.
							take on too much responsibility.
								too much food then can't finish.
								too much to do and can't focus on all of them.
						Self Management Competencies.
							self control, trustworthiness, conscientiousness, adaptability, achievement orientation, initiative.
							Self control - aka self management skills
								the ability to remain composed whatever state your emotions are in.
								People with this competence:
									Manage their impulsive feelings and distressing emotions well.
									Stay composed, positive, and unflappable even in trying moments.
									Think clearly and stay focussed under pressure.
								Eg - once saw the train leaving when we were late for it. Can laugh at our mistake.
							trustworthiness - aka communication skills
								means that you will do what you say when you say you'll do it.
								People with this competence:
									act ethically and are above reproach.
									Build trust thru their reliability and authenticity.
									admit their own mistakes and confront unethical actions in others.
									Take tough, principled stands even if they are unpopular.
								Eg - We want short cut but watering plants to grow takes time.
								Communication skills.
									listening, friendliness, open mindedness, feedback, confidence, non-verbal communications.
							conscientiousness - aka Time management skills
								involves an individual being thorough, careful or vigilant and implies a desire to perform a task well.
								People with this competence:
									Meet commitments and keep promises.
									Hold themselves accountable for meeting their objectives.
									are organize and careful in their work.
								Urgent X Important - 11, 01, etc - Do now, Do next, Do later or delegate, ignore.
									Q1 is MOP, Q2 is MOG and Q3 and Q4 are MOP and MOI and not very productive.
							Adaptability - aka Learning agility
								the ability to change something or oneself to fit occuring changes.
								People with this competence:
									Smoothly handle multiple demands, shifting priorities, and rapid change.
									Adapt their responses and tactics to fit fluid circumstances.
									are flexible in how they see events.
								Learning agility factors
									Results agility - deliver results in challenging first time situations.
									self awareness - extent to which an individual knows his strengths and weaknesses.
									mental agility - ability to examine problems in unique and unusual ways.
									people agility - skilled communicator who can work with diverse types of people.
									change agility - likes to experiment and comfortable with change.
								adapt response as per situations.
							Achievement orientation - aka Goal setting skill.
								requires an individual to show concern for working toward a self imposed and defined standard of excellence.
								People with this competence:
									set themselves challenging goals.
									measure their own performance against these goals.
									actively seek out information to get the job done.
									use their time efficiently.
								Setting goals is the First step in turning the invisible into visible.
								?SMART Goals - measurable, be positive but realistic. Pair goals with action and be flexible.
							Initiative - aka Decision Making skill
								means taking the lead in problem solving.
									and conflict resolution as well as taking action to prevent problems from occuring in the first place.
								People with this competence:
									seek out fresh ideas from wide variety of sources.
									entertain original solutions to problems.
									Generate new ideas.
									Take fresh perspectives and risks in their thinking.
								Data informed decision making.
									Announce (decide and coming forward)
									Assess - monitor the outcome.
									Ask - formulate a focussed question.
									Acquire - search for the best available data.
									Analyse - critically appraise and analyse the data.
									Apply - Integrate the data with your professional expertise and be conscious
								Decision means - cut off all other alternatives.
								7 steps of efficient decision making
									identify the decision.
									gather information
									identify alternatives
									weigh the evidence
									choose among alternatives
									take action
									review your decision
					Self management situations in our daily life
						situations
							opposing your opinion
							broken promises
							cheating
							didn't bother - about your convenience, needs and problems
							expectations unfulfilled.
						generally we get hurt by these - dependent on our maturity.
						Management = Man + Age + men + t.
							Manage the man within you b4 managing men.
							Gain age (maturity) to know what, when, how to manage.
							Am I willing to change - if I am, they may be willing to change also.
						How can I best serve in this situation - should be our question.
							facilitate or serve you - Krishna becoming servant of Arjuna - we can learn.
							Micromanagement - gotta learn how much to manage sb.
					Chanakya - Proactive Leader (or student) must shun the following 8 activities.
						Craving for carnal pleasures - lust.
						Losing temper - anger.
						Unhealthy comparison - greed.
						Craving for gratifying tongue
						obsessed with personal beautification.
							dress well but not too much.
						moving in fair for entertainment.
						excessive sleeping
							like 15 hrs etc make dull
						Overindulgence in entertainments - TV, sports, FB, Internet use, etc.
							time is a resource to be utilized not drained.
					Practical tips for self management
						regulating body, mind and words promotes wisdom and satisfaction to the practing leader and his team.
						BG 17.14-16 as ref.
						Body - 4 regs and simplicity and worship SPOG, teacher, mentor, parents.
						Speech
							speak truthful words.
							wisdom from literature.
							Pleasing.
							Beneficial and not agitating to others.
							Eg - teacher correct his studs (even if agitating) but not others not his students.
							Also regularly reciting vedic literatures.
							1 should study the limitless stock of vedic literatures available.
						Mind
							Gravity in thought.
							satisfaction
							simplicity
							Self control
							purification of 1's existence.
							Eg - ask instead of suggesting or instructing them.
							How to clam the raging mind? Say Yes to 5S.
								Satisfaction (vs greed)
									Give up unhealthy comparisons, practice gratitude, see what you have
									Divert the mind to Ramayan, MB, BG, SB, etc.
									Eg - husband asks wife - I overtook that guy ain't I smart - yes but also foolish cuz we had to take turn 1 Km back.
									Money rat race - run madness and no time for family and happiness.
								Silence (vs useless talks)
									avoid rumor mongering, back-talking, gossip, etc.
									They will lead to clashes
									Speak honestly, truthfully words of wisdom, see and speak good in others.
									encourage others.
									Be a person of HEART - Humility, encouraging others, appreciating others, Respecting others, Tolerating others.
										encourage means seeing good potential in sb even b4 they do good work.
										Recognize means after they have done good work.
								Simplicity (vs duplicity)
									Avoid frivolous speech and behavior.
									Lead a simple life free from duplicity and alawys think of doing good for others.
									No delight in hurting or insulting others.
								Self Control (vs Sense gratification)
									Detachment from 4 regs to practice MATCH.
								Sanctification - Purification of 1's existence.
									treat others as you wish to be treated.
									See every woman as mother and don't exploit wealth of others.
					Practical tips for self management from BG
						Sthitaprajna - What are symptoms of self manager - managed his emotions successfully.
							speak - How are his intel and words affected by affection, anger, neutrality. How does he respond.
								St black hat guy in team - will tell why any new idea won't work - but need critical thinkers also.
							sit - how does he not engage his senses - what is his mentality when his senses are restrained.
							walk - how does he communicate and interact with people of all sorts without losing cool.
							2.55 - materialist vs spiritualist.
								When a man gives up all varieties of desires for SG arising from mental concoction.
								when his mind thus purified find satisfaction in the self alone.
								smoke vs agarbatti. Meditating Krishna or opposite sex.
						Principles b4 people.
							My endeavor his grace.
							2.58 - say yes to right thing and no to wrong things like tortoise.
						Sense control
							Test of a yogi - able to control the senses according to his plan.
							senses - like venomous serpents - wants to act losely without restriction. devotee like snake charmer.
								never allows them to act independently. Follow do's and don'ts.
							Senses of KC person - only used in service of Lord, withdrawn otherwise. Eg - tortoise.
						6 urges to be conquered by NOI - Rupa G.
							vaco, manasa, krodh, tongue, belly, genitals or sex urge.
							stimulus - reactive behavior vs exercise choice with responsibility.
							Reactive is outside in and proactive is inside out.
							Reactive is if I had good boss, more time, cooperative team members.
								vs I can be more diligent and creative to meet boss needs, my time; be more patient and respectful to team to get their cooperation.
								if had vs Let me be.
							Words usage -
								nothing I can do vs Let's look at the Alternatives
								That's the way I am vs I can choose different approach
								He makes me so mad vs I control my own feelings
								They won't allow that vs Let's create an effective presentation,
								I can't vs I choose
								I must vs I prefer.
							Circle of influence vs concern
								O lord let me change things that can and ought to be changed.
								the serenity to accept the things that can't be changed.
								wisdom to know the difference.
							Stress reduction and positive thinking
								quiet envt, comfortable position, repetition of a prayer or chanting; passive attitude free from thoughts.
								slow metabolism. more self esteem.
								Sleepy zone, drowsiness zone, alpha zone, active and hyper-active zone.
								hippies to happies.
								remove all bad habits. Hankering for opposite sex, etc.
					QA -
						how to forgive yourself for hurting 7 unknowingly - overcome the guilt.
							Barking Dog shot dead but was only telling that wallet had fallen.
							go to temple and chant to pacify the mind.
						how to be proactive - learn from mistakes and TAG. 5S, 6 urges to overcome.
							sudden situations - learn overtime with postmortem then sudden will also come.
						loose temper with stupid lazy people - see them as ignorant not envious.
							feel sympathy for slow MOI but fast MOP.
							Rabbit will not always sleep - slow and steady wins but situational leadership - find his USP.
						After spirituality don't wanna do much.
							Arjuna wanted to leave from battlefield
							maam anusmara yudhyascha.
							brahmacaris also work hard not lazy - no1 can avoid.
						st failure mid way cuz of sudden change.
							see win defeat equally.
							cricketer wins then effigies and lost then defeat.
							smaller picture of life and larger picture - take life sportively.
							Castle on sand is smaller picture of life - parents calling in car is larger picture.
						Good self manager - read NOI 1-3 and KC and don't do SG - day to be kept busy.
						trauma about my past - depression when alone - come outta shell and associate with good ppl. Hear HK.
							Many nice books.
							Give them link for SSR.
							KC is very joyful movement - mutual.
						tug of war between worldly things or spirituality.
							waiting for old age does not happen.
							shreyas and preyas - lots of wealth but not narayan.
							USA has eth but people committing suicide so they need Krishna.
						Krishna has all good quality so how they come in us.
							see away from sun you see shadows.
						Chanting and past memories come
							yes they come in beginning - don't let mind go back to them - bring it back.
						overcome fear of failiure - affects your performance.
							focus on performance and result not in our hands like Krishna says - karmanyeva adhikaraste.
							children can be happy cuz leave troubles to parents.
						hereditary trait in anger - calmly ask what do you want.
						blamed for no fault then how to handle without anger
							Key 7 else taken but you shouted at.
							Clarify is the answer.
							Just waiting to throw tantrums - fire can't be countered with fire but water.
				</SelfManagement>
				<SelfDiscipline>
				Episode 4: Self-discipline – a regulated lifestyle for all round happiness (power of habits)
				Self Discipline - yukta ahar to regulate.
					Discipline - the word not liked by many.
						Children like to play but parents want them to go to school.
							will like to reach office late but gotta punch card on time.
							sun on time, seasons, flowers, cows, fields give grains.
							planets orbits are disciplined.
						It won't be do's and don'ts - if end result is clear then we don't mind.
							Like prep for IIT. Singing practice. Athletes for olympics.
							Discipline is painful burden without end result.
							1 reason ppl give up spirituality - big set of rules.
							constructive and productive is better.
					Koshas
						Lust - gang rapes; criminal acts in anger, money scams, scandals etc in greed.
						anger make employees turn away; anger causes divorse.
						5 koshas - layers to the self.
							annamaya - physical
								Interactive system - structural / body. Explore.
								young - food is main thing.
								hatha pradipika - asanas strengthen annamay kosh - the body.
									control the senses also.
							pranamaya - energy
								Express - Kriya shakti, power to act.
								13-14 age then very active for exercise.
								hathayoga pradipika - pranayam to strengthen the life force in the body.
							manomaya - emotional
								Involve - Ichha shakti - will or desire.
								teen - dream - adventure, freedom, explore life, etc.
								pratyahar - avoiding harmful agents into mind.
									hathayoga - strengthens the manomaya kosh.
									putting things that are harmful the body - cigar to feel cool, etc.
							vijnanamaya - wisdom
								Knowledge - Jnana shakti - knowledge from experience.
								twenties - and so forth.
								hathayoga pradipika - dhyan and dharan (by holding HK Mantra and concentrating on it)
									to strengthen vijnanamaya - realize I am spirit soul, not the body.
							anandamaya - bliss
								Enlightenment or blissful experience - life goal.
								hathayoga pradipika - samadhi to attain this.
									meditation on the supreme lord Vishnu or Krishna.
						Bhrigu asked his father what's brahman - it's beginning, sustainer and end of eth - I have given clue now find it yourself.
							is it body - cuz dust is starting and end. no, go ahead.
							is it energy - go deeper.
							is it mind - go deeper.
							is it soul - good - loving relationship with God.
								God is embodiment of love - all pleasures of this world become insignificant that much pleasure.
					Purify our mind - from viruses of lust, anger, greed (LAG - make us lag in life not lead)
						Mind Control - if controlled then best friend; if uncontrolled then worst enemy.
						REL shopping mall go to buy sth - impurity in the mind.
						uncontrolled mind - disturbed senses, fickle mind, lusty intelligence.
							lack of confidence, depression, stress, hypertension, damage family and society, weakened determination.
							loss of trust, madness, dangerous diseases.
							social - rape, murder, suicide, prosti, burning houses, cigars, liquor, breaking tv, picking quarrels.
							@Mouse can have grains and pulses from ew but chooses cheese cake in the trap.
							@Fish - falls victim to a trap - saw sth nice.
							Human has desire trap for the mind but the different from former.
								they know it's a trap.
								they know it's not necessary for survival.
							Office perspective
								no control over eating, not fresh at work, smoke break of 15 mins every hour
								unnecessary affairs at office, not attentive at work.
								moody fellow - should I recruit 7 with good habits.
								BG 3.34 - currently our mind is uncontrolled so don't take mind's likes and dislikes very seriously.
								like child would obviously want to play not study and harms himself. How long - all time.
						Solution 1 - Mind is powerful like elephant.
							chariot - first blind the horses.
							Then tie a rope of intelligence to control them.
						Habits - definition
							Settled or regular tendency; practice that is hard to give up; mental constitution or attitude.
							we take shelter of our habits.
							Sanskar on encounters and repeated then it becomes vritti tendency.
							vasana - it resides in us very deep.
							cultivated from family, friends, books, movies, association, etc.
							BG 3.41 - adamant desires should be given up.
								change habits by changing mental scripts - what all resides in our head or mind.
							Habits are addictive - HABIT - remove a letter and bit remains.
								starts with high but come back little below normal.
								depressed and want to come back to normal
								but depression becomes new normal.
							Say No to bad habits.
								sources of scripts - books, movies, music, friends.
								GIGO - Garbage in garbage out OR good in good out.
									positivity or negativity in and accordingly out.
						Solution 2 - Control senses first (Tortoise and snake)
							withdrawing senses from harmful habits.
							snake fang of impurities removed by chanting.
							tortoise - good things come then welcome. not favorable then withdraw your likes.
						Solution 3 - Choose books, movies, friends carefully to get encouragement in ur good habits.
						Solution 4 - Put aside likes and dislikes chosen by the impure mind. remember GIGO principle.
					Broaden and elevate our consciousness - ishaavaasyam, vasudha eva kutumbakam.
						1 IT guy in 45 asked - are you enjoying ur life - no - how long will you work - maybe till 80.
						How can I control my thoughts, desires, habits
							Functioning of mind - thinking, feeling, willing.
							immediate needs - preyas.
							ultimate goals - shreyas.
							1 reason of being perturbed is thinking only preyas and not shreyas.
							Imagine being recruited by company but can't tell money - won't be happy.
						Levels of happiness - physical, mental, intel, spiritual.
							physical ESMD. few sec.
							Mental - music, arts, poetry, sports. Intox, parties, fashion.
							Intellectural - debate, brain games, wrangling, chess.
							spiritual - not that don't want others.
								unending pleasure for all times to come.
								every moment is pleasure dance.
						Individual tasks - what's special in all animals - ESMD.
							Latest methods of communications - still talking mating and how to enjoy life.
							what's beyond life is purpose of life.
							Why am I suffering - where will I go - like Mahatma Buddha asked.
								Real problems - BODD. BG 13.8-12
								3 fold miseries besides those.
								@Trishul of durga.
								Temporary solutions of BODD - patch up solutions but not permanent solutions.
							Where do I go after this life
								soul in body - soul leaves body drops dead.
								2.22 - soul changes dress so we change body like stages of body.
								Man in different bodies - can be on cycle, bike, car, plane - likewise jivas.
								no dress then nalakuvera manigriva - trees.
								8.6 - soul enters the body to fulfill one's desires.
								every karma has reaction.
								Instant karma.
								Delayed karma.
								good karma, bad karma.
								4 regs breaking vs austerity, sacrifice, knowledge association.
								ABCDE - E for engagement or seva.
					change of heart - greed to satisfaction; cruelty to compassion; arrogance to humility.
						Goal of spiritual life is change of heart.
						Material pleasures are
							changeable and perishable - can't give lasting happiness.
								Stops after sometime - gulabjamun, birthday gifts, picnic, newly wedded couple.
								Not new - chewing gum.
								Limited - How much and how long can we enjoy.
								REL BODD.
							Duality - sukh dukh. They come in combo - person and shadow come together.
								Eg - day-night, life-death, summer winter, pleasure pain, joy sorrow, association separation, etc.
								Eg - marriage, house, car
								REL car but also maintenance.
							Relative - I want better.
								Bike - I want another with better looks.
								Mobile - that has more facilities.
								Position - get more pay and control.
								Possession - house is bigger and better.
								People - Earlier I knew MLA but now CM.
								Penny - slog 4 more hours to get better pay.
								Pleasure - sabda, sparsa, rasa, rupa, gandha.
						Splendor of the sun which dissipates darkness of this whole world comes from me - doesn't charge a penny.
							splendor of moon, edibles, eth supplied by God.
							natural resources - sun, rain, etc.
							knowledge, association, parampara Krishna gives.
						everlasting without dualities with 6 opulence.
					Ultimate goal of human life to be attained.
						Material world is upside down tree of spiritual world.
						Real vs fake - mango, currency, marble, forms (changing and 6 changes)
						@ Jail - Material world, Jailkeeper - maya.
							Food - grains, fruits; medicine - herbs, checked shirt - material body.
							whips - lamentation, illusion, hunger, thirst.
							release - BTG; stay in state - sp world; laws of state - laws of god; PM - God.
						@Independent God - Fish outta water - independent car to enjoy.
							lost son of father.
						@nourish the root, feed the stomach; feed the whole.
							yajna means to act in alignment with God.
					QA
						leaving body so depression - my devs never come back to world. aham+car.
						conscious mind vs subconscious mind - chanting removes sinful reactions but also tendency.
						soul changes form form material world to spiritual world - soul has its own form currently sankucit. Original rupa remains.
						Arjuna applied BG - how should I do - plants to be protected - put fence - 4 regs and association; water - ABCDE; etc.
						why work in temporary world - Krishna in BG how will you earn without work.
							If very rich then can directly work for Krishna.
						Avoid the ego of being in KC - I was also 1 of them. Let me serve.
						My son is angry - Authoritative parent but not authoritarian parent.
							make agreements - polite and firm.
							assertive - not aggressive or passive.
						world validates on material achievement - fear of being tagged as failure in spiritual achievement - Arjuna, Ambarish Prabhu.
						Fearless - soul can't be cut, etc. Godhead but if material desires then heavens and then come back.
							COVID and we came back but even if we die, Krishna promises good birth to continue to serve.
						soul feels suffering without body - soul imagines to be body - in the mind.
							like car - scratch pains.
						overcome depression - smaller and larger picture of life - castle brooken but parents call back it's richer.
						died in covid - depends on how lived his life.
						innate part and parcel so how come back - spark from fire loses its shine - I want to create sth for Krishna.
							proud of creation brahma then comes down.
						COVID for sleep can I try HK - HK MM can calm the mind.
							PMR or shavasan.
						chant without bathing - MM may purify then you will be inspired to bathe and then chant.
						Tulsi mala - 4 regs and onion garlic so we avoid.
						Bad habits not gone - rome was not built in a day - good association. Keep away from tempting situations.
							give spiritual activities.
						Japa bag - mala should not touch ground and many rounds so easy.
						can't focus on japa; is it sinful life in past - it's difficult.
							techniques of concentration.
						path of soul is predetermined then why ghost - vulnerable points in jyotish then murdered, killed, etc.
							fate or free will.
						tulsi mala - win their heart and then without onion garlic then you can wear tulsi mala.
							after marriage then you can - if spouse is a devotee.
				</SelfDiscipline>
				<SelfRespect>
				Episode 5: Self-Respect – recognizing your unique potential (seven types of intelligence)
				Self Respect - recognizing your unique potential
					Quotes
						God created you; you are what you are. learn to love it, live it.
							All species are gifted - you don't have to prove to anybody.
							You are special. God's creation is perfect.
							E1's a star and deserves the right to twinkle.
							Krishna's attention to Yashoda and loves.
							Every gopi gets unique attention, Krishna carries sandals for father.
							Krishna attends to e1 in govardhan lila.
							Einstein - fish would think it is stupid cuz it can't climb the tree.
							Identify your natural inclination - BKVS.
								Teacher - RnD
								Administrators - Admin
								Traders - Fin team.
								Artisans or labors - Labors.
								More - training as per your mindset and self respect for that.
								Spiritual world e1 has self respect.
						Your value doesn't decrease based on 7's inability to see your worth.
							Genuine love blesses you with self respect.
							Fake love rusts; genuine love doesn't (love and trust that never rusts)
							I am wanted, protected.
							Lust vs love
								Lust - what can he or she do for me.
								Love - flows outward selflessly.
								Eg - Multi-millionaire's madness for a hollywodd actress.
									huge money. Good looking but no chastity.
									finish him off and get his money.
									2 body guards and not trust.
								Mundane love is simply attraction for skin color, face cut, bodily shape.
								Love qualities
									Love implies service, not just feeling without service.
										Eg - Gajendra, Bilvamangal, charioteer Krishna.
									Love is voluntary - Jagannath rath cleaning, boss forcing subordinate.
									Love is selfless, lust is selfish.
										Competition and exploitation become the norm - killing finer human instincts.
											key to good career.
											Got to get better grades.
											I'll prove myself.
										God centered civilization - all exchanges based on mood of service with full consideration of other's feelings.
											Relationships and welfare of others is given more importance than economic or material advancement.
										King Gaya's rule - PDS, full protection and security, sufficient food, distribute gifts, call meetings with citizens. good instructions.
											SB 5.15.7
										Selflessness is built in god's creation
											Tree, cow's milk, pearls, agriculture. Sun, moon freely.
											digestive system, temple, universe.
									Love involves sacrifice and pain - satisfaction of the beloved.
										Labor of love in cooking for my family.
										vs when individuals are only interested in gratifying the senses eth becomes machine line.
										no patience to cook and no time. Have to go to gym.
									Love is free from unrealistic expectations.
										Bridge forming - no force. Vs boss in corporate.
									Love means respecting and valuing individuality.
										not pay attention to me.
										values their gift.
											similarly for children, etc.
										Trust vs rust
											Krishna and Sudama vs Drona and Drupada.
											Krishna and Arjuna vs Karna and Shalya.
									Love means unconditional in all situations.
										Vibhishan.
									Love means tolerance and forgiveness.
										Putana forgiven.
									Love means security - support, shelter, pleasure - Jatayu.
								Hotel - where is trust required.
									marriage, doctor, business partnership.
						Don't compare yourself with others; if you do so you are insulting yourself.
							Learn that healthy competition that can boost your self respect and help you work successfully in a team.
							Story - Rabbit and Tortoise.
								Slow and story wins the race. Rabit wins cuz doesn't rest.
								Involve river based tortoise wins. Only land rabit wins.
								Situational leadership.
								Collaborated and won together.
								Both individually brilliant and have strong core competencies.
								work in a team and harness each other's core competencies.
								Situational leadership - let tortoise lead in water and rabbit on land.
									All fingers can work together.
						The better you feel about yourself, the less  you feel the need to show off.
							No1 wants to get old. Cosmetic industry is flourishing due to fear of old age.
							suicide on first white hair - that's not right.
						False Ego is negative but self respect or esteem is positive.
							Kasturi searches for fragrance that's with itself.
							The opinion which other people have is their problem, not yours.
							Squirrel to mountain in Rig veda - If I am not so large as you, you are not so small as I.
								I can't carry forest on my back and neither can you crack a nut like me.
							Hanuman glorifies Lord Ram and didn't care for Ravan's opinion
						The opinion which other people have is their problem and not yours.
							he has gone to USA - but I have devotee spouse and parents have company; all visit temple.
						Our self respect tracks our choices. Et we act in harmony with our authentic self and heart, we earn our respect. It's that simple. Every choice matters.
						Character - the willingness to accept responsibility for one's own life - is the source from which self respect springs.
					Spiritual quotes
						Lord Krishna is original supplying source of all our beauties and powers.
						Lord Krishna, your supreme well-wisher has made you unique.
						Identify your unique potentials and live in alignment with his will.
						Lord Krishna, your supreme wellwisher has made you unique. Identify your unique potential and live in alignment with his will.
					Krishna bestower of 7 intelligence
						About - Krishna has all of them.
							Acronym SLIMBIL
						Spatial or Visual - Picture Smart eg - artist.
						Linguistic - Word Smart eg poet.
							Krishna uses different languages with different jivas.
						Inter-personal - People Smart eg - socializing.
						Musical - Music Smart. Eg - musicians for raag, taal.
						Bodily kinesthetics (Physical) - Body Smart eg - sports, athlete.
						Intra-personal - Self Smart. Eg - self aware and contemplative or philosophical.
							contemplative, can stay with books, etc.
						Logical or Mathematical - Logic Smart. Eg - Mathematician.
							Fibonacci series for the world.
						Extra - Aligned with nature - nature smart.
						More - identify your talents. Why compare fish with monkey - they are unique in talents.
							Be grateful for your gifts.
					Krishna is source
						List
							I am taste of water.
							I am light and heat of sun.
							I am source of light of moon.
							I am omkar.
							shabda khe - sound in ether.
							I am ability in man.
							I give fragrance to eaerth, heat to fire.
							I supply food for 8.4 million species of life.
							I inspire ascetics with ability to perform austerities.
							seed giving father.
							I intelligence of intelligent. Prowess of powerful.
							spark of my splendor - all vibhutis - opulent, beauty, glory.
						This means all greatness were gifts from Krishna.
					Body we travel but soul is inside but body based tensions - white hair.
						after attaining me never come back world.
						Asato ma sadgamaya.
						boosted self respect cuz world is like moth running for fire - why worry.
						aligned with God then belong with him - self respect - whole world validation no more required cuz Lord is with us.
						Like mother allows accept peda so child accepts.
					QA
						Even 1 intel is enough - no minmax.
							effortlessly, others notice in you, you have attraction.
						Identify god gifted talent - self awareness exercise.
						Good habits to wake up early - gotta sleep early then can wake up.
						Comfort zone out for service - nth wrong to be attracted to a specific service.
							come out of service in which we are very successful - menial services for humility.
						Feeling of luxury life - use body as springboard for spiritual body.
							accept facilities but not involved in SG
							I am custodian of this money and doesn't go with me - Ford Pr.
						origin of HK MM
							Narad - Kaliyuga people minds are dull and disturbed, Brahma says Kali for HK MM.
							Kali sant taran upanishad - cross over kali ocean.
						How to pratice your tips - simple sessions.
							ppt will be made available.
							how to apply is the question.
						proud of talent a bad thing?
							ability is given by Krishna.
							eye can we be proud - sun or lamp dependence.
							grateful.
						false ego and true ego
							jivera svarupa Krishnera nitya das.
							False ego - get rid of false ego but true ego has to be known.
						I wanna preach but people restrict it to religious beliefs - sun can be called different people.
							SP books are best books.
						Serve lord with living life to fullest
							Good delicious prasadam, singers, darshan, dance, dramas, etc.
							Engineer then flourish in the field like Arjuna did.
							chhodana nahi jodna hai.
						work till 12 then how brahma muhurta - choose new situation where don't need to work that much like work in shift.
						mind trouble can't sleep - then chant loudly.
							venkatesh suprabhatam - some time for sattvik session.
						continuous comparison - different talents.
						should be early age - better late then never.
				</SelfRespect>
				<QnA>
					QnA is a shastik practice and helps 1 step in increment of wisdom and clarification of doubts.
					Tulsi mala with Onion garlic - HK MM is first priority; even 4 regs come later.
						favorable later then you can wear - tolerate it.
					spouse is non-devotee then what to do - good qualities should win the other person.
					Feel bad when going against parents wishes - good principles don't know where to go.
						actions now create future body - accountable for ur karma. Next life different body and relations.
						strengthen your convictions - your relatives don't have to be like us.
					Devotee vs PDS - vaidhi, raganuga, bhav, prema.
					ego grows when close to guru - Krishna will purify our pride.
					why don't e1 surrender to Krishna - they want to be independent.
					bumble bee dies in lotus and can't penetrate cuz intoxicated so engage riches in God's service.
					why instant pleasure - cuz of association.
					Family man right rate of progress - family, career and spiritual.
						short term and long term - crisis management, steady state maintenance and expansion program.
					balance spiritual life and college - can't do both same time - morning for Krishna and evening for studies formula.
						jet age gurukul or voice.
					balance spiritual and personal life - balance the 2.
					Why can't girls live without marriage.
						We don't recommend to marry or not - that's individual choice.
						take responsibility for whatever you do.
						Any choice it can go wrong so make conscious choice.
					There is only 1 man in the universe that's Krishna. Why discrimination in material world.
						16 year old boy can travel throughout world but girl can't do that cuz physically weak and can be exploited unfortunately.
						Woman should be protected physically by father, son, brother, husband, etc.
						Emotional and rational - general psychology. Firm decision and soft decision making.
						Spiritually equal and no difference.
					No attachment and ignorant then stone hearted Woman
						men and women both can have it - Krishna chastises Arjuna in BG starting.
						Kunti M had affection for sons but spiritualized them so should we.
						Give them gift of KC.
					Can girl take sanyas and stay in vrindavan.
						No, very risky. 3-4 girls together can.
					Not getting respected.
						Making you feel useless - avoid such people.
						Associate with cheerful friendly respectful people.
						If family, then can't stay away then do needful.
						how can we earn her respect.
					Feel aged cuz of stress - can visit temple.
					QnA we do for people, give books - what undue advantage can people take from us.
						stole books - fortunate thief - he will read and get benefitted SP said.
					purpose of human life - drop in mud - purpose of life is glorify God and go back.
					Why religion or god - thirst then need water.
						can company be without CEO - so many people, 1 leader.
						love is last word in transcendence - in God we find it best.
						love self, family, nation, world, jivas then God. Love God, Love all.
					A teases B and B can be teased by C not necessarily A - not endless small cycle.
					Why soul punished for bodily related karma - kurta punched you not me - I who chooses.
						kurta is dead. Likewise matter is moved by spirit.
						soul carries karma to next body if unsettled.
					experiencing karma or inviting karma
						careful in this world - other jivas give stimuli.
						Respond consciously. Not overdo.
					About to die in 10 mins - Chant HK.
						he Ram when Gandhi dying. So, in devotee family.
					business doesn't need acads - give them basic education at least; they should not complain.
						choose schools with good values.
					BG of significance for passing away - yes nakshatra can be important.
						chanted HK then blessed. If connected to devotee then also good situation for her next life.
					tempted by social media - keep it away for attentive japa.
					Haridas called Namacarya but not Ganga mata goswamini - why?
						Name was given by LCM - Ganga mata came later - not that every 192 chanter should be called so.
						others also and even today - we do what SP has taught us.
					HK MM - LAG anarthas and then affects my relationships, etc so HK MM claims mind properly.
						greed by need, anger by sensitive behavior.
					NKY - seva for God.
						BKVS all results to Krishna.
						help preaching activities.
						Dravya yajna - physical things like ghats.
						tapo yajna - sacrifices like wake up early.
						svadhyaya yajna, etc.
						BG 4.24 - 33
					What to do in situ like Arjuna
						ask devs or professionals.
						dharma and religious principles - can ask devs.
					Make society better place to live
						fights continue to exist - cut throat competition.
						subdue others this tendency needs to be cured.
						bee buzzing and all birds stopped to listen to it.
					Other countries have books but not India - cuz India needs people like him.
						eb chooses this topics only.
					Losses of the past - only depression from past; learn lessons.
						look at the road ahead now.
					Stop overthinking about competition
						distraction from goal - don't divert attention.
						who will push me down. How many others are doing.
						have regulated lifestyle.
						have 7-8 items to do in a day.
					BG but getting diverted - concentrate towards KC
						can have some performance like shloka recitation.
					don't forgive then relationship is finished.
						forgiven are those who forgive.
					attentive in service - putting cement, making wall, making temple for Krishna.
						more book reading helps.
						vrata or vow - full attention to 1 thing at a time.
					don't offer to Krishna - eat with guilt.
						offer to Krishna on altar and then thanks thru mahaprasade govinde.
						May look like picture but Lord of the universe.
				</QnA>
				Episode 6: Self-Reliance – from dependence to freedom (Depend on Lord or take reins on hand)
				Episode 7: Overcoming inferiority complex (Release steam by self-esteem)
				Episode 8: Overcoming superiority complex (overcoming false pride)
				Episode 9: Abundance Mentality and Freedom from Insecurity (rise above competition and insecurity)
				Episode 10: Art of Thinking Win Win (from Mahabharata)
			</PersonalityDevelopment>
			<Prerana>
				About - Reference Material for further learning.
				The secret of life balance
					Extremes that Bharat (Bhar) and Lakshman were subject to by Lord himself.
					Learning how they endured can help us balance our life also - scripture based conduct.
					Bharat - Misunderstood always. Lakshman - Wife says you wanted to enjoy and husband says you are not competent.
				Overcoming distraction
					Stats - so many claim to be distracted at work.
						once in 12 mins. So, be merciful during the session.
						On forever - satatam kirtayanto maam.
						5 years online - this is not included by prahlad M.
						can't focus for more than 11 mins.
					Improve attitude and health thru spirituality - foundation of foundation.
						Eg - All motivational quotes is what spirituality is for.
						Success is moving from failure to failure without losing enthusiasm.
						Competence can be taught at school but character.
					Hack into chemicals thru multimedia - natural sources get compromised.
						can your control this yelling person thru power of your mantra - I am controlling myself with this mantra.
						Distracted so ability to experience happiness has reduced.
					Choice architecture - social scientist - create ambience that distraction is difficult - don't get put into ambience externally.
						focus on strengths and take some breaks for inventory.
						Bombarded by what others are doing - problem in identity crisis.
						Best years of my life spent in arms of 1 who was not my wife - my mother so not scandalous.
							another imitating forgot what second line was.
						In Kali yuga we must have some time for solitude.
					Talents and utilize potentials - for mind, only events not enough
						it's event + expectation creates emotion and experience.
						also need resilience.
						Mind has impression and loop of action, impression and proposition continues.
						Solution is positive cycle for the same.
						Congratulations to all of you.
					Situations then emotion then devotion - latter then e1 seen as orchestration of Krishna.
						We are diverted by dualities - my success and failure but success is in absorption on Krishna.
						raising this is what every meditation does.
						Every situation in life is preparation for death.
						Like business - happiness and distress comes but money should be made EOQ. So with Life.
					When you make other's life blissful then life salutes you.
					QA -
						But social harassment and all
							admin of society - governing bodies take care of deviation.
							What we do here is cope with them internally.
							Give up thinking I can't do it - we help people overcome that.
							May lose kingdom, influence - refuses to lose hope is successful.
							Eg - Ekadashi Monkey fasting. Worry takes us nowhere.
							Live life to give purpose - Vasudev kept positive after losing 6 sons
								ready to endure pain and Krishna left to give pleasure to Nanda M.
						Relapse happens afterwards
							When answerable to 7, the connection gives you strength.
							Association of devs like wind - can carry away anything with it.
							As insect, take shelter of Flower like devs and offerable to Krishna.
						How to make man friend - man ki key is to cure monkey and man ki key is mantra - free the mind.
						SP - can't reach moon in this body. So, why waste money that govt does.
							if we get opportunity we will go to distribute books - transformation is our focus.
							Beyond the scope of current discussion but can connect you to 7.
							Distracted by what others are doing - focus on your circle of infuence then circle of concern later.
							SP was preaching to western youths so presented aptly.
							You read directory book and chanting holy names - sudama bars outside.
							some place of pilgrimage around. But no such facility other places.
							We can't launch missile or satellites so let's launch campaign against bad habits.
							run small institution is difficult - appreciation when you see them manage country - impossible feat.
							In India we don't need more commentators but more players.
							Sitting in room and say what he is playing I would have hit sixer but we would run away seeing baller run to us.
			</Prerana>
		</EBG>
        <BrahmacariLife> lifestyle until one changes the ashram
		Abstract
			Application - Student life of learning spirituality as personal foundation.
        GS - Detachment inducing Talks - focus on temporary nature and Harsh truths - self centered-ness of eb vs spiritual paradigm, etc.
            Syllabus can jotted down but nothing more is intended to be done here.
            There is a possibility of jotting generic etiquette and culture here - which is general - cuz grihasth ashram spawns from this phase.
			Vaishnava Training and Education Manual
			VTW Course, VMML.
        </BrahmacariLife>
        <GrihasthaLife>
		Abstract
			Application - Cultivate Sanskars thru proper understanding and practice.
        NS - Refer my google drive (nitjsr and vitpune shared) for content.
            <B2G>
                ...
            </B2G>
            <Attitude>
                About - Introduction (attitudes and mind map)
                TODO
                    Detox; Grihasthas vs Grihamedhi; ?Vedic View - Boat.
                    attitudes to VA and relp
                    Maturity
                Misc
                    Sanctity - dharma patni - dharma dvara vivahit.
                    Ashram is sadhan. Means shelter or complete effort.
                    envt for mood and do at best. Bhakti not at theater. Bath in kitchen, dining in bathroom.
                    No thanks or sorry - for granted, apna hi hai na but still an individual.
                    not prove duhkhalayam but offer sukh. World lacks good eg. First class philosophy but bad eg ppl put off.
                    Harmonious relp - lack of peace, children disservice. Cold war. Affects every aspect of life - can't focus on work.
                        Health affected,
                        shadi kyun karen - forget leave after shadi; first gotta tell do marriage.
                        no sanctity ppl think - some are still happy - daivi VA - God centered.
                        divorce and stress greater if not religious centered bond.
                        loving, respect, accepting as it is, accommodating, setting right eg for children, clean life.
                        altar at home. Protection so marriage for ladies - distractions at certain age so why window shopping.
                        not married ppl take to mean still available.
                Sankirtan Rasa Prabhu - Grihasta Ashram Seminar - Preparation for Perfect Grihasta Ashram by Sankirtanras Prabhu
                    Principles can't be broken
                        @warship captain - warning lighthouse to tilt else hit - captain asks lighthouse to shift.
                        principles you hit - no prob to them - we get affected.
                        seeing each other at marriage and not even name and face - gotta realize soul - eternal timespan and adjust for 60 yrs.
                        stabbing pain - surgeon paid - benefits. sue for other.
                        changing job cuz other's plate vs I have eth but lesser.
                    Svadharma important
                        I could have come 10 yrs b4 then brahmacari - blissful, recreation and creation.
                            better ur svadharma improperly than other's.
                        fire has smoke - every effort has some fault. Digestion and fire kills microbes but must be done.
                        Jiva thinks doer but MMN - fix faults on 7's head or ourselves - it's MMN.
                            being sad and make others happy - can't go on.
                            Hindi - meri padhai ho gayi. I finished studies. I am responsible for studies.
                            I must be small for grihasthashram.
                    Kali yuga qualities - always disturbed, etc. Quarrelsome. Lazy.
                        Vangbhatt lived for 137 and died cuz of fasting - 2mro work > today. We like lesser work 2mro.
                        don't blame person but kali but not misuse - kali so why satisfied with just you.
                        just see a person for a minute and he would say kya hai be.
                        Boiling - Milk, pot, fire - effect, reason, cause.
                            not by heart - pot is means or nimitta. fire is karma. we forget we are soul so when what wrong - who knows.
                    we break all laws of ashrams. old age and hospital is modern narka.
                        current situ - a-brahmacharya, teen age mothers, live in relationships, single parents, division of elderly, lonely oldage.
                        single parent caused by divorce also.
                        divisions of labor for parents like baghban.
                        Rights and responsibilities - shrink and grow resp with age or ashram.
                        piss in childhood no problem. Cry 7 comes; cleaning our shit.
                        urinary incontinence of old - chastised.
                        oldies more respect if do something social - only TV then nothing.
                        n-1 rights - you take care of e1's rights except ur own and your will be taken care by n-1.
                    Steps in social development of the person
                        brahmacarya - vyaktigat - personal.
                            Personal devp - as a person - not personality as showing what I am not but characteristics development or as a person - tolarance, humility, etc.
                        Grihastha - samashtigat - interpersonal.
                            Interpersonal - with max ppl and also with wife.
                        Vanaprastha - Srishtigat - Universal.
                            Universal - can think of cleaning colony. Grihastha can't think of not using plastic.
                        Sanyas - Parameshtigat - Spiritual.
                    Paths of developments
                        Brahmacarya - Tapasya - austerities.
                            austerities as student then better performance.
                        Grihastha - Santulan - Balance.
                            balance of office and work; kids and wife, etc.
                        Vanaprastha - Seva - service.
                            respect if service centered.
                        Sanyas - Samarpan - Surrender.
                    MB - worship mother, father, fire, guru, soul stays happy in this world and next.
                        shreyas or preyas but simultaneous is rare.
                    Purpose of human life
                        Freedom from sins
                        Enquiry about self
                        Freedom from karma
                        freedom from 3 debts
                        moksh (freedom from BODD cycle)
                        Love Krishna
                    Grihasthashram Definition thru etymology
                        Home vs building - griha vs vastu - relationships vs flats. That's how we start.
                            Griha - Ghar - home and not just mere building.
                        Stha - sthita - staying in or resident of.
                        Ashram - Ashray or aa + shram.
                            for protection, for executing responsibilities.
                        Defn - It is a system that helps human being to evolve to the ultimate goal of human life by satisfying all 3 debts
                            and by following all 4 purusharth under protection of family and society.
                    Glories of Grihasthashram - oh I came here - good maybe but unsuccessful if think so - right thing to do.
                        Wanted to be celibate but couldn't - then lost.
                        MB - As small and big rivers take support of the sea - all ashrams depend on grihasthashram.
                        how will others sustain - also in atharva veda.
                        sanskars for the ashram should be there else you stay as man animal.
                    Characteristics
                        right to earn livelihood.
                        Right to store as security - gotta donate and depend on krishna for next day celibates.
                        Right to enjoy under social and spiritual code (dharma aviruddha kaam) - dharma is what behoves society - don't disturb anyone else.
                        responsibility of 3 ashrams.
                    3 debts - b4 complete surrender we have debts but full surrender doesn't.
                        as beginner we serve eb and exalted anyways serves eb.
                    Dharma - focus on grihasthashram here
                        Brahmacarya dharma is follow guru anyways and guru has the onus.
                        Grihastha dharma - nice care of wife but not old parents or not kids or bad business or no taxes to govt - so many faces to be ideal.
                            @Sugar - Dharma - means nature, attribute, duty
                                Tongue - sweet; For water - soluble, for eyes - colorless crystals, for diabetic - poison.
                                sugar is relative - it is natural synergistic state developed by maturing mutual relations.
                                chastise children and may seem cruel but gotta do it.
                                so like sugar grihasthashram has so many faces to qualify.
                                not bad sugar or good sugar for seeing a face.
                                synergistic - for both not 1. Natural - not forced. Wife doing business and maid from jhopadpatti taking care of child and hence sanskars.
                                    maturing with time.
                        Dharma as responsibility or duties.
                            duty towards husband wife
                            duty towards parents
                            kids, family traditions, caste, society, country, humanity, universe, caste.
                        3 debts
                            dev rin - debt towards higher powers.
                                dev take little and give a lot. danav - takes a lot and repay little.
                                Repay - by DS, respecting demigods and natural powers.
                            rishi rin - debt towards sages and rishis.
                                meagre life but such great science for others.
                                all acaryas of past like sushrut, aryabhatt, veda vyas, etc.
                                Repay - By devp any knowledge stream and hand it over to next generation and society.
                                    so study it; add your experience to it and give back to society.
                            pitri rin - debt towards ancestors.
                                good training and lots.
                                Repay - by becoming excellent parents and create and devp ideal descendants.
                        Join Grihasthashram for repaying these debts not SG - of course that's a part of it.
                            breakups - less salary but ego probs.
                        Different stages in householder's life
                            Entrance - Vivah Samskar
                            Couple - Husband Wife resp
                            Adhijanan - Prep of parenting
                            Samskara - from birth to 5 yrs of life
                            Anushasan - Age of child between 5 to 15 yr
                            Mitracharan - From 16th yr till marriage
                            Vanprastha Mindset - After marriage of children
                        Purpose of marriage - in manu smriti
                            To have children, perform religious and social services, have sex life based on religious principles.
                            upgrade ancestors and oneself to higher planetary systems.
                        Blessings given in convocation ceremony (shikshavalli)
                            Satyam vada - always speak truth
                            dharmam chara - always follow dharma
                                simple defn don't interrupt other's interest in ur enjoyment.
                            matri devo bhava - respect mother as representative of god.
                                7 mothers you know.
                            pitri devo bhava - respect father as representative of god.
                            acharya devo bhava - respect eg teacher as representative of god.
                                not guru actually - married and not sanyasi but teachers.
                            atithi devo bhava - respect guest as representative of god.
                            svadhyaynma pramditavyam - don't be proud of knowledge.
                            prajatantu ma vyavachhetasi - don't discontinue the lineage.
                    QA - Little high standard
                        Excuses are there. Even if true. At least in my case - very sincerely you say it - not incapable but tough.
                        little steps to right thing - yogkshema vahami aham.
                        keep ego away. Adjustments are required. Know svadharma - not others opinions about me but mine.
                        Lord doesn't take resp of your head - but our problem - we do sakaam bhakti. Lord helps st but not to be looked.
                        3 things increase automatically if not resolved timely - loan, disease and doubts.
                        They come closer cuz of you - and fights also cuz of you.
                        You gotta balance and ensure good relp between the 2 - mistake then make them realize also.
                        make her understand time to time - you also get children. If both grihastha then double dose.
                        Ego kept aside - new bride needs time - thakur ke seva mein ahankar kyun.
                        Any fight then you gotta say that it's not ok - if not speaking anything then also problem.
                        you fella fight, what's my mistake.
            </Attitude>
            <Varna>
                About - Varna (work life)
                TODO
                    Financial planning, livelihood
                    Living vs revolution
            </Varna>
            <Ashram>
                About - Ashram (relationships) - different natures
                TODO
                    Mars vs Venus. World of Family.
            </Ashram>
            <Selection>
                About - Selection
                TODO
                    What to look for in life partner; marriage board.
                Vedic View - Selecting a right partner
                    Ref - Grihasta Ashram Seminar - Preparation for Perfect Grihasta Ashram by Sankirtanras Prabhu
                    so many concepts from western and indian books but I will give from vedic books
                    duty of girls father
                        spiritual credits of kanyadaan.
                            price-tags / brands vs values
                                REL raymonds brand but wearable in winter or summer don't ask. tight or loose.
                            considerations during marriage proposal vs reasons for divorce.
                            parameters of gratification vs parameters for relation.
                            short term gains vs long term progress.
                            Finding right boy is a resp - so kanyadaan blessings.
                            We check price tags - education, salary, flat, car, foreign how many times, settling plans in USA, single child - all the money. Pride in parties.
                            Divorce cuz losing jobs or no flat - less heard. So, questions asked b4 marriage are all the wrong questions.
                            parakram in man - history of boy - price he has paid and rupa for stri - not beauty but dealings - soft spoken, e1 wants to be around.
                        why parents and not children - we do most of things to calm the mind instead of mature decision.
                            issues come later and difficult to resolve them.
                    Qualities of bride groom
                        jnanai - knowing vedic principles of life. Intel, Wise (different between vidya and jnana)
                            vidya means knowledge to survive in this material world. jnani means apply knowledge for spiritual purpose also.
                        brahmacari - by action, speech and thoughts.
                        youth - right age
                        manhood - can fulfill all the resp
                        kul - family lineage
                        sheel - character
                        sharir - health, no diseases
                        vitta - financial stability
                        smmapannata - earning ability, prosperity.
                        anurupata - physical match.
                            average looks should marry to average looks else 80% times worried about others should not look at my wife in wrong ways.
                            chanakya - too much beautiful wife is also an enemy
                    Disqualifications
                        no inclination for charity and righteousness
                        non-vegetarian
                        hypocritical and hard hearted
                        cheat and with loose character
                        bald and with white hair
                        suffering from infectious and incurable diseases
                        wasting time in decorating externally
                        with weak eyesight - long vision of life. not daru now and later we see.
                        with corrupt mentality
                        having long hairs
                    Qualities of bride - sequence also taken as given in vedas (important)
                        jnani - knowing vedic principles of life
                        young
                        age should be less than that of bridegroom
                        with full of feminity
                        virgin - ananyapurvika, aprishtamaithura, akshatyoni.
                            like boy be brahmacari
                        beautiful - hansvani gajagamini, meghvarni vishalnetri.
                            sweet voice - pleasing not like crow shouting; like elephant - can lift child;
                            redding blackish than white - anemia otherwise. broad vision also not physical eyes.
                        kul - family lineage and etiquette
                        affectionate behavior
                        having a brother
                            pind daan to 1 gotra
                    Disqualifications
                        Having legs of deer - flickering mind, unstable.
                        having teeth like bull - over eater
                            how atithi devo bhava will happen.
                        moving like a cow - very slow in every action, lazy
                        short tempered
                            atom bomb in house - groom is still ok but bride is dangerous.
                        always want to look better externally
                            this can cosmetic industry badly - simple makeup is ok but hours in front.
                            boys won't see mirror and girls also.
                        sick
                        with problems of reproductive system
                        name is based on river, mountain or nakshatra
                            those times names given by forest dwellers - so as to remember. Does not apply now.
                        having no brother
                        unknown mother and father.
                    Selecting a right partner
                        Gotra, pinda, pravara consideration
                        Match making based on horoscope
                        Kundli kuta - max points
                        varna - 1
                        vasya - 2
                        tara or dina
                        yoni
                        grah maitri or rasyadipati
                        gana - 6
                        rashi - 7
                        nadi - 8
                    Devotee non-devotee consideration
                        As per BG 12.13-19 verse
                        quality of good devotee - yo me bhakta sa me priyah
                        non envious - kind friend to all
                        free from false ego - equipoise
                        tolerant, always satisfied, self controlled, determination, mind and intel fixed on me,
                        pure, not disturbed by anyone, expert, without cares.
                        problem comes when we think of devotee as a brand instead of value as discussed b4.
                            qualities are important.
                            LCM - person taken HN once is dev. SP - my disciples are gentlemen.
                            Consciousness matters more than externals. Devotee and non-devotee poroposals are respected and scrutinised equally.
                            Dev should be value and not mere price-tag or brand.
                        every day introspection is necessary - what to look for.
                How to choose Life Partner | Life Coaching With Namita Purohit
                    Part1 - Life partner choosing
                    sacred bandhan, arranged-love
                    16 yrs so much prep but for life we don't do any home work - read articles on tinder and Jeevansaathi.
                    Parents also useful that how to check - lots of changes in current times - so many facilities vs Ramayan parampara - what's vedic insight.
                    Marriage purpose - seasons and clothes; attitudes also.
                        lesser difficulties in life if we stay to original - if change with time - MOP and MOI like these days. So, better see with MOG - happiness.
                        My enjoyment - my needs and interests; enjoy and do nothing MOI. Duty and service consciousness is necessary.
                        Goal of life is God so elevate each other for spiritual focus.
                        Protect each other and take care of needs of each other.
                        SG in dharmik way. This is 1 goal not only goal.
                        procreate.
                        support all other ashrams.
                        pitron ka dhyan bhi.
                    Qualities - bank balance, family size, etc.
                        we try understand and ppl do change over time.
                        If only SG, then infatuation possible.
                        Nature match - bungee jumping I don't wanna do - language, nature - movies show they come together and happy but lots happen inside.
                        compatibility and respect are most important.
                        first gotta understand yourself and others.
                    Unhealthy relp reasons
                        when ppl are unhealthy.
                        prem hai but don't talk with love - need satisfied so radar don't see other things - infatuation so forget to see other things that should have.
                        psychological needs exploited.
                        marriage ain't between 2 unhealthy ppl but 2 healthy ppl making each other better. Heal each also.
                    Should we depend on arranged marriage
                        more experience and take advantage from parents.
                        even arranged how much do parents get to see - education, job, healthy family, earning, good looks.
                        So only needs or SG elements are only seen. Still same problem as love infatuation.
                        Karma philosophy, God philosophy reqd - probs come anyways in couple after compatibilities - guys be mature.
                        So education for purpose is more important.
                        Why pitri - don't do and have consequences.
                    Caste system - should we go for it
                        mappings - physical, cultural and mental.
                        cultural - eating, lifestyle and dealings in and outside family
                        No in love it doesn't matter - it does south indian told to eat only chapattis - can't carry on.
                        castes map to MMN - intellectual pursuits, desire and action and admin;
                        MOI - enjoyment and not responsibility taking.
                        caste maps to our physical element also - 5 bhoot elements also differences - even child procreation becomes difficult.
                        caste is diluted but not entirely - high low is not worth commenting right now.
                    horoscope
                        jyoti shastra - put light on life thru lights of star on your life.
                        which astrologer you refer is important.
                        astrologer also sees what ppl focus so only enjoyment.
                        Ask specific questions - how good for pitras, etc.
                        36 guna seen; what are those. reproduction is ok, etc. Physically and healthy child.
                        Child health affects marriage.
                        maitri - nature; nakshatra; nadi for child and yoni - reproduction compatibility.
                        vasha - leadership who takes.
                        spiritual focus can be understood.
                        even understand my nature. If not given in past, then karma affected in next life. Pashchattap.
                    Not astrology beliefs
                        this is scientific - sun on head it affects us; depressed if lesser; clothes, etc.
                        Moon also we understood - chandani raten, mind effect lunar and lunatic;
                        grah - grahan kar lete hain.
                        Planetary influence on body book.
                            disease increased in certain constellation.
                            same birth with same cities and dates - similar problems; 200 pairs they studied.
                            farmers - harvest as per nature
                            females hormones with nature.
                        epigenetic and gene expression.
                        rejecting is easy - so just evaluate not just follow fashion unthinkingly.
                    How to be ourselves what other is looking for
                        understand yourself - ayurved, feedback and horoscope.
                        every one has limitations. Learn from others.
                            eg - pregnant girl can be guided by a mother.
                        My needs and goals - spiritual focus.
                        Prayers are important - not enough I try my best but may fall short.
                    Material world problems
                        no promise that enjoyment after marriage.
                        commitment to service to each other, others and service to God.
                        blessings from all - demigods, parents when we marry. Invitees are all for blessings.
                        commitment withdrawn may have karmik consequences.
                        maturity gotta be increased.
                        Sita and Ram - after marriage only probs. Ramji world war after wife abducted. health problems in our case is equivalent of abduction in our case.
                        nala damayanti story narrated to convey that I tell story of person with more difficulties than you.
                        seva => more responsiblity. Probs come - can I face probs with him. No1 forced to marry on gunpoint so take responsibility.
                    QA - high divorce rate so fear. How to find suitable partner and how to find ppl with enjoyment.
                        have patience. Study all divorces and don't follow their patterns and selection criteria which caused divorce.
                        don't marry cuz lonely. qualify yourself.
                        Some HK and ISKCON - only focus spiritual and not other factors - nature compatibility is important.
                        Both have spiritual focus but not whole individuals.
                        When there is shadow there is also real thing.
                    Education with marriage compatibility
                        Varna and ashram interaction is the question.
                        profession demands, also in time and mutual respects.
                        compatibility helped by these.
                        kardam muni asks Vishnu for compatible wife.
                        Devahuti - quality, svabhav, achievement equality helps compatiblity.
                    Bad astrologer?
                        Informed decisions taking. but karma is bad then difficulties come nevertheless.
                        The session just make things better but probs freedom ain't happening.
                        Do best and leave rest.
                    manglik - I ain't astrologer. So gotta check with them. Health probs with them.
                    Neither marriage, nor brahmacari
                        purpose of marriage - protect ourselves is one of them.
                        rule based envt helps us do that - sanyasis etc do it without.
                        Mind wants MOG but easily affected by MMN around us.
                        structured routine and engagements - throughout so plan is chalked out
                        No ashram or like minded ppl - this path his somewhat undesirable cuz difficult.
                        We have masculine and feminine energy - dry otherwise and balance thru the other.
                        focus will go away - we have needs and desires so will get affected.
                        Prescribed duties regulate our mind.
                        2 yr you live and you will get insights but in general it is required.
                        relatives are to be taken care of.
                    How to check a dev or potential devotee
                        If spouse not spiritual inclined - as you serve, you will elevate.
                        first let us grow and try to search in right place
                        spiritual inclinations thru discussions, astrology and guru.
                        Our duty is to serve them irrespective we are dev or not - our dharma.
                    parents separated so how search parents
                        be spiritually strong. Mind works tricks - want a partner then marriage board. Ask sb even websites also.
                        take ur time.
                    how to make or devp sp partners
                        we will change eb - partner gets terrified always behind me.
                        ur personal qualities will be more attractive to them.
                        LCM - Krishna in Radharani's bhav - more happy.
                    How much patience if not right person meeting as per mindset.
                        Mindset and time - if can find a trade off then doable but if not, better be alone and have patience - don't marry cuz of age factor.
                        Loneliness or mindset tradeoff.
                    Livin relp and for bhakti and lost in material world.
                        HK TV - topics. Marriage ain't trial and error - exchanges psych and energy connection
                        try and test it out - so much divorce so better try it out.
                        rin bandhans come - not married but those things come.
                        break up session is there on HK.
                        fear of another partner - clean and purifying yourself. What's in your control - focus on that.
                        as friend and well wisher - bhakti rules and regs easy else difficult - rules and regs are principles of freedom. 4 regs - breaking 1 of them are unfavorable for DS.
                        don't judge choices so connected to astrologer - all details - as soon - aura, energy and intuition - seeing her said that your relp anti to DS, do prayashchit.
                    Can't focus on study cuz of parental fights
                        moving city ain't easy. language, culture, electricity - all of these are challenging.
                        challenges - which one to deal with.
                        too many unknowns ain't good in life.
                        no1 convinces other - only healthy dialogue is possible. Feels attacked.
                        don't give emotional presentation, logically present - if emotional then jot down.
                        covid increased fight ew.
                    Not willing to marry; push from family so as to get spiritual wife.
                        Ur need is spiritual wife so respect their needs and also your needs.
                        let's seek meeting all requirements.
                        we need blessings of even seniors.
                        they want money centered lady - take money earning one - they can also be spiritually elevated.
                    Final message - dharmik sanskar. So meditate on that - focus on svabhav of child.
                        2 circles having same center then no clash.
                    Part 2 - How to choose life partner
                    5 points
                        male female energy balance - SG in dharmik way.
                        Support and heal each other - support spiritual growth.
                        Child procreation - deliver another atma.
                        other ashrams - self care chinta removal.
                        all rins - 3 rins removal. Krishna supreme controller but our gratitude.
                    ayurved and jyotishastra but modern psychology - what to do and what not.
                    what to look when go to see
                        all jivas are prakriti, purushottam. prakriti energized by purush. We try to be purush in material world - I be controller. Resource thing.
                        Feminine qualities of being prakriti easy for this form - expand my purush. nurture, nourish. Purush qualities then male form.
                        simultaneous use of both brain by females but 1 by males and extreme.
                        women more democratic - emotions suited - satisfying senses. nourishing, raising children. Outside dealings need more analytics. Vaam svabhav of Draupadi - is needed but problem.
                        woman also develop analytical side cuz gotta go outside and males also creative side gotta.
                        solid, confident, responsibility as a man - wussification of man - don't display courage. Potential to grow? Dhan uparjan; spiritual focus.
                        What they do in free time -
                            Brahminical - books and study; kshatriya - admin; vaishya - money earning ways; shudra - enjoying how to.
                        Ideal woman - all women they role - look for what you want. Draupadi lots of admin work - do we like that - firey personality - cows, treasury, etc. Like CEO - but admin actually.
                    Leave my child cuz spiritually focussed
                        Spiritually focussed community - eth seems maya - gotta go far. Other things get neglected - parents are right to an extent.
                        show maturity to them. More importantly, be convinced that prescribed duties help purification and is reqd for me.
                    Finding devotee takes time
                        patience level should be known about oneself.
                        Overrated that we want spiritual person - MMN should be understood. Also be open to potential of spiritual partner also.
                        Be open to what your expectations are.
                        no option other than patience - you will stay as you lived for 25 years - not anxiety but personal growth and resolutions. and Development. Calibre, maturity levels increasing.
                    Age gap - boyfriend is 14 yrs old - tradition of shyness.
                        French prez's wife is 25 yrs older than her. Society is judgmental.
                        Be confortable with yourself. Don't want details - you are intel.
                        Confident then no question. ppl test boundaries.
                        Discomfort emotions try to understand - subconscious wants to convey thru discomfort - there is a source behind discomfort address that.
                    Physical violence so fearful of relp
                        the fear is natural and stays - goes slowly.
                        This fear protects us from similar bad experience in future.
                        empathy for yourself - what you understood from incident - many signs but ignored cuz wanted to stay with someone.
                        Visualize and heal.
                        Self respect. Visualize the situation again and how you would act differently.
                        Such signs of such ppl - gotta stay safe.
                    Bipolar Disorder - go for marriage or not
                        maniac and depression phases - marriage problems come. But compassion fatigue comes.
                        Full effort to heal oneself if I were in your place.
                        Sometimes real problem is sth else - 1 lady real problem was losing twin in childhood.
                    Mature woman , perfect age, do job or not
                        mature - role ki awareness.
                        perfect age - age when ready. Early childhood - circumstances have changed - will I be able to sustain myself - young then easy to understand oneself.
                        do job or not - Krishna fruitseller was a job; satyavati was fisher woman so job; gopis makhan and selling - Vrindavan economy and toll.
                            So stri also has varna. vaat pitta kafa - kaikeyi kshatrani.
                            agriculture economy - silk work in china - all by woman. Milkmaid in USA - so even centuries back.
                            cottage and handicraft - now machine for eth - so no engagement at home.
                            work is nature and stri means to expand - lone at home is making her mad.
                        stri - ghar ki lakshmi. Lakshmi devi doesn't stay if girl cries.
                    don't wanna marry - so marry a devotee says mom.
                        shadi ka laddu - khao ya na khao.
                        mind goes outta control very easily. So gotta focus - vyavasayatmika buddhi.
                        need to share life with someone - how will that be met.
                        Never say never - we change with time. Better to stay married or join ashram.
                    should have same nature - opposites attact works?
                        thand, garmi; scuba diving, etc differences do come - can we let go.
                        what can you adjust with - similar answers to many questions.
                        respect, support, encourage and adjust that's important.
                        similarities then easy to give support.
                    love marriages with bhakti.
                        object of love be Krishna - is it ok.
                        vertical and horizontal relp - both are important.
                        gandharva vivah ain't marriage - you can find partner for yourself or arranged - gotta love is important.
                    compatibility important - differences vs love.
                        love is deep word - mostly worldly is infatuation.
                        Mutual respect and care.
                        kali nature - quarrelsome, hypocrisy and all - can we accompany each other for long.
                        you can sacrifice for sometimes but not for lifetime so gotta see compatibility.
                    small disagreements vs love at sight and divorce at first fight
                        less tolerance we have. how can spirituality help
                        even in spiritual circles it is high - compatibility and mutual respect is important - how spirituality helps.
                        grihasthashram - kuchh kuchh hota hai type. But spirituality gives awareness that it is about 5 purposes not 1.
                        dharma is far more important.
                        Like pleasure is temporary, so is distress so spiritual focus helps.
                    High spiritual divorce rates - they have base but why high rates
                        mutual respect and compatibility is less.
                        spiritual life focus and other suffers their needs are not met.
                        Krishna takes care of eth - no why - you gotta give time to each other.
                    I like bhakti she does not
                        what's going on actually is hidden so gotta answer with few details.
                        you must be giving her lesser time. Why changing now.
                        What's important to you - you must be liking the lady.
                        escape mentalitya and peace in bhakti - don't do in haste like driving in mumbai.
                        should start sharing what he likes in bhakti - respect from her - can see. Show her - not for conversion
                        gotta balance self interest and other's interest.
                    Can't forget husband - high divorce rates
                        big tree - uproot and put another place - comfort and eth set - it's painful.
                        it feels like death cuz a life experience is gone. takes 3 yrs subjective.
                    Remarriage with divorce and remarriage
                        Yajnavalkya - but there are situations when it can be done not a license.
                    Marriage based on compatiblities - financial, intellectual, etc.
                        marriage be among equal says SP.
                        so that mutual understanding - status differences then vichardhara differences
                        thinking shaped by these details - feelings of scarcity vs generous at spending. 3rd class train vs flight flight.
            </Selection>
            <VivahSanskar>
                Vedic and western (christian) perspectives
                    1 of 16 sanskars - to be registered
                    spiritual arrangement - legal agreement
                    for selfless service - to guard rights of individuals
                    based on devotion - based on mutual enjoyment
                        scratch back down.
                    step to responsibility - step towards fall down
                    devahuti, kardam muni - adam and eve.
                        fall down from spiritual for adam and eve but not for former they never felt that way.
                    serious enlightenment - festivities and show off.
            </VivahSanskar>
            <GrihasthaLife>
                About - Married Life in KC
                TODO
                    samskaras. counseling, tree of life, home temple. Role of family in ISKCON. Eg of Grihasthas - devahuti.
                    Duties of husband wife.
                Dampati ashram - couple phase
                    Ref -  Grihasta Ashram Seminar - Preparation for Perfect Grihasta Ashram by Sankirtanras Prabhu
                    Time Frame - from marriage till desire to have a kid.
                        2-3 yrs, career oriented 5-6 yrs, for those willing to pay infertility clinic - it can be 10-12 yrs also.
                    Natural different qualities of husband and wife.
                        man - radiance, sacrifice, logic, intel, devotion, mental or emotional tolerance.
                        woman - forgiveness, affection, holding and supporting nature, physical tolerance.
                            man does not forgive, affection not cutting relations that done, emotions more than logic.
                            holds and nourish so nature gives motherhood. Husband work done - nothing but wife multitasking.
                        natural physical, emotional, mental and speech related differences must be considered.
                        Quota of words - man 2K and woman 20K of which man speaks 1.5K at office so left with 500.
                            must say yes no - wife thinks poor guy - speaks that much only.
                    Purpose - When the couple is completely satisfied then entire family lineage gets benefitted and entire family becomes blissful.
                    Austerities
                        Austerity - BG - Of the body - worship SPOG, Brahmins, SM, Superiors like father, mother and in cleanliness, simplicity, celibacy and non-violence.
                            violence is more verbal than physical. Physical is cruelty.
                        Austerity of Speech - truthful, pleasing, beneficial, not agitating to others, and vedic.
                        Austerity of Mind - satisfaction, simplicity, gravity, self control and purification of one's existence.
                    What to do there
                        It's more of interdependence - from dependence and independence.
                        Complete trust -> Mutual Respect -> Raise Together.
                        Visioning about life in this phase  - meditation on economical consideration, expectations based on personal commitments.
                            what to do in different phases of life 30s, 40s, etc - what are the expectations.
                            how you wanna die.
                            economical - if this happens then what; policy of donations, parental care, etc.
                        sets eg for children also
                        expectations are mutual - not one way.
                        Tad viddhi pranipaten - humble enquiry and service builds up a faith in relp where knowledge blossoms.
                            Love is not a noun but a verb
                            Quality of relations in this phase are indications of mental and emotional devp of a person.
                        After marriage - Vedic time
                            parents go to teerth for 3-4 months - proximity so 1 after another - time for couple to know each other.
                            Separate flat or no personal space - both are not as per vedas.
                        Other expectations
                            Training about family traditions, social etiquettes and responsibilities
                            Training about family structure, organization, family business and specific family rituals.
                            knowing nature of other family members.
                            if gel well than girl rules the family.
            </GrihasthaLife>
            <Parenting>
                Ref - Grihasta Ashram Seminar - The Principles of Vedic Parenting by Sankirtanras Prabhu
            </Parenting>
        </GrihasthaLife>
    </PracticalKC>
	<TheoreticalKC>
		<BhaktiShastri>Refer</BhaktiShastri>
		<LilaSmaranCourses>Refer</LilaSmaranCourses>
	</TheoreticalKC>
    <AppliedKC>
        About - Personal, Relational, Social applications of vedic literatures OR its lifestyles.
			vs PracticalKC - that's more personal spiritual application; here it's SVAF application of KC at 3 selfs - personal, relationships and social.
			Shastra Chakshu of life.
        Ref: Radheshyam Pr's Management Camps (MALA, etc), Prerana, TSS, Youth Encyclopedia, One Time Programs, Namita Purohit, Mumbai Congregation, etc.
		<SpiritualApplications>
			About - How to apply what you have understood thru different courses.
		</SpiritualApplications>
        <Varna> Ref - Lectures (VA being soil for the Bhakti plant, etc), PIES, self motivation.
            Lack of passion cuz easily satisfied - nothing happens without determination.
                Eg - SP passionate about spread. Firm stands and All personal qualities but motivation inside
                as far as motivating others - integrity, etc inspires others. So leaders they trust. Not easily busted with setbacks.
                Inspiring others or managing others by hearts vs by hands or heads. They become your representatives.
                Business or job - competition not snub others but decisions for growth within - why fall others - grow oneself - making enemies bad for business.
                Never cheat ur customers and they get trust. Crushing other is a short cut not worth taking
                    Mafatlal's father used to say reputation building takes years and breaking takes 1 day.
                    Taking loan and banker knows it will be paid back and we did.
                Not easily shattered on failures - seeing objectively what went wrong.
        </Varna>
        <Ashram> Ref - Congregation and Counselor System - They want a culture and relevant guidance for a happy life.
            Center of attraction is transcendental means no intersection.
            From me to we - tolerance increased, purpose is evolution. Please God thru it - don't hate instrument
            Personal qualities are attractive and can withstand.
			Lecture - Languages of Love
			Grihastha Ashram Manual (from Radha Gopinath Mandir)
        </Ashram>
        <Personal> Foundational
            <Fearlessness></Fearlessness>
            <Love></Love>
            <SpiritualLustGreed></SpiritualLustGreed>
            <Tech></Tech>
            <Illusions></Illusions>
            <Engg></Engg>
            <EastMeetsWest></EastMeetsWest>
            <TitanicLessons></TitanicLessons>
            <CharacterWithCareer></CharacterWithCareer>
            <DoTheBestLeaveTheRest></DoTheBestLeaveTheRest>
            <LifeBalance></LifeBalance>
            <FromFearToHope></FromFearToHope>
            <TakeABreak></TakeABreak>
            <UTurn></UTurn>
            <ConflictManagement></ConflictManagement>
            <SeekerWithinAchieverWithout></SeekerWithinAchieverWithout>
            <TitForTatORTolerateThat></TitForTatORTolerateThat>
        </Personal>
		<Preaching>
			TTC - PIES,
			Facilitator Empowerment Course
				SP Vision for Devotee Care
				Vision and mood required of a facilitator to care for others
				How should a a facilitator care for those in his guidance by HH RNSM
				Putting the horse b4 the cart
				Taking shelter of hari guru and vaishnava
				Facilitator as a caregiver, rather than as an authority
				Ideal Vaishnava behavior of a facilitator
				Group Presentation - Qualifications and Responsibilities of a Facilitator
			How to read and make notes effectively
				Knowledge
				Understanding
				Personal Application
				Preaching Application
				Faith and Conviction
				Authority
				Theological Application
				Evaluation
				Mood and Mission
				Academic and Moral Integrity
				Responsibility for Learning
				Sastra Cakshus or realizations
			Become Deep By Sacinandana Swami M
			Presentation Feedbacks
				Avoid Unwanted use of humor
				Good Eye contact
				Avoid fillers like "You know"
				Good use of stage space.
				Invite Participation
				Good Voice variations
			Others - Infy
				Personal Brand Identity
				Personal Effectiveness
				Business English Course
		</Preaching>
    </AppliedKC>
    <AdvaitaSabha>
        About - expect life retrospects and realizations from experiences and connect the experiences to spirituality.
            Urgency of spirituality in focus for preparation of exam. How to guide others with detachment.
        <SocialReflections>
            Why crime increasing in society
            How to deal with population explosion
            solution to ecological problems
            etc
        </SocialReflections>
    </AdvaitaSabha>
</Bridge>
