<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Meditation>
	<Japa>
		<NectareanOceanOfHolyNameBySacinandanSwami>
			About - !Treat Holy name as person - first encounter with Krishna in world. Where eth starts.
				can reveal all NGRL; can even help you grow weeds (?ye yatha maam)
				Ref - based on the work Harinam-cintamani (“The Gem of the Holy Name”) by BVT.
				Like ocean holds more depths for seeker, likewise HN.
				visiting it like a botanical garden
				real visit to HN is one's own when one dives into chanting oneself with attention and deep affection.
			<IntroductionToHaridasThakur>
				Prosecuted Hindus but still chose to be crest jewel - limelight.
					Purified Hira.
					Hiranya Govardhan assembly - Gopal Chakravarti hated the idea of HN gave liberation as by-product. Offensive, Undisturbed Haridas, Offended audience
						response was yes logic can't understand this only DS can. Leprosy.
					Advaita fed brahmana bhoj for pitri to Haridas (1K worth he said) - criticized Advaita as outcaste then but later apologized they were beyond varna.
				Scriptural learned so would quote but political problem.
					death sentence if didn't stop chanting - my cut 1K pieces will chant.
					Arrested - inmates started to chant.
					22 market place beating - uninjured body.
				Vaishnav association club - with Advaita (Navadweep mostly scholars and Durga worshippers)
					Streets - only food of Harinam they want they said.
					Jagai Madhai purified.
				3L names ed - whisper, audible and loud. Satvik vikar visible - cry, dance, faint, etc.
					Later LCM accomodated him at Siddha Bakul tree (I have been there - Sume)
					How's your health - body fine, mind is not.
					Passed the next day - life message - fill your mouth with HN nectar in life or death for direct association of the Lord.
					BVT - He reasons ill who thinks Vaishnavas die.
				Passing away
					Glories with 5 mouths. Felt happy with description.
					Feet on chest while fixed gaze on face of LCM.
					Dust of feet of devs on head.
					Chanting and crying and gazing and ended.
					Felt similar to Bhisma. E1 chanted Hari and Krishna.
					LCM lifted body in lap and started to dance in ecstasy along with other devs.
					Body immersed in ocean water - e1 drank charanamrita of feet. LCM declared it to be pilgrimage site (been there also - Sume)
					Smeared Jagannath's sandalwood pulp on his body - samadhi by digging the body.
			</IntroductionToHaridasThakur>
			<NaamTattva>
				SP on HN
					Current state - maya (that which is not) - servant trying to be Lord of prakriti
						exploit resources - entanglement in its complexities
						busy in SG like lower animals.
					Intended Original state - Krishna conscious.
					Transition Agent - sublime and revival of original consciousness.
						cleanse misgivings of the heart.
						recommended for the age.
							Nothing is as effective as this process in this age.
						Practical - ecstasy coming from spritual stratum.
						chanting enacted from spiritual platform and surpasses consciousness at SMIES.
						Efficacy of hearing from PD with love for God vs non-devotees milk touched lips of snake.
						Meaning
							Hara - Energy of Lord addressing. Pleasure energy which helps us reach Lord.
							Krishna and Rama - Addressing Lord himself.
							Maya - material energy aka maya also 1 of his energy.
							Marginal - jiva marginal so we are also his energy.
								jiva in touch with maya incompatible situation. with superior energy then happy normal condition.
							Chant - spiritual call for protection like child genuinely cries calling for mother's presence.
								Mother hara helps jiva achieve Lord father's grace.
					Interim
						Finding cause of all causes - within and without
						spiritual understanding, surpassing the stages of SMIES (Senses, Mind, Intel, etc)
						chanting - spiritual platform.
						For chanting, No need for language, mental speculation or intellectual adjustment.
						Take part irrespective of previous qualifications but on advanced stages no offenses.
						Beginning ecstasy - 8 kinds - stopping as dumb, perspiration, standing hair, voice dislocation
							trembling, fading of body, crying ecstasy, trance.
						Immediately takes to spiritual platform - 1st symptom urge to dance.
						even a materially engrossed man is raised to the spiritual platform very quickly but takes some time.
				Glories - Scriptural references
				Meaning - Different meanings
				Effects - SA 1 explained.
				Yuga Dharma - All yugas dharma explained.
			</NaamTattva>
			<NaamKirtan>
				3 ways - upamsu, etc.
				Krishna's nature and energies
				3 stages
			</NaamKirtan>
			<NaamAparadh>
				<Effects></Effects>
				<TenOffenses></TenOffenses>
			</NaamAparadh>
			<NaamAbhaas>
				Anarthas
				Effects
				Divisions
			</NaamAbhaas>
			<ShuddhaNaam>
				Overcome
				LCM instructions
				Absorption
			</ShuddhaNaam>
			<Tips>
				Practices
				Attitude
				Techniques
				Living with
			</Tips>
			<FAQs></FAQs>
			<OpenSecret></OpenSecret>
		</NectareanOceanOfHolyNameBySacinandanSwami>
		<JapaByBhurijanPr>
			About
				Ref - Shikshastakam, Bhajan Rahasya by BVT and Harinam Cintamani
				BVT in Bhajan Rahasya - SA verses map with stages of bhakti delineated by Rupa G.
				As per our japa session - strive for the highest Practical application among the stated levels.
			<Shraddha>
			About - Maps with SA1
			Practical Application - Chanting Hare Krishna.
			Key 1 - Chant HK.
			</Shraddha>
			<ThruAnarthaNivritti>
			About - Maps with SA2
				?Mind map - so much mercy of Krishna but I don't take interest
					cuz interest in other things
						Prep - Detachment in consciousness.
						Runtime - And mind will still wander but we will bring it back.
					and not interested in spirituality
						Prep - Consciousness - State your sankalpa (or determination).
						Runtime - So, Focus on 1 mantra (present) and don't think burden of the count.
			Practical Application
				Chant without offense
				Attempt to chant with attention
				Listen to one mantra, one holy name.
			Key 2 - Listen to just one mantra.
			Key 3 - State your determination.
			Key 4 - From wherever the mind wanders.
			Key 5 - Detachment.
			</ThruAnarthaNivritti>
			<ToNishtha>
			About - Maps with SA3.
				?Mind map - Chant with humility - that there's long way to go and HN is only hope for that. So, how powerfully you will take to it.
					Chant with tolerance - worldly or social and karmic onslaughts whether pleasure or pain are meant to be tolerated.
					Mind will run on the flow of thinking, feeling and willing relating the associated stimulus of pleasure and pain
					but tolerate that by transcending the mind thru neglect, etc.
			Practical Application
				Humility means chanting Krishna's names with the awareness that their mercy is your only hope.
				Your chanting is coated with praying for shelter
			Key 6 - Neglect the mind.
			Key 7 - Humility
			<ToRuchi>
			About - Maps with SA5.
				?Mind map - Krishna is now a priority - Not interested in other other things but in your DS life after life.
					Therefore, HN is acknowledged and accepted as a shelter now and other things are no more seen as shelter.
			Practical Application
				Awareness of one's insincerity and impurities drives one to
					prayerfully beg the HN for mercy and shelter
					and to fulfill one's longing to serve Krishna.
			Key 8 - Namashray
			</ToRuchi>
			</ToNishtha>
			<ToAsaktiAndBeyond>
				About - ?Maps with SA5-8.
				<MasterKey>
				About - ?Maps with SA5
					driver for all the stages.
				Key 9 - Krishna's causeless mercy
				</MasterKey>
				?Soul in Material realm and yearning for Krishna seva realm - SA6 (?Asakti)
					Krishna is seen as the only option and other others get subsumed under Krishna consciousness but not independent.
					Krishna is no longer a priority but the only option or alternative.
				?Eagerness and Greed for more - SA6 (Asakti and Laulyam)
				?Separation - SA7 (Bhava)
				?Unconditional Service - SA8 (Prema)
					already includes unmotivated, unalloyed, uninterrupted.
			</ToAsaktiAndBeyond>
			<MiscTips>
				Focus on holy name - avoid getting distracted by techniques.
				But it it helps inattention and increases hearing then written form helps like for GKDB - Dots in middle for downward reading.
			</MiscTips>
		</JapaByBhurijanPr>
	</Japa>
	<ShlokasBhajans>
		Meditate on sound vibration of transcendental sound.
	</ShlokasBhajans>
	<Naiti>
		About - hunt about my real self by meditating the inside world - what I am, what elements are, what I am not.
	</Naiti>
	<Mindfulness>
		About - be an observer. Bring back effortlessly without judgement.
			Many variants - flame, breath, etc.
	</Mindfulness>
	<Kundalini>
		About - Chakras development.
	</Kundalini>
</Meditation>