<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Lila>
	<MB> Ref - Govinda Pr, Krishna dharma Pr book
		<About>
			3 lessons (explained by CCP)
				writer's view - lessons from the story.
					allegories permitted to supplement not supplant
				character's view - dielemma of life and choices => results.
				trans view - prakriti laws - karma, desire, Krishna.
		</About>
		<Kunti>
		Kunti - sthirata ki pratik.
			Story telling with deviations - dharma applications in focus.
			Prayers of Kunti - great sages appreciate
				sweet dish preparation has efforts - we forget that.
				happiness without gratitude then selfish.
				Problems tolerated and solved both.
				Hanuman - buddhi bhakti and kriya.
				fire incident - brahmin cuz no1 knew they didn't die
			Bakasur story - parallel govt - extorsion.
				relp bad that our relatives here so didn't leave - but praised.
				Husband has greatest duty; wife - no, wife gets exploited.
				fighting for self sacrifice giving reasons. Daughter b4 marriage anyways gotta go; and meaning of child.
				son is soul. wife is friend and daughter is danger. She says.
				sanskar that kido also said I will.
				In danger, we think that God should solve it - self danger is biggest e1 thinks.
				Kunti argues - no, not brahmin and that too first time.
					mamta but also confidence in the child.
					Pandavas - sangharsh in life so could tolerate anything and also solving.
					USA - opulence but no training for troubles.
				Bhima:Pandavas::50:50. Anti-socialism - equality should be based on purpose.
				Mama, why self sacrifice asks yudhistir - not MOI, greed or compulsion.
					Niti she says - Durbal raja - then should not stay there but we mistake that.
					decision based on discrimination not emotions.
					To Kaikeyi - anything you ask whether dharmik or not - that's emotion driven. Decision beyond rights.
					I have confidence and track record.
					Weak women in India? You have never read these sections.
				Fat guy and eating - bhima ate it all - only veg not buffalo
					killed that guy and his friends ran away.
			In ajnat vas - Kunti stayed at Vidura that they had to return back and not take sanyas.
			Shanti duta - Kunti tells probs not to solve but informing about life.
				They should talk fight not peace. Says Kunti.
				Some son Came back defeated against enemy - better you were not born - die hero is better than dying everyday.
				How hard hearted that wishing my death - that's in ur interest. Fearful, no worker, misdirected compassion - that person never grows. That guy won.
			Kunti to yudhistir - never fear fight - once mucukunda given free kingdom - no I will fight and get it.
				to all 1 by 1 - Vali's wife not trusted so defeated.
				What I hate the most is Draupadi's mistreatment. Tolerating exploitation is favoring their behavior.
				Arjuna chose Krishna vs Narayani sena not that he will fight and I will see.
					I trust my effort and your prasad. Not burden on Krishna but shouldering.
					not habit of God solving eth - Medical seat cuz KC - when study is 50% how is it possible.
				When stri biased to mind or intel. samvedanshil and rational talks also - what a balance in Kunti.
				We don't get Amazon food - we gotta click - do research for the dishes - different types of rice for purpose.
					Pot also need to be understood - Pot guru asked not SB guru - not Krishna's will so tolerate but bake it b4 usage.
					so effort and relevant knowledge.
				1 devotee - cow devotee - why God not helped - Kerala didn't help and cow can't survive there.
					Good emotions but not enough - need system - kheer won't be made if agni aparadh, pot breaks, milk curdles.
					Suji slowly.
					food thrown not good - vivah sanskar - 350 crore in Karnataka - so honor prasadam.
			Madri - I better sati cuz can't handle 5 nurturing - too much sacrifices - no bias, ability to tolerate, have money so let me.
				done oneself is appreciated but Kunti deserves more for her life.
			MB - Bharat - our history starts not 1947 but bharat kula.
				Kaurava dushta - you wanna hear brave or cowards - both - cuz Isho knowledge and mis-knowledge both should be known.
				Pandava life, hari, vidura foresightedness.
				Kunti's determination and tolerance.
				Secular understanding of flag - Saffron sacrifice, surrender, strength white - peace and clean. Green - samriddhi, prosperity and hariyali.
				50-80% of eb life is same - so gotta deal so events some difference but same experiences.
					Puncture of car is fact not why God did that.
					Nothing that happens to us is special - it's law of nature - Garmi - it comes as per weather.
				We get and should get what we pay for - getting 90% with 50% effort - they can't handle.
					Poor In Guj got lottery could not handle and perturbed - after spending it all - he felt relaxed.
					Heart attack outta happiness st.
					Karma and yoga go together
					Rice what to do with it - Kunti made kheer. Not alcohol, khicadi.
				After dharma established symbol and literally after MB but Krishna leaving
					yudhistir going to forest we will come with you said praja.
					smaran se vanchit rahenge - BTG.
					Madhupati not kadwa pati she says - let there be difficulties - no1 names child as kunti.
					Company's name for extra money - Johnson
			Shurasena ki putri - kuntibhoj se adopted.
				adopted at 7 - but she handled that mental turmoil.
				changing family is a trauma for the child.
				I was rejected by my parents. But if good parents, then good; she becomes strong.
			Kunti ki pariksha
				Durvasa blessings who is famous for curse - curse high probability but which one would be question.
				Durvasa cursed Krishna also - different temple in Dwaraka.
				Happy - using her back as table for food. Mantra given.
				astrologers manipulating get impacts in life but sharing without manipulation is fine.
				That blessing became curse cuz of her getting idle curiosity - small mistake but huge results for life pain.
				Surya pranam ed but mantra - sorry - I must do what you called me for. What will society think.
					if you don't then I will have to curse you; your benediction giver; etc - ego of sungod.
				Moon lineage and sun covered then karna comes out - eclipse happens. Very talented but eclipsed intel.
					I had separation all the life - parents, adopters, sun's warning, husband, children, relations.
					Taken care by the adopters.
					She Prayashcit thru the life - Vyasa dev - you are strong and clean so can digest it. You are not faulty.
				Population explosion problem vs what population is doing the problem.
			Kunti used Karna for self centered purpose - No, to avoid fight of MB that would happen.
				That's the wording of karna that people take - She does not plead or beg.
				Even small mistake of touching 10K Volts - it's gonna pain a lot.
			Kunti unlike Ramayan Kaushalya was equivalent of Sita in Lanka
				She is like heaven devi - Success - yash.
				Gandhari also troubled life - but no yash - anger against god that cursed.
				Life is happiness and trouble combination.
				Curious place earth - car but on a run - beggar but can stay.
					experience of dualities of life - pride and happiness of such powerful kids.
				Kunti's pleasure was kids. Draupadi's fortune to have Kunti and vv.
					both took care of Pandavas while others were away.
				She was healthy balance of sukh and sangharsh.
				Stick fight in Kerela - that's life - flexibility to face village life - st rain, st hot, etc.
					Sports should relieve of mental stress not increase it - we need sports Counselors
					Great soul but durvasa service is like living in dense forest but also literally later.
					Can't be artificial - clearing once is yogi - so artificial tryst and become hydrogen bomb.
					Got used to forest but go get justice.
					Begging does not get you justice but alms.
			2nd part
			Struggle in every phase of material world - Satya yuga also - hiranyaksha.
				1 willing to kill child, what would he do to praja.
				Kaliyuga - good people don't have strength and bad people also don't have strength.
				Krishna appeared cuz kings who have rakshasa mentality. That was greater than current times so Krishna appeared - dualities are always there - he does not keep appearing.
				All rakshasas not street goons.
				Life should be seen as a game. Tired but continues - defeated then depressed but continues next day.
				thru Kunti, give weightage to dukha sukha as much as needed not more - KY philosophy.
				MB e1 has read but how many really idolize Kunti, etc.
				Our sanskars => Our ruchi or interests in life. So, we feel sleepy reading MB, etc.
				Shoes shop asking for law details. Seeking wrong thing at wrong place.
				Garbha sanskar - gora hoshiyar and healthy - no1 says samarthya vaan - doing good for others.
				narrow minded - don't think about others but only oneself.
				Krishna's all marriages - in turmoil. Krishna didn't want to marry cuz treta I caused pain to Sita.
				Satrajeet alleges Krishna and all started questioning even relatives and praja - then Krishna acted.
				Lakshagriha - they stayed for 1 year as prince - so staying in place that can be set on fire anyday thru the year.
				Bheem - Hidimba - sin of rejecting valid marriage proposal. Ghatotkach was arranged by demigods as shield for Arjuna to kill Karna. So, they also scheme. but we goota do our part.
					another with Draupadi - controversial - and why not - even that time it was not accepted.
					Some so called scholars - Culture of exploitation - Seniors always exploiting juniors. Guru asking BD from junior. So socialism - so is their consciousness - even they see child exploiting mother thru breastfeed by waking her up.
					so need to hear from vyas.
				Draupadi - heard about her original and kautuhal which Kunti saw and arranged for them to go.
					Arjuna attacked in the way - defeated and asked by attacked - no guru and no grihastha after brahmacarya - not stable.
					Drona was not spiritual guru but martial guru. So go to dhaumya rishi.
					Guru comes to you vs you go to guru - latter is better.
					all in forest - dhaumya was there to guide.
					stayed at Shudra but good consciousness.
					Why bhiksha draupadi - Stri is not bhiksha - kanya daan - girl is not a thing?
						That's not the concept - bhikshuk is below. Giver is high and object given is something of value to giver.
						Word if spoken then never denied - the value of word. What if spoken - go back - not that culture.
					Draupadi knew children gonna die - but experience is different; once SB appreciated but chappal stolen - never came back.
					Not first time - Vyasadev gave eg in past and approved it.
					Can you make decision which you can digest for life - that's not easy.
						Yes, in general not recommended cuz we can't digest - but they could - Krishn married 16K cuz could handle.
						As per adhikar things are allowed.
					Sanskars degraded - no water personal but bottle; no personal cooking but event management team.
						Dharma to be in culture that it becomes attractive - Sita when asked to conduct nicely by Ram she says - no need cuz I know sanskars and next I am coming with you.
					No saas bahu bad story between Draupadi and Kunti - lecture in beginning what the expectations are.
				Donate to brahmins - difference of controllers and owners.
				Krishna in womb - VIP standing in line is respectable. Glorification that nature laws respected.
					he does birth lila but death lila also he does. Respects human life - we don't discuss for sentiment of eternity of God but SB mentions.
			She saw Krishna in agni, he saw Krishna even b4 in difficulties.
				It's possible for her. BG Krishna says - Arjuna see me ew. ?Purpose of life over and had gone there for that.
				Jivo jivasya jivanam - eating, profit from others, me rank 1, others suffer. Hinsa towards others in favor of interests. USA gone but had to leave family.
				If have to kill to stay alive - ask whose life is more valuable. Abort the child or die? If you die, you make child orphan or if they die, you never kill an insect but baby.
				It's a different culture to act in selfless way. Dharma sankat - that's difficult choice in that culture.
				should not say what's right or wrong without knowledge.
				Celibate had heart attack so fell - e1 singing Narsimha arti as if Narsimha will do the needful.
				1 Punjabi healthy doctor started beating him on the chest - he came to consciousness - you were killing him if you didn't do violence here - many devs could not see and ran away.
				So even if kunti allowed killing of 5 people that's act of dharma
				Shastra also like layered cabbage - you keep going deep from superficial to real essence - dharma centered then constitutional centered.
				Ajnat sukriti to Nishada woman - sacrificing like Jatayu.
				Bhima poisoned b4; Now, why they didn't refuse - cuz they said excursion to move out and do some worship (?besides politics of letting nemesis think they are successful)
				Good ppl not to be sacrificed for incompetent people - 7 challenged should be given favor but not adhikar (position of authority)
					that's a wrong mentality.
			I have this regret - Karna rejected and children from demigods not husband.
				Vyasadev said - don't regret you have done it right. And mistakes, you could digest or handle that.
				SP asked - did rama eat meat - doesn't matter cuz even if he did, he knows how to digest it (the reactions). He can eat even fire or poison.
				You are not understood by anyone what to speak of even ordinary woman like me. Humility.
			Q - Arjuna illusioned in BG 1st chapter - he thought neutrality from seniors.
					it all happens spontaneously not scripted and written. where's rasa of life.
					Ignorance for life is good - astrologer telling how you will die - you will die every second till then.
					they acted in the brink of seconds they were in but we in armchair speculation can say what's right and wrong.
				Ignorance never dies on its own - you gotta solve thru knowledge.
		</Kunti>
		<Draupadi>
		Draupadi - Sangathan ki kadi.
			Like Sita in Ramayan - huge description; Ramayan is 25K shlokas and MB is 100K.
			SB is ?18K. BG is 700.
			Brahmins have habit of truth so bluntly harsh from outside st but inside is soft.
				some people are sweet from outside but sword from inside.
			Once eat laddu with lemon flower very sour; New year - bitter sweet dishes to start with.
			Draupadi on birth - she will be cause of destruction of many kings. Gandhari saw not beauty in here but death.
			Genius have some madness also - talent but can't stay married - many fans but not 1 wife.
				ordinary - mistake then self problem. But small mistake from VIP even generations suffer.
				Draupadi - no childhood she got. Krishna used the consciousness of Drupad for orchestration.
				such purity in her that people in her contact - misbehavior then had to get killed.
				So, draupadi special or genius.
				She is agni - when you play with it, then forest fire can kill but can good use.
		L3...
		</Draupadi>
		<Book>
			<Parvas>
				About - Based on chronological life phases (or experiences) of Pandavas
				Adi
				Sabha
				Vana
				Virata
				Udyoga
				Bhishma
				Drona
				Karna
				Shalya
				Sauptika
				Stri
				Shanti
				Anushasana
				Ashvamedhika
				Ashramavasika
				Mausala
				Mahaprasthanika
				Svargarohana
				Addendum - Harivamsa
			</Parvas>
		</Book>
	</MB>
	<Ramayan> Ref Amarendra Pr; Gauranga Pr (Ram Katha and Hanuman series), Krishna dharma Pr book.
		<GovindPr>
		Lecture 1 - Ramayan - when vs what is there?
			Facility for imagining - history made s.t boring - not fiction or fact but impact.
			Movie on how they made a movie so his struggles to write the literature so participant there.
			Vyasadev in MB - but appears there although writer.
			arrogant, crazy or humble to write himself in the book - Valmiki is humble.
			People choose tragedy stories as heros - you become what you think - Arjuna had tragedy but success himself not others - Ekalavya and Karna not successful.
			Krishna asked for boon from Agni - not tu kya dega but in relp you reciprocate - deep friendship with Arjuna. Arjuna asked for divine weapons ensuring Krishna won't misunderstand.
			Perversion to see others team's defeat - choose worst players - Ramayan uses best characters.
			value vs valuable - not vastu but vaastav based.
			300 versions of Ramayan - Valmiki - heart breaking for brahmins and need to break hearts for kshatriya.
				100 version of ramayan - many slanderous - even court case why project Valmiki's version.
				Ram devotee's heart will break - why highlight Valmiki's? (10:00)
				Scholar - agnostic, atheistic, doubtful, dry grammarian (concept > grammar) - absorption makes you transcend page number. 1 with content.
					kshatriya would break their heart.
					alphabets, words, grammar lose their identity to enhance the purpose of Ramayan.
					@orchestra - all have presence but lose themselves for higher.
				Substance internally and externally. If no understanding but only aggression then fanatic.
				Rasikas - relishable
					yet no conflict with siddhanta.
						Raavan - try to find good in evil people. Endorsing that people can get away with crime. Eg - Human resource people come many times - his past or sth.
					Eb is good. God's wish eth happened - Then where's free will.
					overemphasis on greatness of God.
				Ravan told st - fell on feet or Duryodhan I wanna do good - Jiva has good tendency but doesn't stay - but punishable still.
				ordinary poets - have kalpana but not darshan - siddhanta distorted.
			Spirituality done wrongly affects society badly is a fact
			Why - reasons for writing
				Niti - game, wealth, teach practical interactions, gain freedom from curses and disease, achieve moksha, teach and transform others.
				Sahitya academy, jnanapeeth, etc.
				King reads your content and recognition - then prasiddhi.
				Intel -> arrogance. So stay fool? Envious otherwise. So, intel would be ignored in past.
				children you can be flexible but adult in arrogance so why attention to me, etc. So learning best at children even scold and they forget but learn.
				No flattery for psychological growth of child. Ram praising Hanuman was against it.
				Gurukuls run by grihastas - not sanyasis and brahmacaris - no love and harsh bad for them - efficiency by males and affection from females. Dualities of life to experience.
				murti are shaped fast but deities take lots of time - patience.
				certs but not skills
			(10:00)
			</GovindPr>
			<AmarendraPr>
				Spirit - Story told with transcendental reasoning, sanskrit, lessons - and further pastimes supporting the lesson.
					Trans includes allegories, more than earthly vision - karma reactions so this happened, heavens what was going on, what Krishna wanted etc
				<HowRamayanAsScriptureStarts>
				L1 - How Ramayan as scripture starts.
					People know more tech than Rama Krishna. What else to do in evening.
					only 2 chapters you must have heard enough about him.
					Krishna all attractive used to listen about Rama.
					Culture names that have all names RamKrishna bala subramaniam. Ref of person.
					Revive the culture of hearing - how all good qualities - Krishna himself comes in heart and cleans the dirt.
					@uproot leaves will turn yellow some time; fan switched off but it will move for some time.
					@baby dirty under shower will be clean in a very short time.
					Bring mind back - name syllables, bhajan, shlokas, NGRL, etc.
					Yamaraj - bring those who have never heard Krishna and leave those who have heard just once.
					Hear, Glorify, remember, worship - 4 things to connect with Krishna.
					As if Krishna is doing austerity to take darshan.
					Mediums of mercy seen as mediums of punishment - cuz Krishna's hand is not seen.
					Ram Katha in different languages - the root composition is valmiki.
					Tulsidas refs ramcharitmanas in north but not famous in south cuz awadhi.
						I have ref of many authors, scriptures, etc and also valmiki as base - writing for my happiness outpour in simple language.
						some say verse in shastra that valmiki shows up as tulsidas.
					Heaven ram katha has 100 crore verses. can solve greatest sins.
						Great people do it for others - cow doesn't drink its own milk - dividing syllables across 3 worlds - 2 syllables left - Rama.
						Rama = Radha Krishna = Radha + Madhusudan. (?Radharaman)
						24K verses for only Rama - 18K for different devs and all incarnations. MB - 1 lakh for itihas.
							halwa in hand as prasadam is vaishnava aparadh in ISKCON.
							All 10 incarnations - 10 mins for others but Rama katha for hours.
					Krishna is tough syllables to chant his name.
						he walk, actions, glances is crooked. Thief of butter from neighbors but owner of eth - who is thief.
						liberation you want - understand pastimes in truth!
						Then in BG he says be simple and straight forward.
						syllables from vishnu sahasranam to Narayan to Govinda to Rama (that's it) - can't make it one om.
						Ramayan - poetic style and expression like cookoo and depth like lion.
					Valmiki asks Narad Muni - anyone in world with 16 qualities - gunavaan not dhanvaan - Ram.
						Japa goes to places it is attached there.
						see always Krishna - internal or external energies of Krishna.
						chaturvyuh as 4 bros.
						Chitrakoot like Vrindavan - Lord frolicked. Ram vs Krishna loving dev fights.
							Ram is great but Krishna ate mud and all. So, more fun loving.
							Krishna attached then goes to mathura but Ram takes monkeys to ayodhya.
						mad elephant story - tulsidas stood his ground - faith in Rama name
							Tulsidas asked a Krishna devotee you didn't trust Krishna's protection?
							He said - I was thinking should Lord serve me or vv
					Ram Rajya no weather extremes, no mental problems, collaborations, smile solves problems, etc.
						These days center is not Ram but Kam.
						1 celeb said - sandwich on belly doesn't satisfy but tasting so taste Rama katha and not material accumulations.
						Asked Valmiki to compile Ramayan.
						SM and obedient disciple => explosion of katha - SB, Ramayan, BG.
					Valmiki bathing - how will I fulfill. Eg - SP - How will I do it - help will come said BSS.
						All of you are made to take birth here - you are telling me how to be a good disciple.
						KDK empowerment - garland, dream that I will help.
				</HowRamayanAsScriptureStarts>
				<KranchStoryAndPutreshti>
				L2 - Kraunch story and Putreshti.
					9.11.23 - great controller enjoyer when hears, goes beyond envy and stays in world but not karma.
					good material action leads to good reaction and reaction binds us to the world.
					Chaurashtakam - no more birth cuz no more milk in next life.
					Ramji - 27 when banished +14+44 rule after exile.
					guru akshare twice time to say - he is my guru but whether I am become his disciple I don't know.
						Aligning to the degree is as per me then where is surrender as much as we like.
						BSS work had signature of his SM.
						CC - what name have u given driving me nuts.
						Radhanath Swami - Diksha mantra is powerful fills heart with love.
					yamuna can't cross - Krishna is brahmacari then give way.
						Durvasa served - used both hands. Boon - unconditional DS for Krishna. How cross yamuna.
						Controlled senses equally satisfied. Accepts in devotion.
						Gopis from Radha and Radha from heart of Krishna - baby enchanted by his own reflections.
					Kraunch is subspecies of crane or baka or bagula.
						Sex life attachment comes griha, child, relatives, vitta. Bodily egos.
						Dogs trespassers will be prosecuted.
						Male killed by arrow and female confused. PD - soft as butter but melts on heat not true. But hurt 7 else then agitated.
						Curse. Why did I become so angry, that's not like a dev.
						With crane death, Brahmaji on swan has appeared so auspicious - na shobhate hans madhye bako yatha.
						Parikshit cursed by brahmin - accepted by the one who had seen Krishna in womb. That's a devotee - qualities.
							labcoat doesn't make you scientist. Or shirt makes soldier so external as dev but qualities.
							jada bharat - durga devi kills her devs.
							Prahlad never said bad father. These days people say. See what a dev is.
						Use this meter to compose shastra - I inspired this verse from you.
						sits in dhyan for revelations.
							baal gandharva for singing. apsara for dancing. Lava kusha learnt Ramayan and sang to Rama.
							Hari katha is so amazing even hari wants to hear it.
						ethiopia - lavadveep and kushadveep - earth into 2. Kushaites - present day africa.
						Goloka singers - snigdha and madhu kantha - kuvera children - after deliverance. May we see Krishna.
						10.10.28 SB shloka.
					putra - pun + tra. Putra kameshti yajna - first class rishi.
						sanat kumar hari satha said about dasharath - he must have told rishi name.
						Rishyashringa story - no meeting females. But king romapad get rains from - bring him here so send females.
						purush vikar on meeting them. Insignificant portion of fruits we have there. Goes to kingdom and it rains there.
						Radhanath Swami didn't think of women for 8 years in new vrindavan.
						Rishyashringa married and tell father should not be angry.
						Villains ready - Brahma beseeches and Lord appears. Demigods start to appear and I will appear.
						Appear in 3 species - white monkey, brown monkey, bears.
				</KranchStoryAndPutreshti>
				<MultipleMeaningsAndKheer>
				L3 - Multiple meanings and Kheer
					Multiple meanings of the valmiki shloka
						ma nishad had layers of meaning. Like Indra's cussing words on Krishna.
						ut + danda (up stick - showy)
							Indra thought Krishna is talkative - Indra thinking himself as center of attraction.
							Many adjectives used for Krishna. Thinks of himself as pandit.
							pandit maninah as so pandits believe. ajna - nothing remains to be known instead of you know nothing.
						Gopis saying you are not son of yashoda - parokshavad very dear to Krishna - not philosophy.
							you must not be son of yashoda - crying son and she thinking I should help him but you don't.
							supersoul is only witness does not help drowning person.
							So, Oh, Krishna you must be paramatma - you can see us but we can't see you.
						This shloka has Ramanayan scripted in it - kalidas ma's that not steady - ma (laxmi), mano, madhupo, etc.
						Meaning - nishad - residence place of laxmi so ram
							may you stay always in pratisha.
							Ravana kraunch who hit with lust - approaching sita will be killed by Ram who is abode of mother Sita's love.
							while Ravana is intertwined with Mandodiri heart to heart like crane birds.
					Kheer - 50-25+12.5-12.5 - All incarnations as 4 - 4 bros and Jagannath Baladev Subhadra Sudarshan but kali as 5.
						2 becomes 1 and 1 becomes 5.
						Why 4 JBSS - Guru gives mercy to those who have not. Krishna gives mercy to those based on credits.
							Baladev representing guru tattva comes to alter first.
							desire to see the lord rises - su darshan - desire to see Krishna's hand in life. desire to see Lord.
							Curtain of maya removed and yoga maya gives and then Jagannath shows up.
						RLBS - These 4 bros also have meaning - 4 aspects of bhakti - that's cliffhanger.
							all avatars have purposes mentioned - agenda b4 they appear.
							Which university Ram studied to make bridge - Krishna is true karuna nidhi.
						We are never invited and have no agenda in this world.
							In middle ground we claim to be youth but born in stool and blood not kundals, only in middle we have possibility of proclaiming.
							Saci mother was glowing when gonna appear.
							after losing 7 children happy - how's that possible - cuz Krishna had come.
							and demons feel afraid when Lord appear.
							SP touching 1 devotee at gate didn't get up on time after dandavat - he started glowing
							all nakshatras align to Krishna - above astrology they are.
							3 mahaprabhus in Vrindavan - LCM, Vallabhacharya, Hari Vamsha (disciple of gopal bhatta G)
							Hari Vamsha says
								all auspicious signs in 1 chart is less than Krishna cuz that's only limited to 1 life.
								all inauspicious signs - give that signs to even me - if Krishna is there, there obstacle is limited to 1 life only.
							astorology important as science but not important after sincere bhakti - like 2+2 is not very important in high school.
							dhruva after austerity says brahma's abode as glass broken and Krishna is jewel - we think vv.
					madhu masa - spring - honey honey bee - so all about my devs.
						if not ekadashi then dwadashi but properly - he chose shukla paksha.
						navami is maryada tithi (Sita and Rama) if you miss the fast then nothing possible - cuz ekadashi next.
						why ashtami - human values Rama and Bhakti icing Krishna. Irresponsible devotion possible - premature paramahamsa principle.
						Middle of the 14 days so take middle path - take balanced approach.
						Time has to be picked now - muhurta important.
						Ravan vs Jatayu - chariot, heads number and weapons - beak servant; could not fight for you he says. I wanted to not defeat but delay muhurta.
						Last rite not done for vulture that he didn't do for father - 48 mins of bhakti is greater - we have 120 mins of japa ed.
						abhijeet - victorious externally or makes externals victorious. Rama victorious himself and made monkeys victorious.
						In middle of day he appeared - bhakti is top of head in priority then he appears.
						Krishna in middle of night - in problems of life, asking for help - Vasudev Devaki that no hope and Krishna appears after anarthas and guru tattva.
						we get sympathy from common people.
						Empathic listening and people thank you.
						Merciful incarnation of lord as HN - that dog meat eating and bear in hand but chant HK mocking devs chanting in streets.
				</MultipleMeaningsAndKheer>
				<What4BrosRepresent>
				L4 - What 4 bros represent
					Flowers offer frangrance thru wind to Rama on birth.
						too fast wind or too slow doesn' serve.
						@Indira Gandhi appearing so helicopter flowers and no beggars - even for PM of 1 country in this world.
						crying is normal on birth. Made to cry if not. Struggle et.
						sukh samriddhi apartment under construction. Uncooked sweet rice in world.
						Rama Lakshman in basket and Bharat Shatrughna in basket - when together they became happy - master servant makes happiness.
						SP you are dear to me - how dear - like freedom fighter or gandhi - better - cuz connected.
						Shiva drank poison - vish (poison) + ram (peace of mind, emanating of Rama) -> peace of mind.
							turmoils in world and chant ram => peace that's what Shiva did.
					HN - Parvati chants Ram and Lord Shiva gives his form - ardha narishwar form.
						Narsi Mehta - give me the best you have. Gave DS.
						CC - haram called but got BTG.
					Lakshman characteristics - filled with wealth from the name.
						he has wealth of Ram Bhakti
						Ram broke bow and eb got the consorts.
						He used to say let me check if forest temperature alright then you enter.
						Lakshman left his wife unlike Ram - busy serving Ram.
						thru all struggle and suffering for them. Shurpanakha - be wife of lakshman. Do you want mistress or be servant - lord then go to Ram so attacked Sita.
						Marich - Ram runs behind him and Lakshman stays back - they produce different voice. No1 can threaten Ram - you have been waiting for this right when Ram ain't there.
						You are Irresponsible for leaving Sita said Ram - Imagine his surrender. What more is there to continue - he does.
						What all he does for Ram and Sita and how testing - When jewels asked to be identified - I only identify the ankle bell not other ornaments.
						he stands for amanina manadena in SA. Unconditional service.
						Enough husband wife story - let me leave - never. That's principle of bhakti - austerity or luxury but service.
						Prabodhananda Saraswati - If whole identify me but Ram don't what's use; if none does but Ram ids then all gain.
						Some so poor that wealth is all they have.
						Fought with Indrajeet and who becomes hero - hanuman. Why my name not announced - setting score.
						Lakshman in background always serving. Anant always sees us says lakshmi so privacy (not principle in vaikuntha) - ok then Ram birth manthara conspiracy - but where anant - as lakshman still there so what's use she wonders.
						Shalyapurna listened by Ramanuja acarya - he already knows all pastimes but listens attentive - different caste but doesn't - curse to not be born as Brahmin if can't serve.
						His servants - Kuresh, dasharathi - deities back in bag - first deities and then padukas - first your deities then my deities. He smiled.
						Big competition to be served but no competition for service.
						SP has haridas Pr in Mumbai - KC shows broadcasted. He was pickpocket b4 KC.
							Devs merciful - wakes up for mangal arati and sleep themselves.
							asked SP I can't sleep - go shoo away the dogs - their sound comes in dictaphone.
						Hamsaduta Pr for sankirtan bus which gave sound every part except horn - education incomplete but enthusiasm is complete. So do editting service.
						Krishna tells tree as siksha guru for tolerance - fruits for others, tolerates weathers but gives shelter.
					Bharat characteristics - unsung hero - service without reciprocation. Bhakti is path of thorns.
						Bharat had russian mother - Kekeya desha - Russia - Rasia Krishna or Rishi desh.
						dasharath decided to step down - no bill produced like democracy rule is what king says.
						conspired against pandavas now go to Forest. So time very powerful.
						Ayodhya goes from victory to defeat. After 15K years (?astronomical evidence)
						Raven kicked Ashtavakra muni - monkeys will kick you back and defeat your kingdom.
						Angad on head and passed urine - more service than asked - I am vanar can do.
							Vali wrapping in tail - for gayatri - so make him friends.
							Vali finished by Ram - like needle passing thru banana.
							You can't even move me - my power chanted Ram - 10 heads, brains, 100 fingers move my feet - I don't touch monkeys feet.
							Indrajeet will try. Ravan - one who finds pleasure in giving torture to others.
						Ravan in our consciousness and Ram katha will win our heart.
							Dashrath has 10 senses under control - peaceful city ayodhya. Ravan miserable city lanka and makes cry.
						Dasharath announced and Ram corronated - e1 said right decision - he didn't get offended to undo his decision.
						Krishna told by Narad for pain in mathura and Krishna understood I am coming - 1 calf there enough to change his decision.
							Cricket fan - GN deity - umpires giving sixer so their devotees.
							India vs Pakistan in India who wins India or Pakistan - so that's love for cricket.
						Manthara saraswati on her tongue then why not bharat asks Indra
							if on tongue of devotee, then that will be serious offense and you know anger of Lord said Brahma.
							you know the story of durvasa.
						He was thought of as seed of conspiracy. Bharat M thought at least dasharath would understand.
							can I perform rites - no that's what he said b4 leaving better vultures eat my body.
							Let me renounce kingdom - some said genuine others said drama.
							Let me sleep below the ground and eat oats in cow urine. Living the life of forest that Ram's living.
						Bharat is one who did bhakti performing the bhaar or weight of misunderstanding thru his life.
							No NRGL of Lord even in ayodhya, then don't stay there.
						Lord walking with demigods is favor to them but walks among monkeys.
							you have every reason to reject us - no intellect, no bodily beauty but you are with us.
						We want Ram but needs unconditional service attitude of Laxman and tolerance of Bharat for him to appear.
							Madhusudan Pr to Africa - wanted to serve but taking service - serve in every condition or situation is the spirit - rubbing his head.
							Giriraj M - taking headache for Radha Giridhari in Mumbai.
					Shatrughna - bhakti completed by him.
						ahead object not movable - killer of shatru.
						killed the shatru of false ego.
						south indian commentators - served the servant vs laxman who was servant of master.
						Worship of my devotee pleases me far more says Krishna.
						stands for humility - when Krishna uses no anaesthesia to humble us
						humility - thru serving devs it comes.
						Jayapataka Swami's preaching doubled after his medical troubles.
				</What4BrosRepresent>
				<HanumanInRamayan>
				L5 - Hanuman In Ramayan
					hanuman chalisa on rama navami
						you are lotus but honey bee to extract honey is more important to us cuz we can't tap honey from lotus ourselves.
						Impossible to describe Vaaman without Bali. Vishnu without Dhruva. Sudarshan without Ambarish. Likewise Hanuman.
						End with sweet after meal so hanumanji.
					Why Sundar Kand - Hanuman was very beautiful. Ramji also - so in the heart of the one love for that.
						one who connects energy with energetic becomes beautiful.
						Sita playing with ball stuck on tree - used bow to take it down - did you do that? - no I kept it back.
							If husband not strong enough then chatni - so at least be able to pick it with both hands.
							Ramji like best class - doing what the intent is so even broke the bow. Not just doing as much as asked.
							Sita with garland - I did what guru told me - blessings to get married.
						Sita represents luxury of world and Ramji as God so connector of the 2 is beautiful.
					Sun eating
						Sun represents enlightenment - run to eat the knowledge and realization and also gotta digest it.
						Spit sun out e1 says - when we rush for enlightenment e1 stops us from doing that. Fear of becoming sanyasi.
						Thunderbolt - different ways to allure the child.
						Away from shastra - then naughty child becomes - hanuman became.
						Sages saw the potential in child not naughtiness but misused - so cursed only to be reminded later.
						Good leader like jambavan
							leaders should not curse to snub potential
							leader knows the way, goes the way and shows the way.
						Hanuman goes like arrow of Ram - goes and do the needful and retires.
					I am Vayu and past credentials and contingency plans if jump fails
						but most importantly shelter of Ram in every situation.
					Parvat like grandchild - can't help but give luxury, love, gifts, appreciation.
						accept then purpose lost. Reject then ignoring sentiments.
						How to behave - thank you but on mission let me finish and then come and take rest.
						REL Akinchan Krishna Das - SP friend - I accept your gift but like it in your hand.
					Surasa - e1 should enter my mouth
						Hanuman excited can grow - becomes small and enters the mouth - met the condition.
						Atmosphere of Show bottle - stay humble
						Show off the size you are not - not happy and not confident about what we are - humility is to think of oneself less.
					Simhika - Hold ppl by shadow
						Sea monstress - our faults and flaws - busy holding the flaws in envy.
						Other anarthas can be dovetailed but not this one.
						Envy - NV = No Vacancy.
					Lankini - you can't enter.
						slapping maya. Happy she became and other cheek.
						Futuristic announcement - you can leave the service of Ravan and go away.
					Tulsi in Lanka - so devs in lanka - there was a devotee in Lanka.
						Sincerity finds its way.
						So, we are where our association is - Nabraska few devs.
						Great fortune to meet great devotee - I am performing bhakti around great devs.
						but you Vibhishan - teeth are sharp but you are like tongue soft around those.
						Seeing tulsi and identifying hindus in where public devotion not allowed and they are interested.
						Anyone can wear tulsi mala according to shastra - good qualities will show up.
						Tulsi and service - the magic will show up.
					?Searching Sita in chambers and thinking problem for brahmacari but Ram's service.
					Ashok Vatika - gonna commit suicide.
						Not scaring her by sudden appearance.
						bhakti, shakti and yukti all exist in hanuman.
						hanuman was very articulate with speech - so decided he will be messenger whenever needed.
							Speak truth but in palatable way.
						Shakes tree and sings glories of Ram.
						Many appearances have cheated her in past thru sights but never hear - so ear channel was best.
						sensitive to past
						who are you - most powerful then pride and other answer not truth - weakest in army of Ram and see what I will do - the whole chain is coming for you don't worry.
						How's my Ram - He is abode of eternal happiness then what will happen to Sita and if you say he is depressed and crying then what's the hope for her.
							He remembers good moments - but remembers you then finger ring can enter to wrist - which ring - here you are.
						once cold war between Sita Ram in forest - ring fell and Ram gave and Sita smiled - good it fell to make smile.
							ring had united when emotional distance. Now physical distance with his ring.
						Sita represents conditioned soul and golden deer maya - accepted to be separated from Ram in order to get it.
							Separated from Ram. Lord leaves but Vaishnavas are still with us but Vaishnava aparadh then they also leave.
							Conditioned soul without discrimination get cheated by Ravan - 10 heads or 10 senses.
							Garden Ashoka but cause of shoka - Even in peaceful when cry for Ram - Guru sent to that world to come into Lanka of this world.
							Amidst faults then good qualities are seen - like tulsi plant. Sits on tree and does 3 things.
							Ram Katha, Questions of Sita answered and gave rings. So, KK, Satisfying answers and sth more.
							@River into ocean - again water is evaporated but if fish in ocean then swim around and maintain your identity.
							All obstacles in the way of Hanuman. SP like hanuman jumped with BSS inspiration - all seductions rejected.
								obstacles rejected and engaged monkeys like us in west looking for SG and engaged in service.
					Hanuman tail set on fire - with all troubles thinking how to serve.
						with all opportunities, setbacks and fires in the life, choosing to serve Ram.
						he set lanka on fire - fault finding on back is Ravan nature - criticise bhakta behind back then devotion like lanka is lost.
						I can take you out but yes but what about other Sitas but do it for all.
						Sita teaches principle - Not concerned about my liberation but others like prahlad M.
					Found sita I - grammar is not right.
						Most important verb is found.
						Sita is who and I is last and few nano seconds will be wasted.
						embraces hanuman. what benediction - may I always get to jump for your service.
						Accept vibhishan if he has come to shelter - on recommendation of Hanuman. Vibhishan be the Lanka king.
							If Ravan comes to my shelter then him also king - but Vibhishan already then him to ayodhya.
							What about bharat, him Vaikuntha. Then you? I in Hanuman's heart.
					?Hanuman's name in personal diary.
					Our superhero is hanuman not superman, batman, spiderman.
						SP - you make me dance and his service has saved Sita like us conditioned soul of this world.
						Inconceivable mercy of Ram. Everywhere Ram went with invitation accept lanka cuz Sita was calling for him.
					Ramayan has been story of twists and turns - unpredictable change overnight - Ram king, Sita queen, Bharat suddenly culprit, Kaikeyi brainwashed,
						dashrath resigns overnight dies, deer jumps and game change play.
						If flip of planning in you then Ramayan revealing itself in reality.
				</HanumanInRamayan>
			</AmarendraPr>
			<GaurangaPr>
			Pattern - Story granules, philosophy supporting the act, Allegories (what it represents), Action Item, Eg (detailed below)
				Eg - include the following (extended as per appeal)
					?from SB (and more stories)
					?from CC (and personalities in line - includes seniors up to Madhvacharya and down till book distributors)
					Prominent - SP (His superiors upto BVT, devotees, followers), etc.
			<BaalKanda>
			L1 - Baal Kanda
				Valmiki asks Narad Muni - Karma for jivas but lila for God.
					Qualities of material world and people may change but not God - Bhakta vatsala for a long time let me be asura vatsal.
					Lord appears to reclaim jivas BTG.
				Valmiki taking bath - cranes enjoying each other. Pierced and leaving body.
					Why destroyed peaceful lives of these cranes - cruel act may you suffer.
					From shoka came shloka in perfect meter - compose literature so I inspired said brahma.
					Great personality but composing on authority - submission is very important.
					Blessings of vaishnavas is inexhaustible and can take 1 to spiritual world.
				Presented to Lava and Kusha - who went distributing
					best way to understand is hearer and speaker - both advance and experience satisfaction.
					Higher taste required to overcome lower taste of sense gratification.
					Rupa G - Need nectar of KK to alleviate the problems for age of kali.
					MOP and MOI so concentration on KK is difficult - Newspaper 2 reading simultaneously and derive taste.
					KK - 7 said all tensions gone so I sleep peacefully.
					SP - Krishna book on janmashtami night and chapters after chapters. Kurukshetra in people - let's end and loudest hari bol.
					Salt-mine you enter you will end up touching salt so miseries in material world are obvious.
						All great literatures came from 7's tormenting situation - be it SB, BG, etc.
						KK is solution.
				Described Ayodhya's past
					This track of land is not material world. Auspicious flowers. Sophisticated weapons.
					1 frustration that no son - that's the nature of world - n good things and 1 bad thing brings problem.
					harsh + Shoka is the nature of world.
					But he took shelter of great souls - what we do is important - shelter of SG, psychiatrist.
					Highest suicide rate among psychiatrist - what's this suicide and they also end up doing.
					Dasharath had roti kapda makaan so next problems show up.
					Akaama sarva kaamo va - take shelter of Krishna or great souls - charity also.
						Ganesh drinking milk - mood in feeding milk was giving you milk and will get rabdi from you later.
							Get down you don't trust Krishna eats ed and ppl take - why not Krishna.
						St shelter of easy liquidity. Demigods, astrologers but Krishna demands ananya bhakti.
				Yajna
					Kaushalya 1/2 and Sumitra 1/4 and 1/8 to Kaikeyi and 1/8 again to Sumitra.
					Demigods taking birth ready to serve Lord.
						Lord moving with monkeys - no distinguished personality likes to be associated with them.
							Uddhava astonished by nature of God - no shame in accepting services from monkeys.
							Lord accepts service from anyone with love and shelter.
						Mayavadis cut off Lord with energies. Some say SP without associates.
							Krishna means Krishna along with his associates or devotees or paraphernalia.
							can't say Ram but without monkeys.
						Demigods created atmosphere for lord to appear.
					Children Ram, Laxman and Shatrughna, Bharat born.
						Purification - birth by sanskar, money by charity, food by offering, mind by satisfaction, soul by KC.
						Lord also performs sanskars for us to follow in footsteps.
				Vishvamitra Muni
					Dashrath asks how is self enquiry going on - how is your KC going on.
					Your presence like rain after long drought, receiving child after long time, etc - what can I do to you.
					Many disturbances from asuras. Those who interrupt sankirtan yajna are asuras or rakshasas.
					Brahmin doesn't retaliate but ask for help from kshatriya.
					Heart crushed to give Ram for 10 days - can't live without him for a moment.
					Ravan does not appear but sends associate - I will come and fight so don't take him.
					Angry - Such is not expected from dynasty - he was kshatriya b4 and will get weapons and arts from him.
					Ayodhya to ashram. Taataka demon killed. Marich could be killed but for service for future not killed.
				Ahalya regains her form by touch of Lord.
					SPOG divine feet in our lives - our lives get transformed.
					Ram to Mithila Janaka.
			</BaalKanda>
			<AyodhyaKanda>
			L2 - Ayodhya Kand
				Shiva's bow
					Janak M asks Vishvamitra M - history of bow of Lord shiva to be witnessed.
					Shiva sacrifice - daksha opposed so used the bow - extremely afraid and Shiva to demigods to forefathers to Janak.
					So heavy that 500 men lift it - levelling ground and effulgent baby girl from earth came out with divine qualities.
						she lift effortlessly so condition to marry her but no1 ever successful.
						will you allow Ram to take a look. Sure.
						brought to arena with 500 men - e1 waiting to see what will happen.
						Ram stringing it and broke in the process.
					Sita is eternal consort of Ram - 9 years of age for Sita.
						huge dowry from Janak.
					Parshuram another incarnation meets - very rare they do - lift the vishnu's bow and he did.
					Lakshman and bharat also had been married.
				Coronation planned - Future events
					Pastimes for us to give us hope. If he can tolerate why should not we - I can't change the nature of the world.
					change the situation of battlefield Arjuna could have said but no, nature of the world.
					Dashrath had promised bharat's father once that he would be installed as king and didn't want to honor that.
					bad omens so impediments so perform ceremony tomorrow.
					Quality of devotee wrt to SPOG will be showcased in future.
					1 person extremely angry - Manthara - demigoddess from heavens for the purpose.
					Demigods to ensure that Ram should not forget asuras killing purpose - Ram should be forced to kill Ravan.
					Envy and rage to see festivities.
					So separatist vision just like Dhritarashtra (maam and pandavas) at the beginning of BG.
					Temple - mine and their same attitude. Different from supreme interest.
					ISKCON like dharmakshetra but can become yudhakshetra if interests are different.
				Manthara poisons Kaikeyi
					How in ignorance; don't know the events - Ram be king - yes and gave jewels to those who brought the news.
					She has feelings of devotion and love.
					If he becomes king then not bharat and you relegated to maidservant.
					First seed of suspicion, doubt and intrigue put inside the mind - so association impacts.
					Opening mind - 1 of 6 exchanges is association.
					Avoid mayavadis - how to identify mayavadis in India - scratch any Indian hindu and mayavadi inside.
					Amritsar - eth is 1 - then thread of blanket is same as blanket so take the thread for the night.
					Manthara's criticism made kaikeyi lose faith - thinking of possibilities she felt insecure.
					Modern day manthara - Internet misguidance. 7 has trouble of writing - no smoke without fire so there must be something.
					Somewhere solmen island - indigenous people technique abuses for trees and over 6 years tilts and falls on ground.
					blaspheme and criticise the morale drops. So much affection from Ram but affected thru the sound vibration.
					what to do - now you are talking - you remember benedictions - ask 2 boons now. Danger if Ram is around so send him to forest.
					She felt ecstatic cuz contaminated by association - that's the impact.
					Raghunath Bhatta G - never tolerate criticism - walks out - try his best to serve Krishna is all I know.
						Only Krishna can judge.
					Manthara you are beautiful lady - not sinful, best of hunchback women. Walking stooped like lotus under wind.
						 will decorate your hunch and will massage - discrimination is lost.
						Kamat krodhobhi jayate.
					Among all in Ayodhya only she is my well wisher.
				Dashrath confronted
					shrivelled and clothes torn - attached to wrong person and motives causes misfortune.
					let only 1st one be fulfilled - you had promised you can't go back on words that's dynasty.
					hard hearted cruel woman who was so happy devotee b4.
					Kaushalya came to know about this first.
					Ram thinking something about proceedings.
					Dashrath calls but sth wrong felt - Dashrath could not speak so fell unconscious
					Kaikeyi said he doesn't have strength to speak so I will - vow that you will follow his instruction then I will say.
					2 desires told - alright from father but even from you it's fine - I will go to forest with your blessings.
					maryada purushottam eg. Children in India criticised be like Ram and they say you be like dashrath.
					Kaushalya just told by Ram as matter of fact and leaving.
					Lakshman filled with rage - he is just acting outta lust. I will corronate you and if Dashrath opposes I will kill him also.
					Lakshman don't be angry - please gimme blessings - your tears are discouraging me from obeying my father. Plz encourage me.
					Sita told - you can't live in forest. Her feet earlier became red touching lotus so soft. roots, fruits and herbs won't suit you.
					I will perish in separation - you not here then hell and being with you even forest is heaven.
					Lakshman stay here for service - Shatrughna can do that so let me come.
				Leaving Ayodhya
					Ram Lakshman Sita prepared to go to forest and money charity given - Trijata
						stick and all cows that it goes over are yours.
						Dashrath said let soldiers, merchants and treasures come with you - she will have doubt in my integrity.
						You can't take resources without permission of Bharat said kaikeyi - I will wear tree bark - she shamelessly brought from him to wear which he did.
					Sita could not and it slipped so wear above sari said Ram.
					People - let us leave with you, forest will be ayodhya and vv. Ram appreciated their devotion but didn't allow.
					Many old sages slowly walking while he was going - he walked along with them.
					King of Nishadas Guha king - but devotee - stay here and be the king of nishads.
						delicious dishes brought - only fruits and roots and delicious dishes given to horses.
						I want to cross the river - I have a request to wash lotus feet. Why?
						Ahalya converted to lady and I can't allow that to boat so removing dust.
					Bharadwaj Rishi greeted - suggested somewhere far so that Kaikeyi also assured that vanvas going on.
						100 miles you find chitrakoot - so scenic that happy with wife - like spiritual world non-different - near Satna in MP.
						without tour guide you heart will be enchanted.
						Janaki kund - Sita's bath place, mountain for parikrima, Narsimha murti carved by Ram. 13 years spent there so very powerful.
						kinda like vraj lila.
					Bharat M comes back to Ayodhya on message - interesting response and meeting chitrakoot.
						it was not sentimental meeting but more to it.
						Not 2 bros like Ambani asked to stay together like former for share prices.
						Nasik Dandakaranya forest visit in future - Sita's kidnapping place.
						Shurpanakha and abducted any peaceful place - chitrakoot was last peaceful place and from here action starts and many like that.
						How can hanuman jump the ocean - superman jumping so why not - that's where ideas come from.
			</AyodhyaKanda>
			<AranyaKandaBegins>
			L3 - Aranya Kanda (Beginning)
				Kali yuga qualities diminish - Naimisharanya most auspicious place.
					Only yajna is hearing and chanting as given by LCM - SB, Hari katha and chant HN.
					sitting in posture in kali yuga is impossible in current age.
					small child can't even ball on the pitch so big and boundary so big that can't see - ball replaced plastic.
					things simplified so that they think they are doing it - so is recipe for kali people.
					Just be in right association and perfect will come - massage needed then stay in the train.
					Just stay near the gate and needful will happen.
					1 gets forcibly dragged to perfection that's the power of devs.
				Bharat returns
					Bharat was away to Kaikeya - present day Russia.
					message sent to come back to Ayodhya.
					Enters the city and e1 grief-stuck.
					Reaches and realizes that Dashrath is gone. Stay equipoise in happiness and distress says Kaikeyi.
						Bro Ram Lakshman Sita exiled and left body in separation calling their names.
						Exiled on sin like Brahmin killing - no, you don't know what all happened and told.
						He screams at mother - wicked lady, you personify kali. I will also go to forest. So wicked how you think I will accept.
						I will not consider myself as your son from today.
						Meets Kaushalya - explains that your plans will be met. Extreme sad that don't speak like this - never consulted and don't misunderstand me.
						1 minister brought manthara - shatrughna starts beating her - Bharat intervenes don't behave with woman like this.
					Mood of Bharat to bring back Ram with entourage - this is essence of Vaishnavism - eternally part and parcel of Krishna.
						Mayavadis think that we can become God. Bharat M's behavior is punch on that philosophy.
						Atheist - God not exists, retired after creation, God exists and I will kill him, I am God.
						99.9% spiritualists tinged with mayavad.
						Growth opportunity we look for - trainee for 30 years - stagnant not growth - Krishna says eternal servant.
						Education system with show of humility but desire to be the master underneath.
						Here Bharat given the lordship but rejected.
						1 devotee to parents wrote letter - Signed your servant - that's what you have become - sorry, it's servant of the servant.
						No desire for Post, position, prestige.
						SP - Mayavadi asked SP no mention of Krishna and dhyan means bhakti yoga. Just pointing out no Krishna but you mention.
							why tolerating SP so much - generally SP would punch.
							This man chanting name of Krishna for 1 hour he chanted HK so next time he will listen.
							1 mayavadi visited temple and said with confidence you are worshipping me very nicely ed.
				Bharat Starts
					Guha asks Bharat why so many soldiers what are you intentions - do you know about his whereabouts; you think I can enjoy without Ram.
						just testing - go to bharadwaj Ashram and he will guide further.
						Huge army - what are your intentions - just wanna serve Lord Ram. I knew thru mystic yoga but was testing.
						Whole army gives best arrangements for the night by his mystic power - power of the past.
					Ram hears sound and Lakshman on the tree to see - huge army approaching.
						I see flag of Bharat - he is coming to kill us - gimme arrow and I will kill him immediately.
						You wanna be king you can do that - I am convinced that he is coming to meet me.
						Don't act hastily to destroy relationship - don't jump to conclusions without clarity.
					Bharat comes and says after demise of Dashrath, eldest takes over the kingdom - grief.
						requests to come back. Args to come back and counter args to not come back.
						alternate ideas - Jabali Rishi - why bona fide ways didn't work - body is made of chemicals and life is temporary
							eth will finish to dust. Enjoy the kingdom and then eth finishes to dust.
							Not new chemical theories. Very old.
						SP - Archaeologist - what you do - study primitive people - I am devotee and study advanced people.
							Theories existed in past - cuz guilt gone when God is removed.
							Jagannath Puri - Pandas ask gotra - Dyutakarma Pr - Darwin's followers should say monkey gotra.
						Give them chance to serve you - e1 wants you back - will be back after 14 years.
					Seeing he won't come back - place your feet in sandals and they will remain on the throne.
						You will continue ruling for next 14 years and I will simply be humble servant.
						instructions from sages to do needful.
						No royalty - stay in Nandigram outside and drink simple soup and sleep under the ground.
						All facilities to enjoy but choosing to serve and surrender to the will of the lord.
						Ram wear and takes feet away - puts sandals on the head and leaves.
						Service attitude over the years in HK goes on increasing.
						SP - Jayananda Pr - Garbage cleaner and so blissful thus preaching.
							go near apple tree and tree offered to Picture of Krishna - e1 picks apples from trees will take prasadam and be devotee.
							never bought new clothes - at least for sake of movement wear new clothes.
							In a market - for myself I won't pay, so won't pay for T-shirt for my own SG.
							Such sincere face judge asked police why don't you pay.
							Cancer and admitted - posh room - came near bed and SP picture with garland - and where is patient - lying on ground near sink.
							Opulence from SM and simple life for me he said.
						Devs here make arrangements for Lord to wear
							you won't see devs in temple with opulence for themselves.
						SP - 1976 celebrating 10 years of ISKCON inception - cake cutting.
							We offer to Krishna and he gives back - servant enjoys so much.
							Servants enjoying as much as master - no, servant enjoys more than master. He takes little and servant has it all.
						SP observed banana dance - banana smoke then LSD feeling. SP laughed I never knew this use of banana and did kirtan.
							offer from hippies - 1 banana for jagannath and said peels back. Never knew I had to solve such scenarios.
							Mood of offering to Krishna is good so let's accept it. Money, resource, time, life force for Krishna.
					Mood Bharat vs Ravan - Serving Ram's enjoyment vs snatch Sita away for his own enjoyment.
			</AranyaKandaBegins>
			<AranyaKandaLatter>
			L4 - More Aranya + Kishkindha
				Bharat with all his intel tries his best to convince Lord Ram. Not successful so brings sandals.
				Killing viradha.
				Sitikshana ashram they stay - Sita devi says wanted to say this for long time - sword in hand.
					Indra to Brahmin I have come to hunt - hold the sword - uses for tree, then animal, then human.
					You may end up killing cuz sword in hand. Protect kingdom vs protecting the sages in the forest.
					Law of association - association with even objects in the world they have power to influence us.
					Even electronic gadgets create influence on us.
				Agastya rishi - who guides them to panchavati - stayed at parna kutir - made of leaves.
				Shurpanakha appears in Janasthan
					lust so forgot to change her form. Who is this ugly lady.
					Ram in sarcasm said that arrangement of Lord - my wife already here and co-wife you will become.
					Lakshman be approached with strong arms. Big difference between Ram and me - I am das so you become dasi.
					You wanna be dasi? No to Ram. back and forth ping pong. That happens when lusty.
					Angry so tried to choke Sita and pastime finished with cutting off the nose - fell in nashik from other side of godavari.
					14K rakshasa army headed by khara and dushan invoked by her and killed by bros.
						akampan escaped and told Ravan. Not happy with news then Ravan used to kill so gimme assurance to not kill.
						Humans but very powerful - don't go to kill them alone. He is extremely attached to Sita so kidnap her.
				Ravan meets Marich
					Very urgent mission. Killed my 14K - insult to rakshasa race.
					Demons nature is SPOG as human - they appear to be ordinary humans but are tremendously powerful.
						without being favored by devotee, one does not get to understand lord.
						Bilvamangal thakur - Huge Varha dev Body - 1 skin pore of his body so big that all oceans in earth could fit in there.
							But he can be bathed in 1 drop of water. That's inconceivable nature.
						SP - I have presented so many books for you to understand that he is inconceivable and we can't understand him.
						Virat rupa deity - all clothes, all food will be consumed.
					Marich - who advised to kidnap Sita - whoever did this wants to see your death ASAP.
						his arms like ocean where enemies just die.
						1st class advise but vinash kale viparit buddhi. You already have millions of queens.
						In youth thinks that lust influence so let me come in contact with another person in lust and satisfy each other.
						lust converts to anger and so forth. Eth as opportunity to fulfill lust vs world to serve Krishna.
						SP - why Krishna created world - for enjoyment...not yours but Krishna's.
						Ravan mentality keeps propping so take dev association.
						SP - Factory anxiety. Give it to us and you be peaceful. Give us the address - I know your address; gave reluctantly.
						At this stage he thinks he can't be happy without Sita. Ravan in constant anxiety since infatuated with Sita.
						But still, Ravan buys the advise of Marich and comes back.
					Shurpanakha - no justice in your kingdom. Look at treatment done to me.
						She details Sita devi - most beautiful and your life is useless until you get her.
						This obsessed Ravan being agitated by Shurpanakha and revisits Marich.
						Plan worked. Why again asks marich - this time plan and instruction not advise
						If I follow then killed by Ram, If I don't, then by Ravan. Better get killed by Ram (?bad move)
				Sita Abduction
					Deer shows up and hides - Ram observes and kills still.
					No power can touch Ram - instructed to not go. I know your inner motive - you wanted to enjoy me - thunderbolt on heart.
					Marich's call felt like Ram but was demon - st mind cheat us in the name of Paramatma - maybe it's Lord's desire.
					So, don't disobey gurus (siksha or diksha, etc) saying that it's lord's wish - be submissive to help discriminate.
					SP - plz bless to be humble - first be humble.
					Ravan entered. Approached Sita Devi - asked many questions - who are you asking beauty - are you damsel from heaven.
					She bewildered sage should not speak like that.
					Gimme alms - advantage to kidnap her.
					You like jackal and playing with lioness without knowing consequences. Wipe eyes with needle. stop fire with cloth.
					Drinking poison like foolish.
					You like crow and he is garuda. You like muddy puddle and he like ocean. He like nectar, you poison. He sandalwood and you wood.
					You like fly wants to eat ghee - you will just drown in the ghee.
					Valmiki Ramayan has no mention of Lakshman rekha but is there in other version.
						when we cross the maryada boundary then we are not safe.
					Sita represents Bhakti and Ravan as swindler - saffron wearing but stealing the bhakti away.
						Hanuman's search for Sita is like sadhaka seeking bhakti
						Jail lecture can't run away - Why Ramo although Ram - Our person also scholar so clapped.
							Eat this aamo will you reject this.
							In sambodhan st called like this.
						Many movies on Bhagat singh we have it on Sundays congregation - how? bhagats come and they sing.
							word jugglery - upadharmis. Chhal is another swindler. King of manipur met BSS said tea from BG - sarvasya chayam (7 told him so).
						Bhakti in heart is precious; safeguard it else Ravan like people come and steal it.
						Pray from Lord Ram that we may sincerely chant HN for rest of our lives.
			</AranyaKandaLatter>
			<JatayuAndQA>
			L5 - Kishkindha, Yuddha and Uttar
				Jatayu - eagle or vulture - eager and inspired to serve seeing Sita abducted.
					Vidura meets Uddhava - remembering Krishna tears filled eyes of Uddhava. Same devotion and enthu when he was young.
						Walt Disney - medicine to overcome death. 10M dollars for research - some system to put on machine and bring him back.
						Another 10M with propaganda to not bring him to life.
						Soul is eternal so perfrom activities on the platform of soul. On body level fatigues but none on soul platform.
						No retirement in bhakti - inspired to do more. Bhakti not that no more latter like other activities ?in MOI - Bhakti for more bhakti.
						Jatayu was so old that he had every excuse to not act but sprang into Action.
						Physical incapability but could not stop him - that's bhakti.
					Different body parts were cut by Ravan.
					She threw jewels on the ground and this was observed by apes.
					Many services we may feel incapable - others meet our false ego - our surrender and service is tested st.
						Ravan should have fought me 100 years back then I would have helped - my best wishes for Sita, so obvious, I will pray for you, will convey message to Ram.
						Conditions are not right. Mgmt ain't right - let me stay here in lethargy.
						Ravan too powerful for me - let me not even try - here's a chance of service - whatever results I must try - need of the hour.
						Work is worship is what they think - factory is temple - siren is shankh and crude oil is charanamrita.
						Other times paralysis in analysis - Centipede dancing nicely - you dance very nicely how you do it - stopped dancing and thinking but could not walk - paralysis in analysis.
						Whole time in consequences of action thus no action taken - Jatayu didn't fall for this.
						Service - good in the eyes of others and not those - we have preferences.
						Ram came and no idea - touched by Jatayu - Sita kidnapped doesn't pain me as much as Jatayu sacrificing his life.
						Jatayu has gone BTG cuz of sacrifice. Who won is the question.
					Arjuna won for Krishna and BTG. Here in Jatayu, lost but BTG. From material perspective defeated cuz Ravan proved to be more powerful.
						We try in material world and st fail in our mission - not material organization but bhakti can still win.
						Internal moods and motivations matter. Mundane person thinks Arjuna role model and Jatayu blew it but he was successful - need maturity.
						Material propaganda is so high that forget Jatayu. Battlefield I be victorious. What's best from Krishna's perspective is important.
						SP lost - Business set on fire. Tested again - giving eth. Seiko watch. Credit cards. Never losing bhakti.
						SP in africa - not eating - how can I eat when they steal cement bags in mumbai. I am not a man to be disappointed.
					Try level best then that's what matters.
						SP - Pamphlets distributed but no1 came - SP - didn't you see there were demigods. BSS used to spread the mat full - demigods may come.
						SP - Vrindavan temple - Donate temple promise - Mr Sarve - not honoring his charity. Described king mriga. Became lizard. Satsvarupa Pr had taken SP's clothes - thought he won't use so shivering.
							chit system and then mood of shops in front - SP wrote the letter.
						SP - Gurudas Pr in Vrindavan only chanting - Gurudas Pr said about Krishna's lila he wondered.
							his words were cement - what's esoteric about it - we need cement bags to finish fast.
						SP - What 6th verse of MA mean - he said distribute books - assist acaryas.
					Arjuna fought level best and abhimanyu died.
						Arjuna crying. Krishna crying why you crying - just spoke BG to you and see you crying so I cry.
					Vulture last rites - they not allowed in same queue as others.
						Nandigram to meet bharat b4 Bharat b4 Ayodhya.
						Hanuman warned Sophisticated place can't do monkey business.
						Ram asked hanuman to share the plate - can't eat with master - cut in banana leaf - paramatma and atma are different.
				QA from Ramayan
					Q - st we have luxury of time. Yes, but st we don't - leap of faith to be taken and test of service.
						st expectation to go beyond zone of comfort.
						what can I do best in a given situation
						SP - discouraging SP that why 44 years to coming to west - he was always busy every 11 years.
						Modern education system is major disadvantage in bhakti - from personal experience - understand eth then you can do. Deeply ingrained.
						Inconceivable for anything you can't answer is not liked by intellectuals.
						Advanced devs depend on mercy of Krishna. Must do.
						Must shoot for Rhinos and success will come.
						Life interesting - our plans and leave rest to Krishna - power shows up while doing.
					Q - Ram banishing Sita devi controversy.
						Ram experiencing mood of separation - enhanced love.
						King responsibility - must establish justice no matter what.
							touched by another man 7 suspected - queen has to be above suspicion.
						Ram generally people accept but Krishna - from his glance and posture to pastimes eth is curved.
						Can't live without Krishna - so many SB classes - for every SG some shloka comes - dukh yonaya eva te.
						bath mantras - tilaks mantras - not possible - we won't come outta bathroom if do them all.
						India has very few players. Many commentators. HK MM - you chant, grandfather did it. Good - should do it. You go, I will come.
						2 cricket player come together don't ask - chanted rounds? no, cricket so KK in dev circle.
					Q - Ramayan
						check the source which Ram is he talking about - who told - some priest, milkman coming ed.
						anyone can claim anything I am king of england. That's speciality of madhouse.
						Authority in every field - mobile correct to Prabhu chant some mantra - I know one svaha and dangerous consultant.
						Invest money - what to do - returns are eternal so paper give this side. Financial consultation.
						Grandmother which university for higher studies - go to galli school - parantha.
						Do research and go to USA - remembering your parantha while eating pizza.
						Research in acads but spirituality anything goes - hanuman chalisa cuz grandmother said.
						SB ppl think granny's tales b4 going to bed. We have learnt in youth by SP's mercy.
						West only 1 window - Indians 33 crore windows to choose from.
						In case it is not Krishna - keep all windows open - play safe - take as per your capacity. I take no risks.
					Q - Vali killed from behind trees
						animal can be killed from any angle anywhere. Regular warfare kshatriya rules don't apply.
						was enjoying with tara - usurping 7's wife so criminal - right to kill sinful.
						Sugriva had asked for protection irrespective of situation.
						Radha criticises Krishna - Vali shot from behind the trees so you have cheating mentality.
			</JatayuAndQA>
			<HanumanSeries>
			S2 - Hanuman
			L1 - Love of Ram
				characters mahajan in Ramayan - like superman we have hanuman for those who haven't heard.
				Sun thought as apple - Rahu came in the way so ran after him also - Indra intervened with thunderbolt - cracked chin so hanuman (1 with cracked chin)
				Vayu said you mistreated my son so revoking air from earth. So much power that you can't imagine - all demigods blessings.
				iccha mrityu, no effect of my weapon, etc.
				Naughty activities with so much power - putting huts on fire, jump on backs and pull hair, etc.
				Many sages tried to curse but won't work cuz benediction. Mantra to forget powers to avoid misuse. Narad Veena stolen to get lotus feet dust.
				Hospet few miles Hampi - cave birthplace anjanadri, all around is kishkindha.
				He was 1 to tell about Sita's whereabouts and inform Ram.
				Big ocean throwing into the ocean - Hanuman laughing at squirrel throwing small stone - e1 doing serve at their capacity so don't laugh.
				Ram written on stone and thrown into water - it would float. Ram tried throwing on his own - No need to write the name cuz I am Ram. What happened? It drowned
					embarassed no1 should be seeing - Hanuman was behind.
					Why this happened - day and age to not float the stone - allow your name to do the job and it can uplift us - ?If you renounce 7 then no hope.
				Ravan also watching this bridge creation from distance - asked mandodari what to do - fight starts. They used to worship demigoddess for power - Ravan hid behind deity and Rakshasas.
					You have made mistakes and must repent - what should we do - bring laddus and kheer in huge quantity and now you go away - eat the whole.
					After that hanuman kicked and punched all of them.
				Pushpak viman - airplane with dimensions which can be increased.
					Monkeys wanted to see ayodhya - what you think - very risky and uncontrolled these monkeys - we have pushpak.
					strict instructions - you monkey business won't work - behave yourself - follow me and do what I do.
					feast prasadam for all of them - monkeys like chickpeas. Hanumanji pressed and rascal you jumped up leaving cover in the hand and jumped to eat it.
					Monkeys followed along - Ramji saw from above and saw dancing kirtan going on. They followed me blindly.
					Ram said - I can't repay what you did for me, I can't repay - I wish confortable stay here.
				Kunkum Sita put in hindu tradition - what's purpose - Ram sees then pleased and happy - if little Kunkum does it, he covered his body with Kunkum.
					Came in front of Ram - red lump jumping but with tail - why red like tomato - Hanuman explained - Ram laughed - I pleased with your simplicity - only concerned with Ram not public.
				B4 Aryodhya went to Nandigram Bharat and prasadam there also.
					all seats covered - Ram concerned said you come and we will share the plate - but how same plate - no I will make division on banana plate.
					1 more devotee and no time - Narad M preached - Appointment diary it is full you can see - bathroom toilet then chant there - Never thought about it.
					Hanumanji heard and wanted to see the person - chanting pure name in impure place so let him come out and slapped when came out.
					Ram holding his face and scar on his face - 7 slapped my devotee; my devotee chants name anywhere it purifies so no excuse.
					Try chanting the name st - invest 15 mins a day for month - tried different things in life - doesn't work give it up but you will see difference and experience change.
			L2 - obstacles on the way to Lanka
				All monkeys on the on the look out.
				Angad says we gotta cross the ocean. Jambavan asking each monkey - 5, 10, 20, 50.
					Jambavan old now - 21 times could but now only 90. Angad - 100 I can but no strength to return.
					Leader should not go across the ocean. Jambavan sees at hanuman and says he can do it.
					All the fogotten power reminded.
					Mount mahindra will be good launching pad - expands and huge, gigantic - e1 sees hanuman size and gets bewildered even sages.
				Hanuman's mission to find Sita - we are on hanuman mission to find bhakti.
					we also gotta jump 100 yojans to get to find our bhakti.
					sadhana service sadachar - so much to do to get there.
				Sadhana Lesson Mainak under ocean - had relation with hanuman's father vayu
					We get opportunities to take rest and get complacent in sadhana - allure to relax our efforts in KC.
					Since the goal is very far and real taste in bhakti is not there yet so relaxation is possible.
					SP - when calamity on devotee, his faith dwindles and becomes complacent.
						SP - proof of good chanting is after 16 rounds you ask why only 16 why not more. We think why not less.
					Any service with time you can do with eyes closed eventually but chanting you can't do - you think so and next moment you dose.
					Life is a mission not intermission.
					Material life like onion - every peel brings tears.
					Why Krishna doing this to me - is he not keeping track of my 16 rounds.
					Problems and rather than taking shelter of Krishna, we think of problem or parallel processing.
					Your JD is to worry - when do I get my first cheque - that's your first worry.
					Japa of SP - and you hear - Sit properly. Posture, Pronunciation and pace for good chanting.
					SP - sleep too much then lazy else crazy.
					St old conditionings cause losing faith.
					Starts with little complacency which grows with time.
					SP - 1 dev too much into yoga that forgot HK chanting - All of your problems cuz of rasayans not proper
						brake not working - which rasayan you would use and SP peacefully chanting - it's back - nothing can protect us from BODD.
					Jananivas Pr sits in Bengali class - sound vibration is purifying.
					Mind wants to give reasons to not do bhakti - bhakti is good but not so much.
				Service Lesson - Surasa - comes with mouth wide open - brahma's benediction to pass thru my mouth - eat e1 -
					Allow me to go and get back then you can eat me.
					10 yojans - 20, 30, 50. 100 - Hanuman became very tiny and entered your mouth.
					I fulfilled your condition - You are very intel monkey.
					False pride in doing one's service - who is better competition
					Brahmin very particular at gayatri and kali woke him up. You are same or changed
						You would have felt if you missed - humble and great advancement so made you do it to stay proud.
					Competition and conflict - law of gravity in spiritual circles - More you go up, great chances of fall. Lighter, Krishna will lift.
					Humility - eager to serve others or be served, glorify Krishna or myself, thinking of Krishna or myself.
						When false pride comes it's already fallen; only detail comes later.
						We start from dasanudas to das to...mahaprabhu.
					Hare tortoise story extended.
						Individual race.
						Hare pride.
						Different route - even river this time - tortoise won.
						Friends now - reached destination fastest on the toughest route - switched the role and enjoyed experience.
						Not competing against each other but challenges together.
					Difference of opinion with another devotee - it proves mayavad is bogus said SP.
					KC is not black or white - 1 is right does not mean other is wrong.
					SP - 1 dev said Krishna is black and Balaram is white. Yamuna mataji said no Krishna enjoys Radha.
						He is right. She is right but both contradictory how can both be right - yes you are right. Who is right - you decide.
						Eth can't be understood by logic and reasoning.
					Took humble position and conflict was resolved.
					Other religions to get free of sins but SP gave us freedom from false pride
					Rupa G to Jiva - I already sign - you mentality not fit for vrindavan.
					LCM defeated prakashanand sarasvati thru his humility not scholarship.
					LCM's childhood friend - book on logic and grammar or I also written but who will read mine now - forget my book threw in ganges.
				Dealings and Relationship - Sindhika - grabs Hanuman's shadow - could not move thru mystic power.
					straight into mouth, heart and pierced her.
					dealings and relationships are we critical or appreciative.
					Nature of envy - you see dark and pull down the person.
					Original envy is why Krishna is god. Original desire is why not I god.
					God as oridinary and I as special is mayavad.
					SP - My book. Plz tell. Many notes. Now swami will tell about my book. Yes, this book is bogus don't read this mayavad.
						Bewildered cuz big program for his book launch. Sorry I can't compromise.
					We have to struggle and destory it in the heart.
					Not vedantists but be-dant-ist - vaishnavas have removed this poisonous teeth.
					So many swamis think they are god what you think - they are bogus - sth more - yes one more that they are rascals.
					Any good quality in others we don't like - origin is that against Krishna.
					Story - Only 1 hand judo teacher only 1 trick - continuous practice you mastered lethal trick - only 1 defense hold left hand you didn't have one so won the tournament.
						Rather than what you don't have - maximize what you have.
					Krishna - you didn't give me that which you gave him or her - appreciate what we have and others - not critical or criticize.
					Free from burden of getting appreciation.
					SP - Shyamsundar Pr - 1 dev had to go jail for previous offense - fearful of confronting SP cuz putting bad name.
						gotta go to jail - Krishna was born in jail. Selling drugs b4 - I had pharmacy so drugs. Chant HK there.
						SP gave feedback right way for different feeling.
					Painting - Radha's hand with garland away from Krishna - oh another boyfriend she observed - no she liked your painting so offering garland to you.
					You neglect me I will not forgive. You encourage me I will never forget you.
					SP - This leader not chanting HK 16 rounds. Arjuna didn't chant on battlefield. I never thought this way - concentrate on yourself don't look at him.
						Thanks for telling me I didn't know.
					Many marriages - I am not encouraged or appreciated enough.
					If you wanna dig gold - dig thru tons of dirt to get there.
					Put pressure on carbon and it becomes diamond.
					With binaculars we can see far off clearly. ISKCON is the one for Krishna.
					12 mahajans - 1 said SP you are 13th and SP said you are 14th.
					Hanuman reached lanka - so grand and beautiful.
				Preaching - Took form of cat searching for Sita. Lankini stops.
					no1 enters - no1 can enter without permission so leave - she was about to punch hanuman - hanuman slaps timely and she fell apart.
					The day monkey slaps you brahma said the destruction of ravan starts.
					Spreading mission of Lord Ram in areas just like lanka where influence of demoniac influences prevail. Rakshasas are strong.
					Opposition and stopped by lankini like people. What's you business here - this destroys our enthu.
					Hanuman just became fearless when faced with opposition.
					Once preaching and child asked mother - who is he - she said bhoot. The child later will think bhoot and temples bhoot bangla.
					SP - here MIT where is almighty - There is opposition.
						SP why this mud on your head - why this tie on neck - never thought about it - sit down and think about it.
						questions be relevant not this non-sense questions like this - on dress and all.
					Indian asked SP - why preaching in west - why you came here? - I for higher prospects.
						Tell them gita they say we already know gita. We can teach you some gita.
						e1 is guru there.
					SP - controversial question - who is greater - MK Gandhi or me - he drove them out and I engage them in my service. I don't pay him anything.
						no business man can understand this.
					1 joined temple - parents sent his other son and he also joined.
						why kept both my sons - from streets and here so gentleman so you should gimme donation.
						I already donated my sons - SP said thank you very much.
				Hanuman solved all these obstacles with right attitude - all the demons representations - service attitude, fearless preaching, etc.
					next we explore hanuman's childhood pastimes and what follows his search for Sita Devi.
			L3 - Lanka Visit
				Jambavan tells story how he forgot power - due to offense heavenly damsel born as anjana.
					Vayudev in charge of wind enchanted to see her - gonna beget son thru you.
					gave birth to stout looking monkey called hanuman.
					saw sun and thought to be fruit and leaped to eat it.
					E1 scared what will happen when later he grows up.
					sun didn't disturb and arranged chariot - rahu interrupted.
					indra's airavat next target. Hanu maan - vayu resentment.
					Blessings - effulgence, no weapons, no curse effect, etc.
					Even more powerful now - disrupt sacrifices and pull beards, jump on their backs, etc.
					Kesari told not the misbehave but no change - e1 came together to resolve that make him forget his power.
				On reaching lanka, becomes a small cat and looks for Sita Devi.
					Unable to find Sita anywhere - beautiful palace must be Ravan's.
					Intoxicated women partially dressed enjoying with person must be Ravan - his thought if only he engaged in KC.
					Saw beautiful lady besides Ravan - could be Sita but no - how can she enjoy independent of Ram.
					I am seeing women and observing closely - is that correct for brahmacari like me.
					inapt - deeply analysing his motives. Search for horses, then gotta look in stable.
					My motive is clear - not agitated and bewildered cuz specific guided mission.
					St services for lord which involve interactions with material energy.
						Then one can remain protected.
					SP - 1 person turning away from money photo - take my photo other way round cuz engaged in Krishna's service.
					Kurma Brahmin wanted to leave - LCM said no don't do it. Sthane sthita.
				Tried homes, forests, etc - Depression.
					Objective not achieved then depression comes. Frustration when setbacks.
					overcome by doubts - Maybe Sita's no longer alive.
					Lots of time analysing maybe what all could have gone wrong - jumped from vimaan, suicide, Ravan cut her, etc.
					What has happened, why it must have happended and What will happen.
					Ram will definitely leave his body on leaving body, lakshman will leave. 2 bros also - Ayodhya people will.
					Sugriva thinking that he could not - suicide and also leaders. So why return let me do it now only.
					FEAR - False evidence appearing real. Dark room where negatives develop.
					Once Vanars decided to do ekadashi - but won't have energy to jump the tree, pluck the fruit, keep fruit close, chew it, let us eat only - I have eaten.
						How mind works.
					Full of doubts then only enthu, patience - nishcayat dhairyat.
					determination enthu for all bliss in 1 sanskrit bliss.
				I will find with effort - Krishna helped - saw a tree - yogakshem vahamyaham, ye yatha maam.
					Effulgent Lady must be Sita - Fire covered by smoke, vedic text misinterpreted, hope shattered, intellect misused.
					Ravan there to entice Sita - I have tried all efforts please agree.
					Cupid's arrow of Lust - Harshanam (joy), smaranam (remembrance), rocanam (demanding), karshanam (pain), roshanam (no appetite and weakness), maranam (die).
					SP - 1 beautiful lady passed by and 1 dev kept looking and realized his mistake and saw at SP; SP looking at him.
						when shameful. SP said beautiful wasn't she - didn't know what to say - If worldly beauty is so charming how beautiful Krishna must be.
					She puts grass in front of Ravan with smirk. Many interpretations by different sampradaya.
					She tried all sam daam danda bhed with Ravan.
						protect me like other wives (saam) else ppl rejoice on your death (Bhed)
						Ram will give you jeevan daan (daam) and gifts else he will destroy you (dama)
					Ravan angry on this - I am tolerating you and you chastise - if she doesn't agree chop her up and I will have her for my lunch.
					Sita planning to use braid for suicide - Hanuman thought must gotta come outta incognito.
					She screams and ladies wake up and then soldiers and then e1 will know - Must convey s.t Ram and Sita's interests are protected.
					SP - particular at presenting per TPC. In english and distribution on streets no1 knew.
						SP - Your distributors are ew book book book ew; they are bookworms - better than stool worm.
				Ravan like contaminated mind; Sita like Jiva and teacher has come for message. Qualities of Jiva to qualify.
					Guru gives message when disciple is bona fide.
					Ramanujacarya says qualities that teacher sees and to be redeemed
					ekagra (concentrated) - allurements could not distract her - could not be chief queen but resists maya.
						1 dev in Vrindavan would chant only 2 lines of SA4 - next 2 lines too difficult - LCM has given highest standard.
						SP - Brajvasis - even if given 1 crore won't give up Krishna's service all claps including students; you are not yet tested but confident.
					adhyaya vasaya - faith in power and mercy of lord - I will chop and devour you and Ram is anyways gonna be killed.
						faith that avashya rakshibe Krishna - You are master and I am your dog says BVT protect me.
					Aadar - reverence for seniors, instructors, guru - Hanumanji appeared as monkey.
						could have felt a normal monkey and Ram geet that this is messenger of Lord Ram and no disqualification
						not just forest animal but Lord's representative.
						SP - BSS told SP to distribute books and preachi in english
						Hayagriva typed few pages - anymore typing work - full of SB purports in trunk - many lifetimes of work.
					Anusuya - lack of envy
						complete trust in words of instructor - responses to KK - reject, doubt the intent, misinterpret, 4th one - ?accept.
						bull goes around and water comes out - 1 machine in India.
							bell so that I know he is working - what if he keep shaking head - he is not logician like you.
						SP - why chanting HK nw in Upanishads - what you think upanishads say - continued for 10 mins - finished - then demolished his args for 20 mins.
							after st questioner said can we have kirtan.
					Qualified then KK and 2nd task after nourishment is protection.
						Sita gave ring for id.
						Ravan and his men - 2nd part starts.
						How to destroy evil propensities in mind - mind holds soul captive in current state.
				Asuras encountered
					Forest destroyed.
					Prahasta - defeat
					Jambamali - do you wanna get killed - mission of Ram so no1 can kill me.
						Even indra on flag post and 9 grahas do cooking in kitchen.
						release Sita devi - let me finish - 80K soldiers and stone pelting on them.
						arrows and held his arrows and threw back.
						mantras to increase his size and hanuman coming till his ankles.
						Closed to be even more big and then saw 2 big circles.
						Those are my knees said Hanuman that was my capacity - any soldier to help - no1 responded
						I kept Ravan's sth on them and they died peaceful - that's maya - what are you doing.
						Chant name of Lord ram - with Index finger on his naval threw on ground.
					Indrajeet - garuda pasha and personalities - so bound.
						how monkey could do it - give sitting place for messenger.
						No animals - sit on trees - so I have to become less than animal to sit here.
						kill him. Ok I will make my own place and twisted tail with height greater than Ravan - now we can talk.
						So angry - kill him - no you can't kill a doot - monkeys love their tail put it on fire.
						Another part of his mission was done - seeing fortification and formations for defense, etc.
					Tail set on fire.
						Few verses on power of anger. Bona fide engagement of anger eg but he says.
						Still dangerous he says - lanka set on fire what if ashoka vatika goes on fire.
						Give up anger like snake gives up his skin
						Gang to visit temple and collect Lord's mercy for chappals and thieves photo we have taken.
						Group of devs waiting for them - give them mahaprasad - why was I not called 7 said.
						comes back to Sita Devi - you are best of vanars - only vayu and garuda could cross this ocean
						How will others do - idea of profit adoration and distinction - imagine getting it from Sita Devi and that too seems true.
						He said it's not true - e1 in sugriva's army is either equal to me to better than me. No false humility.
						I can prove this - messenger is a postman - warrior or generals are not sent as messenger - imagine havoc they can create.
						Lord Ram - 1 crore mahaoagh monkeys he was managing - anyone claims to be god give them 3 monkeys to manage.
			L4 - After returning from Lanka.
				Hanumanji position as acarya.
					Krishna has relationship with jiva - leaves and suffering for both jiva and more so for ishwar.
					What efforts Krishna makes to reclaim jiva in the world.
					Shri Sampradaya writes a lots; other sampradayas also write on Ramayan.
					Sita not equated to jiva but analogy is given.
					SP writes Devaki represents bhakti - VCT present these insights. not literally.
					Ravan holds soul captive - 10 heads represent karma and jnana indriyas.
					Divine messenger is sent to reclaim the souls - the messenger is very beautiful in the eyes of the Lord so sundar kand.
					Soul foolishly thinks that ocean and forts are impregnable - only hanuman like acaryas can relieve the soul.
					Such preachers are very dear to me says Krishna
					Lankini is goddess of lanka or represents power of lanka - represents false ego - surrendered to Ravan.
					Ego is there => can't make further progress.
					Lankini stopped onwards journey of Hanuman but got a slap - ego prevents guru from making influence and guru fights back.
					preceptor thus has important duty so gotta bombard jiva's ego.
					All pleasures surrounding Ravan. Should not see undressed women - apt under Krishna's guidance.
					Even helper may get influenced by the contaminated mind (?ecosystem) - so need powerful KC.
					Entered lanka but didn't let lanka enter him - preach as per one's capacity.
					Purity is the force SP says.
				Hanuman was best messenger against Ravan - cuz Hanuman had conquered lust.
					how had he mastered lust - by love for Lord Ram. He stayed uncontaminated in the culture of Lust.
					Effect of preaching as per our purity.
					SP was free from lust - got down from vyas asana - obeissance cuz I am free from lust.
						Driver speaking thru mirror to SP - some kinda swami - sit on nails for meditation - can sit among room full of naked women and unaffected - wooh!
						@kabaddi - as per capacity you go deep or not.
						Hefty guy - casually kabaddi-n and e1 holds and turns to come back. thinner guys just say kabaddi once and come back - at least safe.
					Sita in grief separated from Lord - so are we without KC.
						4 kinda people come to Lord - arto, artharthi, jijnasu, jnani.
						In kali arto is prominent.
						walking like zombie under unconscious state - mind holds captive and tortures like Ravan.
						Hanuman sings song of Lord Ram - Sita rejuvenated. Guru creates hope in soul - possible to get association of Lord.
					7 phases of vayu - his son being hanuman - 7*7 = 49.
					Saturday important for worshipping hanumanji for this reason - 7 is important number for him.
					Hanuman makes analysis of situation and recommends to SPOG.
					Hanuman presents his case to Lord Ram. Guru presents case to Krishna.
				Why he does all this - WIIFM - Lord's embrace.
					Ram is waiting for reports or results - should I say I found Sita.
					I...didn't find Sita, found dead, etc - may collapse outta anxiety, expectation.
					Sita...was found, by me, dead, not alive, is gone, etc - Sita is safe.
					Finally he said Found Sita I - mood and emotion more important than grammar at that time.
						Of course, won't talk about Ravan.
				Dhanushkodi from where bridge starts.
					Thin piece of land making starts - even now some small tract of land goes inside.
					I have nothing to offer you - no money, etc so only embrace. Risks you have taken.
					This is what they hanker for - vanar means - va means like a man. Like man, monkey.
					Vrindavan - deadly monkeys - glasses stolen - better vision - taking away out position; we taking away Krisha's position.
					SP - banana and showed. and negotiation skills. Offer them sth and then they return it.
					va nar - like man in only appearance but beyond - godly - representing Krishna.
					Only reward is pleasure of Lord.
					Hanuman so satisfied that stays in material world - let me stay for your mission.
				Plans on attacking Lanka
					Vibhishan's advise to surrender - not worth it - enemy in guise of relative so go away.
					Comes to Lord Ram - friends, relatives may object with our dev's association.
					He had to make decision of coming to Lord Ram - no email discussions or confirmation but in uncertainty faith is tested.
					Will Lord accept - reliable sources - bhakta vatsal, deen vatsal, deen bandhu, deen nath so will give shelter.
					Based on what's heard will also work out - that's iota of faith.
					logic and reason help but stop at a point and there is a leap of faith.
					Other people like Sugriva and monkeys started blaspheming - being misunderstood is painful.
					Aage kuan peechhe khai was his situation - the message can be twisted - he is a spy for sure - born in lanka.
					We base our judgment based on where 7 is born - maybe demon like Ravan but some demon.
					Angad allow but set spies for him.
					Hanuman - you opinion - his face and intent pure and clear - left opulence at risk to take shelter.
						with faith that lord gives shelter.
					Sugriva - You don't know the clans and they are too dangerous. May set fire to our camps at night.
					Ram - about their power. You know who you are talking to - I am SPOG by the way.
						bring all species in front of me - most formidable rakshasas, danavas, etc - I can crush them with my index finger crush.
						My firm vow for all times to come - 7 comes in front of me - not even with full commitment - tava asmi - My dear Ram, I am yours.
						should become fearless. I make them fearless.
						See who standing outside - requesting my protection - even if Ravan requesting I will give him - unconditionally.
					Sugriva - Vibhishan is nice person. I will bring him in.
				So many pastimes during the fight.
				Hanumanji reports to Sita that Ramji victorious - craving for this.
					want to reward with opulence of this creation - my master, all rakshasis tormented you. Let me kill them.
					Under control of Ravan. Don't resort to such behavior.
					Sita Devi tells a story - Tiger chasing man and beer sleeping - man climbs - common enemy so throw him down.
						No he has taken my shelter. So won't.
						tiger plays politics - throw the bear down so opportunist and bear will taken away and you safe.
						bear seduced to throw the man saying that see what he did to you - no must stick to my dharma.
				Returned pastimes
					Vanars taken to Nandigram - banana leaf plate division.
						represent lord shares all opulence with jivas surrendered.
						also represents that jiva and Lord are separate.
					Ayodhya - we will follow hanuman - thanks for allowing us inside.
						jumping in front of me not in my control. Standard way of eating must be to jump and eat - blindly following me.
					Sita - kunkum powder - logic so if I cover my body with kunkum.
						dancing - red figure jumping up and down.
						Pleased with your simplicity only concerned with pleasing me and not public
					New schedules for seva - his name is nw
						we decided that so much service that made up for years of seva.
						no1 to do chutki when Ram yawns.
						Hanuman constantly sitting so gotta clap my fingers so must sit constantly. Greedy to serve Krishna to any capacity.
						Intimate associate of Lord Ram.
					Bedi Hanuman - high tide used to flood deities.
						Pandas to prevent flooding - hanuman can control - staying as guard.
						Bored by eating khicadi. Ayodhya had so much opulence - puris, sabjis, laddus, kachoris.
						Service is right but want some good prasad.
						Ayodhya feast and next morning came back - ocean god waiting for this chance
						disappeared - jagannath why you left - from now on - special laddus made of dry fruits to him.
						but our faith is shattered - maybe fed up of laddus - chain around his legs so agreement.
						Dakshina to pujari and he shows the bedi to you.
					Many spiritualists in India - dvati, advaita, mayavad, Vainavite, demigod worshippers and khicadi.
						all of them agree that hanuman is wonderful.
						Gyms in India have murti of hanumanji - gimme power of muscle - but don't know spiritual side.
						Need a girl for marriage from hanumanji - he is brahmacari - that's why - he will be detached to give me.
				May we get power to engage in service without need for credits and all.
					same spirit of giving credits to others and not want for ourselves.
			</HanumanSeries>
			</GaurangaPr>
		<Book>
			<Kandas>
				About - Location where Ram is.
				<Baal></Baal>
				<Ayodhya></Ayodhya>
				<Aranya></Aranya>
				<Kishkindha></Kishkindha>
				<Sundar></Sundar>
				<Yuddha></Yuddha>
				<Uttar></Uttar>
			</Kandas>
		</Book>
		<Misc>
			Ramayan
				Use and throw - to demoralize vanar sena. it was ineffective day. but ram would perform rites
				we pray for service but more so service attitude.
				mimimal service and max returns is material world limitation - both server and client.
				bhavna + kalpana - makes angry combination - bharat coming with army.
				Ram said - bhavnayein to alankar hain but encourage those that take us towards dharma.
						emotions give fuel to life. but are agitated in life so that we don't use intelligence (ads to paralyse intel until you buy)
			SQ - Ram katha Triggers (Different states that characters were in)
				Conflict on sacrifices
				Bharat M and Shatrughna gone to uncle.
				Dashrath
					birth - potencies.
					corronation
						Kaikeyi's suspicion
							Exile
							Bharat's rejection and bro appeasement.
				Vashishta
					Studies - amicable brotherhood.
				Vishvamitra
					sacrifices resuming - engagement (Maricha escapes); profuse weapons
					marriage plan - Sita and sisters.
				Shurpanakha
					wants grats - confrontation and rejection - attack - bleeding nose - Ravan provocation.
				Ravan
					Anti-devotional.
					infatuated with lust for Sita
						Alliance with Maricha
						Kidnapping - Jatayu, Jewels fall in Kishkindha.
				Ram
					exile
					searching - found Hanuman and kishkindha where jewels were.
					Alliance with Sugriva against vali.
					Bridge
					Fight
				Hanuman
					Searching - lead from jatayu's brother.
					Lanka exploration - Sita's found and confidence, fortification understood.
					Informed.
					Sanjeevani
			SQ - Ramayan FOE
				chronological important series of events and their sequencing
		</Misc>
	</Ramayan>
	<KrishnaLila> Ref Krishna book; Radha Govind Swami
		Spirit - Take a pastime - Meditation over small details, sanskrit words, trans aspect focus (tell about Krishna's NGRL, philosophy accompanied), Relate.
		<JanmaLila>
			<Lecture1>
			BG - janma karma ca me divyam
			Intro
				divya means aalokik - svarg - here aprakrit - spiritual.
					no more birth - where he goes? Back to me.
				Place, day we discussing KK is our fortune.
				bhaga+vaan - all opulence + possessor - Vishnu purana parashar defines 6 ops.
					outta respect also - bhagavan narad, shuka, maitreya but also a vaastavik artha - that's Krishna only.
			Arjuna told that gave to Ikshvaku - that's so long back.
				when comes? dharma ki glani, etc.
				what you do? destroy, protect, establish dharma.
			7th garbha uda diya - ppl thought thru tantrik - Rohini transferred thru yoga maya.
				anshon ke saath Krishna enterred
			Vasudev 1 name - anant dundubhi - trumpet. He will be father to God.
				all demigods waited for Vasudev after forecast - played these 2 instruments.
				atoms in earth can be counted by all demigods (not possible as such) but not my names and qualities.
			Kamsa maara gya not that I killed. Krishna's said.
			He appeared in the mind - not thru maithun or dhatu.
				He started glowing like sun. No1 can see sun directly - such tej that no1 could see - even for 7 to appreoach difficult - defeating very.
				He transplanted Krishna to the mind to Devaki - she accepted like moon (anandkar)
				sun and moon analogies - tej utna nahi bikher rahe the.
				janma nahi diya - mool karana nahi - east direction doesn't give birth to sun or prachi disha to moon.
				Krishna is svayambhu but can be dharan not originated.
				What resides in Krishna - resides inside Devaki.
				Had Krishna but not sushobhit - like knowledge holder doesn't share or light inside a pot.
					so attraction to Krishna not possible in there - Devaki if she gave pravacan then upakar possible but not possible here in prison.
					If SP didn't share, that would not have been good.
					That's why Vaishnavas must preach - first establish Krishna in oneself and then share it with others.
			Kamsa went to see - he must have kept track thru calendars or whatever ?or thru ppl. Or just to meet.
				Karagrih looked beautiful - anand ew - prison became dham.
				Suci means clean but also sukh - mild smile on Devaki.
				If iron pot has hot coal - the pot will also burn - she also showed happiness, forgetting all pain of previous children.
				He estimated hari gonna hara my praana is gonna appear.
					Kalanemi had killed me b4 - Narada had told - jaan maara tha.
					He knew the potential and power of hari - cuz she wasn't that pleasurable b4.
					She used to be in great pain.
			Kamsa thoughts on Seeing Devaki happy
				Vaikuntha left and is here - death is here - he will definitely kill - is closer now than b4.
				He thought let's now better kill devaki only - uterus also gone but Krishna's presence non-violent and compassion - no, no!
				I can't degrade my name for history. Woman, sister, respected man I am.
					My age, opulence, reputation will be all gone. Brahma reduces life span.
				she was man b4 in previous life.
				Person who lives at killing others - that life is worthless - strange it is that kills child easily but not killing sister.
				Torturing jivas for oneself has no right to live - killing human and animals to live.
				Outta fear, ppl don't say on his face but after his death, wish all bad to him. Wish all hell to him.
				Muhavara - Kaji's dog died e1 went (to please him). Kaji died, no1 went (he doesn't matter anymore)
				after death - natural diet for vultures, jackals - why keep decorating it.
				Hell is tamah literally - no light department there only st when 7 is to be burnt - torturing one's relative goes there.
					Kamsa was better off than ppl of these days - believed in hell.
				Prabhu addressed to Kamsa - such defeating one's nature.
					Devs prabhu not ishwar but suppress the lower nature. ?also my master attitude.
			but enmity for God is not gone - explicitly mentioned by Shukadev.
				such wait is inspirational to devs - shown by Kamsa but was miserable cuz fear and envy. Envy was shishupal mainly - kamsa was mainly fear.
				very less sleep and there also thinking hari. In food, remembered Krishna.
				Unfavorable but very viscous remembrance.
				He's gonna kill asuras but I am top on hitlist ain't gonna leave me.
				Used to talk vishnu with others also.
				Vishnu chhal and kapati coming as child but gonna kill - like masking as innocent so gotta kill he thought.
				He saw world vishnu-maya. Janmashtami day like us must have fasted.
			All demigods appeared to Kamsa or Krishna
				Terrorists had made life into hell at that time.
				Krishna natavar and shiva nataraj - devs waiting for Krishna like chatak.
					demigods like elephants - pained by heat waiting for the rain - agha, etc asuras very torturous.
					We have come like them not vv - giving your analogy is not considered ok.
				Baby in womb is bent and scorched but praised at that time.
				You are satya sankalp - you said you will come and here you are. Also satya vrata.
					1 vrata - many but 1 of them - If once you say, I am yours => I will make him fearless - In context of vibhishan he said.
					If ravan bro, then like him so arrest him - let him come with the attitude said Rama.
					His lilas are satya - our existence itself is not satya (temporary)
			QA? Here discussion on pastimes; let's take technical questions some other time; philosophical questions not vicharaniya (worth thinking) at this point.
			</Lecture1>
			<Lecture2></Lecture2>
		</JanmaLila>
		Baal Lila
		Braj Ras
		Dwaraka Lila
		<KrishnaBook>
			<VrindavanLila></VrindavanLila>
			<MathuraLila></MathuraLila>
			<DwarakaLila></DwarakaLila>
		</KrishnaBook>
	</KrishnaLila>
	<SB> Ref RNSM By Themes, By SP Book.

	</SB>
	<CC> Ref ?BCS, By SP Book.
		<HistoryOfGaudiyaVaishnavism>
			https://www.thespiritualscientist.com/2012/03/history-of-gaudiya-vaishnavism-ii-post-chaitanya-phase/
		</HistoryOfGaudiyaVaishnavism>
	</CC>
	<SP> Ref Prabhupada Lilamrita; Various devotees.

	</SP>
</Lila>