<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Lila>
	<MB> Ref - Govinda Pr, Krishna dharma Pr book
		<About>
			3 lessons (explained by CCP)
				writer's view - lessons from the story.
					allegories permitted to supplement not supplant
				character's view - dielemma of life and choices => results.
				trans view - prakriti laws - karma, desire, Krishna.
		</About>
		<Kunti>
		Kunti - sthirata ki pratik.
			Story telling with deviations - dharma applications in focus.
			Prayers of Kunti - great sages appreciate
				sweet dish preparation has efforts - we forget that.
				happiness without gratitude then selfish.
				Problems tolerated and solved both.
				Hanuman - buddhi bhakti and kriya.
				fire incident - brahmin cuz no1 knew they didn't die
			Bakasur story - parallel govt - extorsion.
				relp bad that our relatives here so didn't leave - but praised.
				Husband has greatest duty; wife - no, wife gets exploited.
				fighting for self sacrifice giving reasons. Daughter b4 marriage anyways gotta go; and meaning of child.
				son is soul. wife is friend and daughter is danger. She says.
				sanskar that kido also said I will.
				In danger, we think that God should solve it - self danger is biggest e1 thinks.
				Kunti argues - no, not brahmin and that too first time.
					mamta but also confidence in the child.
					Pandavas - sangharsh in life so could tolerate anything and also solving.
					USA - opulence but no training for troubles.
				Bhima:Pandavas::50:50. Anti-socialism - equality should be based on purpose.
				Mama, why self sacrifice asks yudhistir - not MOI, greed or compulsion.
					Niti she says - Durbal raja - then should not stay there but we mistake that.
					decision based on discrimination not emotions.
					To Kaikeyi - anything you ask whether dharmik or not - that's emotion driven. Decision beyond rights.
					I have confidence and track record.
					Weak women in India? You have never read these sections.
				Fat guy and eating - bhima ate it all - only veg not buffalo
					killed that guy and his friends ran away.
			In ajnat vas - Kunti stayed at Vidura that they had to return back and not take sanyas.
			Shanti duta - Kunti tells probs not to solve but informing about life.
				They should talk fight not peace. Says Kunti.
				Some son Came back defeated against enemy - better you were not born - die hero is better than dying everyday.
				How hard hearted that wishing my death - that's in ur interest. Fearful, no worker, misdirected compassion - that person never grows. That guy won.
			Kunti to yudhistir - never fear fight - once mucukunda given free kingdom - no I will fight and get it.
				to all 1 by 1 - Vali's wife not trusted so defeated.
				What I hate the most is Draupadi's mistreatment. Tolerating exploitation is favoring their behavior.
				Arjuna chose Krishna vs Narayani sena not that he will fight and I will see.
					I trust my effort and your prasad. Not burden on Krishna but shouldering.
					not habit of God solving eth - Medical seat cuz KC - when study is 50% how is it possible.
				When stri biased to mind or intel. samvedanshil and rational talks also - what a balance in Kunti.
				We don't get Amazon food - we gotta click - do research for the dishes - different types of rice for purpose.
					Pot also need to be understood - Pot guru asked not SB guru - not Krishna's will so tolerate but bake it b4 usage.
					so effort and relevant knowledge.
				1 devotee - cow devotee - why God not helped - Kerala didn't help and cow can't survive there.
					Good emotions but not enough - need system - kheer won't be made if agni aparadh, pot breaks, milk curdles.
					Suji slowly.
					food thrown not good - vivah sanskar - 350 crore in Karnataka - so honor prasadam.
			Madri - I better sati cuz can't handle 5 nurturing - too much sacrifices - no bias, ability to tolerate, have money so let me.
				done oneself is appreciated but Kunti deserves more for her life.
			MB - Bharat - our history starts not 1947 but bharat kula.
				Kaurava dushta - you wanna hear brave or cowards - both - cuz Isho knowledge and mis-knowledge both should be known.
				Pandava life, hari, vidura foresightedness.
				Kunti's determination and tolerance.
				Secular understanding of flag - Saffron sacrifice, surrender, strength white - peace and clean. Green - samriddhi, prosperity and hariyali.
				50-80% of eb life is same - so gotta deal so events some difference but same experiences.
					Puncture of car is fact not why God did that.
					Nothing that happens to us is special - it's law of nature - Garmi - it comes as per weather.
				We get and should get what we pay for - getting 90% with 50% effort - they can't handle.
					Poor In Guj got lottery could not handle and perturbed - after spending it all - he felt relaxed.
					Heart attack outta happiness st.
					Karma and yoga go together
					Rice what to do with it - Kunti made kheer. Not alcohol, khicadi.
				After dharma established symbol and literally after MB but Krishna leaving
					yudhistir going to forest we will come with you said praja.
					smaran se vanchit rahenge - BTG.
					Madhupati not kadwa pati she says - let there be difficulties - no1 names child as kunti.
					Company's name for extra money - Johnson
			Shurasena ki putri - kuntibhoj se adopted.
				adopted at 7 - but she handled that mental turmoil.
				changing family is a trauma for the child.
				I was rejected by my parents. But if good parents, then good; she becomes strong.
			Kunti ki pariksha
				Durvasa blessings who is famous for curse - curse high probability but which one would be question.
				Durvasa cursed Krishna also - different temple in Dwaraka.
				Happy - using her back as table for food. Mantra given.
				astrologers manipulating get impacts in life but sharing without manipulation is fine.
				That blessing became curse cuz of her getting idle curiosity - small mistake but huge results for life pain.
				Surya pranam ed but mantra - sorry - I must do what you called me for. What will society think.
					if you don't then I will have to curse you; your benediction giver; etc - ego of sungod.
				Moon lineage and sun covered then karna comes out - eclipse happens. Very talented but eclipsed intel.
					I had separation all the life - parents, adopters, sun's warning, husband, children, relations.
					Taken care by the adopters.
					She Prayashcit thru the life - Vyasa dev - you are strong and clean so can digest it. You are not faulty.
				Population explosion problem vs what population is doing the problem.
			Kunti used Karna for self centered purpose - No, to avoid fight of MB that would happen.
				That's the wording of karna that people take - She does not plead or beg.
				Even small mistake of touching 10K Volts - it's gonna pain a lot.
			Kunti unlike Ramayan Kaushalya was equivalent of Sita in Lanka
				She is like heaven devi - Success - yash.
				Gandhari also troubled life - but no yash - anger against god that cursed.
				Life is happiness and trouble combination.
				Curious place earth - car but on a run - beggar but can stay.
					experience of dualities of life - pride and happiness of such powerful kids.
				Kunti's pleasure was kids. Draupadi's fortune to have Kunti and vv.
					both took care of Pandavas while others were away.
				She was healthy balance of sukh and sangharsh.
				Stick fight in Kerela - that's life - flexibility to face village life - st rain, st hot, etc.
					Sports should relieve of mental stress not increase it - we need sports Counselors
					Great soul but durvasa service is like living in dense forest but also literally later.
					Can't be artificial - clearing once is yogi - so artificial tryst and become hydrogen bomb.
					Got used to forest but go get justice.
					Begging does not get you justice but alms.
			2nd part
			Struggle in every phase of material world - Satya yuga also - hiranyaksha.
				1 willing to kill child, what would he do to praja.
				Kaliyuga - good people don't have strength and bad people also don't have strength.
				Krishna appeared cuz kings who have rakshasa mentality. That was greater than current times so Krishna appeared - dualities are always there - he does not keep appearing.
				All rakshasas not street goons.
				Life should be seen as a game. Tired but continues - defeated then depressed but continues next day.
				thru Kunti, give weightage to dukha sukha as much as needed not more - KY philosophy.
				MB e1 has read but how many really idolize Kunti, etc.
				Our sanskars => Our ruchi or interests in life. So, we feel sleepy reading MB, etc.
				Shoes shop asking for law details. Seeking wrong thing at wrong place.
				Garbha sanskar - gora hoshiyar and healthy - no1 says samarthya vaan - doing good for others.
				narrow minded - don't think about others but only oneself.
				Krishna's all marriages - in turmoil. Krishna didn't want to marry cuz treta I caused pain to Sita.
				Satrajeet alleges Krishna and all started questioning even relatives and praja - then Krishna acted.
				Lakshagriha - they stayed for 1 year as prince - so staying in place that can be set on fire anyday thru the year.
				Bheem - Hidimba - sin of rejecting valid marriage proposal. Ghatotkach was arranged by demigods as shield for Arjuna to kill Karna. So, they also scheme. but we goota do our part.
					another with Draupadi - controversial - and why not - even that time it was not accepted.
					Some so called scholars - Culture of exploitation - Seniors always exploiting juniors. Guru asking BD from junior. So socialism - so is their consciousness - even they see child exploiting mother thru breastfeed by waking her up.
					so need to hear from vyas.
				Draupadi - heard about her original and kautuhal which Kunti saw and arranged for them to go.
					Arjuna attacked in the way - defeated and asked by attacked - no guru and no grihastha after brahmacarya - not stable.
					Drona was not spiritual guru but martial guru. So go to dhaumya rishi.
					Guru comes to you vs you go to guru - latter is better.
					all in forest - dhaumya was there to guide.
					stayed at Shudra but good consciousness.
					Why bhiksha draupadi - Stri is not bhiksha - kanya daan - girl is not a thing?
						That's not the concept - bhikshuk is below. Giver is high and object given is something of value to giver.
						Word if spoken then never denied - the value of word. What if spoken - go back - not that culture.
					Draupadi knew children gonna die - but experience is different; once SB appreciated but chappal stolen - never came back.
					Not first time - Vyasadev gave eg in past and approved it.
					Can you make decision which you can digest for life - that's not easy.
						Yes, in general not recommended cuz we can't digest - but they could - Krishn married 16K cuz could handle.
						As per adhikar things are allowed.
					Sanskars degraded - no water personal but bottle; no personal cooking but event management team.
						Dharma to be in culture that it becomes attractive - Sita when asked to conduct nicely by Ram she says - no need cuz I know sanskars and next I am coming with you.
					No saas bahu bad story between Draupadi and Kunti - lecture in beginning what the expectations are.
				Donate to brahmins - difference of controllers and owners.
				Krishna in womb - VIP standing in line is respectable. Glorification that nature laws respected.
					he does birth lila but death lila also he does. Respects human life - we don't discuss for sentiment of eternity of God but SB mentions.
			She saw Krishna in agni, he saw Krishna even b4 in difficulties.
				It's possible for her. BG Krishna says - Arjuna see me ew. ?Purpose of life over and had gone there for that.
				Jivo jivasya jivanam - eating, profit from others, me rank 1, others suffer. Hinsa towards others in favor of interests. USA gone but had to leave family.
				If have to kill to stay alive - ask whose life is more valuable. Abort the child or die? If you die, you make child orphan or if they die, you never kill an insect but baby.
				It's a different culture to act in selfless way. Dharma sankat - that's difficult choice in that culture.
				should not say what's right or wrong without knowledge.
				Celibate had heart attack so fell - e1 singing Narsimha arti as if Narsimha will do the needful.
				1 Punjabi healthy doctor started beating him on the chest - he came to consciousness - you were killing him if you didn't do violence here - many devs could not see and ran away.
				So even if kunti allowed killing of 5 people that's act of dharma
				Shastra also like layered cabbage - you keep going deep from superficial to real essence - dharma centered then constitutional centered.
				Ajnat sukriti to Nishada woman - sacrificing like Jatayu.
				Bhima poisoned b4; Now, why they didn't refuse - cuz they said excursion to move out and do some worship (?besides politics of letting nemesis think they are successful)
				Good ppl not to be sacrificed for incompetent people - 7 challenged should be given favor but not adhikar (position of authority)
					that's a wrong mentality.
			I have this regret - Karna rejected and children from demigods not husband.
				Vyasadev said - don't regret you have done it right. And mistakes, you could digest or handle that.
				SP asked - did rama eat meat - doesn't matter cuz even if he did, he knows how to digest it (the reactions). He can eat even fire or poison.
				You are not understood by anyone what to speak of even ordinary woman like me. Humility.
			Q - Arjuna illusioned in BG 1st chapter - he thought neutrality from seniors.
					it all happens spontaneously not scripted and written. where's rasa of life.
					Ignorance for life is good - astrologer telling how you will die - you will die every second till then.
					they acted in the brink of seconds they were in but we in armchair speculation can say what's right and wrong.
				Ignorance never dies on its own - you gotta solve thru knowledge.
		</Kunti>
		<Draupadi>
		Draupadi - Sangathan ki kadi.
			Like Sita in Ramayan - huge description; Ramayan is 25K shlokas and MB is 100K.
			SB is ?18K. BG is 700.
			Brahmins have habit of truth so bluntly harsh from outside st but inside is soft.
				some people are sweet from outside but sword from inside.
			Once eat laddu with lemon flower very sour; New year - bitter sweet dishes to start with.
			Draupadi on birth - she will be cause of destruction of many kings. Gandhari saw not beauty in here but death.
			Genius have some madness also - talent but can't stay married - many fans but not 1 wife.
				ordinary - mistake then self problem. But small mistake from VIP even generations suffer.
				Draupadi - no childhood she got. Krishna used the consciousness of Drupad for orchestration.
				such purity in her that people in her contact - misbehavior then had to get killed.
				So, draupadi special or genius.
				She is agni - when you play with it, then forest fire can kill but can good use.
		L3...
		</Draupadi>
		<Book>
			<Parvas></Parvas>
		</Book>
	</MB>
	<Ramayan> Ref Govinda Pr, Krishna dharma Pr book.
		Lecture 1 - Ramayan - when vs what is there?
			Facility for imagining - history made s.t boring - not fiction or fact but impact.
			Movie on how they made a movie so his struggles to write the literature so participant there.
			Vyasadev in MB - but appears there although writer.
			arrogant, crazy or humble to write himself in the book - Valmiki is humble.
			People choose tragedy stories as heros - you become what you think - Arjuna had tragedy but success himself not others - Ekalavya and Karna not successful.
			Krishna asked for boon from Agni - not tu kya dega but in relp you reciprocate - deep friendship with Arjuna. Arjuna asked for divine weapons ensuring Krishna won't misunderstand.
			Perversion to see others team's defeat - choose worst players - Ramayan uses best characters.
			value vs valuable - not vastu but vaastav based.
			300 versions of Ramayan - Valmiki - heart breaking for brahmins and need to break hearts for kshatriya.
				100 version of ramayan - many slanderous - even court case why project Valmiki's version.
				Ram devotee's heart will break - why highlight Valmiki's? (10:00)
				Scholar - agnostic, atheistic, doubtful, dry grammarian (concept > grammar) - absorption makes you transcend page number. 1 with content.
					kshatriya would break their heart.
					alphabets, words, grammar lose their identity to enhance the purpose of Ramayan.
					@orchestra - all have presence but lose themselves for higher.
				Substance internally and externally. If no understanding but only aggression then fanatic.
				Rasikas - relishable
					yet no conflict with siddhanta.
						Raavan - try to find good in evil people. Endorsing that people can get away with crime. Eg - Human resource people come many times - his past or sth.
					Eb is good. God's wish eth happened - Then where's free will.
					overemphasis on greatness of God.
				Ravan told st - fell on feet or Duryodhan I wanna do good - Jiva has good tendency but doesn't stay - but punishable still.
				ordinary poets - have kalpana but not darshan - siddhanta distorted.
			Spirituality done wrongly affects society badly is a fact
			Why - reasons for writing
				Niti - game, wealth, teach practical interactions, gain freedom from curses and disease, achieve moksha, teach and transform others.
				Sahitya academy, jnanapeeth, etc.
				King reads your content and recognition - then prasiddhi.
				Intel -> arrogance. So stay fool? Envious otherwise. So, intel would be ignored in past.
				children you can be flexible but adult in arrogance so why attention to me, etc. So learning best at children even scold and they forget but learn.
				No flattery for psychological growth of child. Ram praising Hanuman was against it.
				Gurukuls run by grihastas - not sanyasis and brahmacaris - no love and harsh bad for them - efficiency by males and affection from females. Dualities of life to experience.
				murti are shaped fast but deities take lots of time - patience.
				certs but not skills
			(10:00)
		<Book>
			<Kandas></Kandas>
		</Book>
	</Ramayan>
	<KrishnaLila> Ref Krishna book; Radha Govind Swami
		Planned - Not started yet (0:00)
			Baal Lila
			Braj Ras
			Dwaraka Lila
		<KrishnaBook>
			<VrindavanLila></VrindavanLila>
			<MathuraLila></MathuraLila>
			<DwarakaLila></DwarakaLila>
		</KrishnaBook>
	</KrishnaLila>
	<SB> Ref RNSM By Themes, By SP Book.

	</SB>
	<CC> Ref ?BCS, By SP Book.

	</CC>
	<SP> Ref Prabhupada Lilamrita; Various devotees.

	</SP>
</Lila>